<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding and Math Classes in Charlottesville! Prep for AP Computer Science and AP Calculus!</title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Coding and Math Classes in Charlottesville! Prep for AP Computer Science and AP Calculus!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Free trial coding classes </title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/17/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/17/post4/</guid>
      <description>Open house every Sunday at 1pm!
Come in to see the space and meet the instructor!
Bring in your child for demo sessions.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Location in Downtown Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/05/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/05/post3/</guid>
      <description>The new office is ready for students!
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Location in Downtown Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/29/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/29/post2/</guid>
      <description>Starting in September, Blue Ridge Boost is located at 222 Court Square, Charlottesville.
To reach us, please walk around to the back of the building. Walk up the stairs to the secong floor and enter through the door on your left.
The closest paid parking is the Market Street Garage. Free 2-hour parking is available throughout the Downtown area.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall Classes</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/15/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/15/post1/</guid>
      <description>Fall classes coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/vision/</guid>
      <description>History of Blue Ridge Boost During the COVID-19 pandemic, I spent significant time teaching and helping my children learn and discovered that I greatly enjoy teaching young students. As a result, I quit my Ph.D. program in Computer Science to pursue a degree in teaching at the University of Virginia, which I completed in May 2022.
During the lockdown, my children tried a variety of challenging and exciting classes. Still, however good the instructors were, they could not compensate for the lack of face-to-face interaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 Tutoring in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/algebra1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/algebra1/</guid>
      <description>Get Ready for Algebra 1! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review pre-algebra, including fractions, ratios, proportions, order of operations, and exponents.
Algebra 1 Remediation The instructor will work with the classroom teacher when available to match the teaching style and materials to maintain consistency in the presentation style. For example, in a tutoring session, the instructor reviews concepts your student learned in class and assists with homework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 2 Tutoring in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/algebra2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/algebra2/</guid>
      <description>Get Ready for Algebra 2! Join our summer classes in August, to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review Algebra 1, including linear functions, linear equations and systems of equations, exponent laws, quadratic functions, and polynomials.
Algebra 2 Remediation The instructor will work with the classroom teacher when available to match the teaching style and materials to maintain consistency in the presentation style. For example, in a tutoring session, the instructor reviews concepts your student learned in class and assists with homework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AP Calculus AB/BC Tutoring in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/calc/</guid>
      <description>Get Ready for AP Calculus AB/BC! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review linear, quadratic, polynomial, exponential, and trigonometric functions.
Tutoring Contact us for problem-solving sessions!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AP Statistics Tutoring in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/stats/</guid>
      <description>Get Ready for AP Statistics! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review probabilities, statistics, and linear, quadratic, and exponential functions.
Tutoring Contact us for problem-solving sessions!
 
   --   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/authors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/authors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block Language Classes for Six to Ten-Year-Olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/k2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/k2/</guid>
      <description>Block Language Coding for Lower Elementary School Students Students learn fundamental coding concepts by helping [a beaver build a dam](https://www.codemonkey.com/courses/beaver-achiever/) on instructor-provided Chromebooks. First, students learn to code using simple commands to move left, right and drop logs. Next, students learn to code repetition using repeat loops executed a fixed or a variable number of times. In the second part of the course, students learn to code using conditional loops. In the third part of the course, students learn to code using conditional statements with simple and compound conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Request Form</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/form/</guid>
      <description>Please submit this form or email nora@blueridgeboost.com for more information or to join a class. 
 Your email: 
  Your name:    Which type of class are you interested in? Select and age range Kindergarten - Second Grade Second - Fifth Grade Middle School     Any other information that would be helpful (including scheduling preferences):
  Send</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</guid>
      <description>Free trial classes every Saturday at 10 am and every Sunday at 4:30 pm. Sign up for a free trial class here!    -- 
Kindergarten &amp;ndash; Second Grade 
Block Coding
Times by request   Scratch
Sundays, 1:00 &amp;ndash; 1:50 pm Sundays, 2:00 &amp;ndash; 2:50 pm  Second &amp;ndash; Fifth Grade

Coffee Script  Sundays, 11:00 &amp;ndash; 11:50 am
Sundays, 3:30 &amp;ndash; 4:30 pm
Other times by request   Middle School</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Group Classes for 4 to 6 year olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/preschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/preschool/</guid>
      <description>Coding Group Classes for Early Coders Our youngest students learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a monkey collect bananas on instructor-provided Chromebooks. Students learn the basics of coding using left, right, jump up, jump left, and jump right commands to guide a monkey to collect all bananas before opening a treasure chest. In addition, students learn to code repetition by using loops and conditional loops. The course concludes with procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Lessons</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/coding/</guid>
      <description> Coding Lessons and Courses Preschool Coding Block Languages using Code Monkey Robotics with Lego WeDo 2.0 Scratch Robotics with Lego Spike Coffee Script using Code Monkey Python Programming  Tutoring AP Computer Science Principles (Python) AP Computer Science (Java) USA Computing Olympiad Bronze College-Level Courses-- Intro to Programming Data Structures and Algorithms Discrete Math and Theory Programming Languages   


 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Script Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/upper_elementary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/upper_elementary/</guid>
      <description>Students learn fundamental coding concepts using Coffee Script, a beginner-friendly text-based coding language. The young coders use an attractive graphical interface to generate text by pressing buttons on instructor-provided Chromebooks. Some previous experience typing is helpful but not necessary.
Classes run in four-week sessions. Each class is 50 minutes long. We adjust classes to the pace of each student. Students typically need between ten to fourteen sessions to complete the course, depending on age and previous coding experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition Math for Elementary and Middle School</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/moems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/moems/</guid>
      <description>An experienced instructor teaches mini-lessons on topics commonly found in Math Olympiad contests and leads students in solving practice problems.
The content of the class depends on the target competition and the student&amp;rsquo;s background. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch with us for further information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science Sessions</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/cstutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/cstutoring/</guid>
      <description>Click on a session to see availability and book it! window.addEventListener &amp;&amp; window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;, function(event){if (event.origin === &#34;https://blueridgeboost-cs.youcanbook.me&#34;){document.getElementById(&#34;ycbmiframeblueridgeboost-cs&#34;).style.height = event.data + &#34;px&#34;;}}, false);</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch with us for any learning needs in math and computing. We offer online and in-person one-on-one instruction and in-person group classes for students from middle school to graduate student level in Mathematics and Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geometry Tutoring in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/geometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/geometry/</guid>
      <description>Get Ready for Geometry Join our Summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review Algebra 1 topics, including linear equations, systems of linear equations, and the Pythagorean Theorem.
Geometry Remediation The instructor will work with the classroom teacher when available to match the teaching style and materials to maintain consistency in the presentation style. For example, in a tutoring session, the instructor reviews concepts your student learned in class and assists with homework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individualized Math Tutoring</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/math/</guid>
      <description>Elementary (K-5) Math Counts -- Elementary Math Math Olympiad  Middle School (5-8th grade) Middle School Math Algebra 1 Geometry AMC 8/10/12     High School Algebra 2 Pre-calculus Prep for AP Calculus AB and BC Prep for AP Statistics  College Calculus Abstract Algebra Real Analysis General Topology      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego Robotics for Children in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/spike/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/spike/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego Robotics for Children in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/wedo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/wedo/</guid>
      <description>Build Lego Robots and Code with WeDo 2.0 Come and learn to build and program Lego robots! In each lesson, students build a Lego robot using a design model, improve and extend it, and then create a program using Scratch to control and move the robot. The robots use a medium power motor to act, depth, and tilt sensor to sense. A Scratch program encodes the robot&amp;rsquo;s actions in response to sensing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math and Coding Camp Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/aug23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/aug23/</guid>
      <description>Morning Coding and Math Camp 
Ages 6 to 10: Come to learn to code using Scratch or Coffee Script, build Lego robots and solve math puzzles!
Session 1: 9 am to 1 pm, July 31st to August 4th
Session 2: 9 am to 1 pm, August 7th to August 11th
 Afternoon Math Review!

Algebra 1: 1:30 to 3:30 pm, July 31st to August 4th Geometry: 2 to 4 pm, July 31st to August 4th Algebra 2: 1:30 to 3:30 pm, August 7th to August 11th Precalculus: 2 to 4 pm, August 7th to August 11th AP Calculus AB/BC: 1:30 to 3:30 pm, August 14th to August 18th AP Statistics: 2 to 4 pm, August 14th to August 18th</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Sessions</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/mathtutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/mathtutoring/</guid>
      <description>Click on a session to see availability and book it! window.addEventListener &amp;&amp; window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;, function(event){if (event.origin === &#34;https://blueridgeboost-math.youcanbook.me&#34;){document.getElementById(&#34;ycbmiframeblueridgeboost-math&#34;).style.height = event.data + &#34;px&#34;;}}, false); </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Tutoring for Children in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/elementary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/elementary/</guid>
      <description>At Blue Ridge Boost, we teach problem-solving skills using a variety of math manipulatives, Montessori materials, and math games. In addition, we use a variety of curricula based on the Virginia Standards of Learning, Common Core, Singapore Math, and Beast Academy.
Experienced instructors are ready to help your child develop a good understanding of the content, whether to keep up with classwork or expand knowledge beyond the school curriculum.
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middle School Math Tutoring in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/msmath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/msmath/</guid>
      <description>At Blue Ridge Boost, a qualified and experienced teacher assesses your student&amp;rsquo;s knowledge and builds an individualized instruction plan that targets weak areas while assisting with topics the student is learning.
Supplementing Classroom Instruction The instructor will work with the classroom teacher when available to match the teaching style and materials to maintain consistency in the presentation style. For example, in a tutoring session, the instructor reviews concepts your student learned in class and assists with homework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precalc Tutoring in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/precalc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/precalc/</guid>
      <description>Get Ready for Math Analysis/Precalc! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review Algebra 2 and Trigonometry, including quadratic, exponential, polynomial, and trigonometric functions.
Precalc Remediation The instructor will work with the classroom teacher when available to match the teaching style and materials to maintain consistency in the presentation style. For example, in a tutoring session, the instructor reviews concepts your student learned in class and assists with homework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prep for AP Computer Science A</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/apcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/apcs/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prep for AP Computer Science Principles</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/apcsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/apcsp/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prep for USA Computing Olympiad</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/usaco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/usaco/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/python_ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/python_ms/</guid>
      <description>Are you a middle schooler interested in Python? Come and learn with us!
Students learn Python using a combination of lessons that use the Code Monkey platform and Jupyter Notebooks created by the instructor.
Classes run in four-week sessions. Each class is 50 minutes long. We adjust classes to the pace of each student. Students typically need between ten to fourteen sessions to complete the course, depending on age and previous coding experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch Coding for Children in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/scratch/</guid>
      <description>Scratch Coding Learn Scratch with us! We teach Scratch using a project-based approach. You will learn to create games, including Make it Fly!, Dungeons, Pong, Dodge the Balls, Jumping game, Math facts practice, a clone of Crossy Road, and much more.        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train for AMC in Person in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/amc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/amc/</guid>
      <description>An experienced instructor with MathCounts and AMC8 coaching experience teaches mini-lessons on topics commonly found in competition math problems and leads students in solving practice problems.
The content of the class depends on the target competition and the student&amp;rsquo;s background. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch with us for further information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Instructor: Nora Evans</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</guid>
      <description>Math Experience  Master of Science - Mathematics from the University of Virginia Master of Teaching - Mathematics Algebra teacher at Peabody School AMC8 and MathCounts coach AP Summer Institute training in AP Calculus AB/BC Calculus and Abstract Algebra in-person tutoring for over a year internship at Monticello High School in Algebra 2, Precalculus, and Geometry co-founder and organizer of Cville Math Circle for preschool and elementary school-age girls teaching assistant for graduate-level courses Financial Mathematics instructor at the University of Virginia  Computer Science and Coding Experience  Master in Computer Science co-author of several research articles several years of industry experience over a year of online tutoring on Wyzant in C, C++, Java, Python, List, and Prolog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
