<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Science and AP Calculus Tutor Charlottesville</title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Computer Science and AP Calculus Tutor Charlottesville</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Free trial coding classes </title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/17/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/17/post4/</guid>
      <description>Open house every Sunday at 1pm!
Come in to see the space and meet the instructor!
Bring in your child for demo sessions.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Location in Downtown Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/05/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/05/post3/</guid>
      <description>The new office is ready for students!
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Location in Downtown Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/29/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/29/post2/</guid>
      <description>Starting in September, Blue Ridge Boost is located at 222 Court Square, Charlottesville.
To reach us, please walk around to the back of the building. Walk up the stairs to the secong floor and enter through the door on your left.
The closest paid parking is the Market Street Garage. Free 2-hour parking is available throughout the Downtown area.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall Classes</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/15/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/15/post1/</guid>
      <description>Fall classes coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Coding For Kids in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/kids/</guid>
      <description>Computing At Blue Ridge Boost, we teach computing using play, starting with robots to visualize the programming concepts. The programming exercises use an attractive graphical interface to reinforce concepts through practice.
   We believe that students have to be exposed to the same programming concepts in a variety of situations and language variations. For this reason, students learn a few block languages to program WeDo Lego robots, mBot robots, help a beaver build its house in the Code Monkey framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Afternoon Camp for 9-12 year olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/afternoonwintercamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/afternoonwintercamp/</guid>
      <description>Camp at a glance When: Monday, December 27 – Friday, December 31, 2021, 2:00 am – 4:00 pm
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia (Pantops area)
Who: 9 – 12 years olds, no prior computer programming experience required
What: Coding instruction using Coffee Script or Python depending on student&amp;rsquo;s experience and preference (no video games!)
Cost: $350
Sign Up: nora@blueridgeboost.com
Conditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a mask for the duration of the camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/authors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/authors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block Language Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/k2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/k2/</guid>
      <description>Students learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a a beaver build a dam on instructor-provided chromebooks.
Maximum class size: 6 students.
Duration: 4 weeks.
Lesson length: 45 minutes.

Session 1. Sequencing and Loops Students build a foundation in coding and problem solving.
Lesson 1. What is coding? Students learn that coding is giving precise instructions to a computer. Each student creates their first program – a dance routine for the class to follow!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding and Computer Science Tutoring</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/cs/</guid>
      <description>Experienced software engineer and tutor provides individual instruction.
Book a session now! Adults/College  Coding with Java, Python, C/C++, Prolog, Lisp, and Rust. Introduction to Programming Sodtware Engineering Data Structures and Algorithms Discrete Math Program and Data Representation Programming Languages  High School  AP Computer Science Principles (Python) AP Computer Science (Java) Preparation for USA Computing Olympiad Bronze Level  Children We believe that students have to be exposed to the same programming concepts in a variety of situations and language variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</guid>
      <description>Free trial classes every Sunday at 1 pm. Sign up now! Four coding classes for only $95!   
Lower Elementary 
Session 1 of Beaver Achiever
 Saturdays, 10:00--10:45 am Sign up!
4 spaces available!  Session 2 of Beaver Achiever
Sundays, 2:00--2:45 pm Sign up!
2 spaces available!  
Upper Elementary

Session 2 of Coding Adventure  Saturdays, noon--12:45 pm
Sign up! 2 spaces left!  Session 1 of Coding Adventure Sundays, 4:00--4:45pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Script Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/upper_elementary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/upper_elementary/</guid>
      <description>Students learn fundamental coding concepts using Coffee Script, a beginner friendly text-based coding language. The young coders use an attractive graphical interface to generate text by pressing buttons on instructor-provided chromebooks. Some previous experience typing is helpful, but not necessary.
Maximum class size: 6 students.
Duration: 4 weeks.
Lesson length: 45 minutes.

Session 1. Sequencing and Objects Students learn sequential execution, objects and properties.
Lessons 1 and 2. Basic coding Students learn that coding is giving precise instructions to a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science and Math Tutoring</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/hs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/hs/</guid>
      <description>Computing At Blue Ridge Boost, we provide individual tutoring sessions for high ability students in the following subjects:
 AP Computer Science Principles (Python) AP Computer Science (Java) Preparation for USA Computing Olympiad Bronze Level   Math A licensed, experienced teacher provides individual instruction in:
 Algebra 1 Geometry Trigonometry Algebra 2 Math Analysis AP Calculus AB AP Calculus BC Math for SAT/ACT    Book a computer science session now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science and Math Tutoring in Charlottesville for Adults</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/adults/</guid>
      <description>Computer Science  Coding with Java, Python, C/C++, Prolog, Lisp, and Rust. Introduction to Programming Data Structures and Algorithms Discrete Math Program and Data Representation Programming Languages   Math  Financial Mathematics Calculus Transition to Higher Mathematics Real Analysis Abstract Algebra General Topology    Book a computer science session now!  Book a math session now!     Contact us if your needs are not met by one of the existing offerings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science Sessions</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/cstutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/cstutoring/</guid>
      <description>Click on a session to see availability and book it! window.addEventListener &amp;&amp; window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;, function(event){if (event.origin === &#34;https://blueridgeboost-cs.youcanbook.me&#34;){document.getElementById(&#34;ycbmiframeblueridgeboost-cs&#34;).style.height = event.data + &#34;px&#34;;}}, false);</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please contact us with for any learning needs in math and computing. We offer online one-on-one instruction and in-person group classes for students from middle school to graduate student level in Mathematics and Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Classes Schedule</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/schedule/</guid>
      <description>Book 1-1 classes here!  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Sessions</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/mathtutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/mathtutoring/</guid>
      <description>Click on a session to see availability and book it! window.addEventListener &amp;&amp; window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;, function(event){if (event.origin === &#34;https://blueridgeboost-math.youcanbook.me&#34;){document.getElementById(&#34;ycbmiframeblueridgeboost-math&#34;).style.height = event.data + &#34;px&#34;;}}, false); </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Tutoring</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/math/</guid>
      <description>Experienced teacher provides individual instruction.
Book a math session now! Adults/College  Financial Mathematics Calculus Transition to Higher Mathematics Real Analysis Abstract Algebra General Topology  High School  Algebra Geometry Trigonometry Math Analysis AP Calculus AB AP Calculus BC AP Statistics Math for SAT/ACT  Children At Blue Ridge Boost, we teach problem solving skills, rather than drill and memorization. For younger students, we offer math circle type classes, in which students solve challenging problems in groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morning Camp for 6-9 year olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/morningwintercamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/morningwintercamp/</guid>
      <description>Camp at a glance When: Monday, December 27 - Friday, December 31, 2021, 10:00 am – 1:00 pm
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia (Pantops area)
What: Coding instruction using block languages (no video games!)
Who: 6 – 9 years olds, no prior computer programming experience required
Cost: $350 (early drop off at 9am is available for an additional $50)
Sign Up: nora@blueridgeboost.com
Conditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a mask for the duration of the camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past Coding Classes Offered at Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/past_classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/past_classes/</guid>
      <description>nora@blueridgeboost.com --Where: Before August 15, Zoom meeting from the comfort of your home.
When: at a time that works for you.Who: Any student interested in coding.Cost for six 1-hour sessions: $250 for elementary school, $350 for middle school, $400 for high school.Introduction to Coding At Blue Ridge Boost, we teach the same fundamental coding concepts to students of all ages. The courses are structured around three 6-class sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preschool Coding Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/preschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/preschool/</guid>
      <description>Students learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a monkey collect bananas on instructor-provided chromebooks.
Maximum class size: 4 students.
Duration: 4 weeks.
Lesson length: 35 minutes.

Session 1. Sequencing Students build a foundation in coding and problem solving.
Lesson 1. What is coding? Students learn that coding is giving precise instructions to a computer. Each student creates their first program – a dance routine for the class to follow!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/python_ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/python_ms/</guid>
      <description>Students learn to code instructor-provided chromebooks using Python, a widely used programming language in academia and industry. Previous experience with computer typing is recommended.
Maximum class size: 6 students.
Duration: 4 weeks.
Lesson length: 45 minutes.

Session 1. Sequencing and Objects In the first 4-week session students learn objects and properties, lists and indexing.
Lessons 1 and 2. Basic coding Students learn that coding is giving precise instructions to a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Instructor: Ana Nora Evans</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</guid>
      <description>--   Math Experience  Master of Science - Mathematics from the University of Virginia Master of Teaching - Mathematics   AP Summer Institute training in AP Calculus AB/BC Calculus and Abstract Algebra in-person tutoring for over a year internship at Monticello High School in Algebra 2, Precalculus, and Geometry co-founder and organizer of Cville Math Circle for preschool and elementary school age girls teaching assistant for graduate-level courses Financial Mathematics instructor at the University of Virginia  Computer Science and Coding Experience  Master in Computer Science co-author of several research articles several year of industry experience over a year of online tutoring on Wyzant in C, C++, Java, Python, List and Prolog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
