<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classes on Coding and Math Classes and Tutoring in Charlottesville</title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classes on Coding and Math Classes and Tutoring in Charlottesville</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Block Language Classes for Six to Ten-Year-Olds | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/kids-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/kids-coding/</guid>
      <description>Block Language Coding for Children Students ages six to ten learn fundamental coding concepts by helping [a beaver build a dam](https://www.codemonkey.com/courses/beaver-achiever/) on instructor-provided Chromebooks. First, students learn to code using simple commands to move left, right and drop logs. Next, students learn to code repetition using repeat loops executed a fixed or a variable number of times. In the second part of the course, students learn to code using conditional loops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/ongoing-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/ongoing-classes/</guid>
      <description>Ongoing Coding Classes in Downtown Charlottesville Coding for Kindergarten to Second GradeBlock Coding Class
Times by requestScratch Coding Class
Sundays, 1:00 &amp;ndash; 1:50 pm Sundays, 2:00 &amp;ndash; 2:50 pmCoding for Third to Fifth Grade
Coffee Script Coding Class Sundays, 11:00 &amp;ndash; 11:50 am
Sundays, 3:30 &amp;ndash; 4:30 pm
Other times by requestCoding for Sixth to Eight Grade
Python Coding ClassSaturdays, 2:30 &amp;ndash; 3:20 pm
Sundays, 12:00 &amp;mdash; 12:50 pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Group Classes for 4 to 6 year olds | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/preschool-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/preschool-coding/</guid>
      <description>Coding Group Classes for Early Coders Our youngest students learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a monkey collect bananas on instructor-provided Chromebooks. Students learn the basics of coding using left, right, jump up, jump left, and jump right commands to guide a monkey to collect all bananas before opening a treasure chest. In addition, students learn to code repetition by using loops and conditional loops. The course concludes with procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego Robotics for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/lego-wedo-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/lego-wedo-class/</guid>
      <description>Build Lego Robots and Code with WeDo 2.0 Come and learn to build and program Lego robots! In each lesson, students build a Lego robot using a design model, improve and extend it, and then create a program using Scratch to control and move the robot. The robots use a medium power motor to act, depth, and tilt sensor to sense. A Scratch program encodes the robot&amp;rsquo;s actions in response to sensing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego Spike Robotics for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/lego-spike-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/lego-spike-class/</guid>
      <description>Build Lego Robots and Code with Lego Spike Come and learn to build and program Lego robots!
Students learn to build robot attachments and code the Spike robot using Scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/python-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/python-class/</guid>
      <description>Python Classess and Tutoring in Charlottesville Are you a middle schooler interested in Python? Come and learn with us!
Students learn Python using a combination of lessons that use the Code Monkey platform and Jupyter Notebooks created by the instructor.
Classes run in four-week sessions. Each class is 50 minutes long. We adjust classes to the pace of each student. Students typically need between ten to fourteen sessions to complete the course, depending on age and previous coding experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch Coding for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/scratch-class-tutor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/scratch-class-tutor/</guid>
      <description>Scratch Coding and Tutoring in Charllottesville Learn Scratch with us! We teach Scratch using a project-based approach. You will learn to create games, including Make it Fly!, Dungeons, Pong, Dodge the Balls, Jumping game, Math facts practice, a clone of Crossy Road, and much more.
Contact us to join an ongoing class or for private tutoring!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
