<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blue Ridge Boost</title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blue Ridge Boost</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Afternoon Camp for 9-12 year olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/afternoonwintercamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/afternoonwintercamp/</guid>
      <description>Camp at a glance When: Dec 27 - Dec 31, 2021, 2pm-4pm.
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia.
What: Coding instruction without video games using Python and CoffeScript.
Cost: $350.
Conditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a safe mask correctly for the duration of the camp.
Daily Schedule Campers will spend two hours daily, from 2m to 4pm working together and individually on fun programming challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classes</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/classes/</guid>
      <description>In January and February, we offer week-end enrichment classes of up to 4 students. Sign-up for as many as you like. Payment is required to reserve spot, no walk-ins accepted.
Competition Math for Fourth and Fifth Graders When: TODO
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia.
What: Problem solving strategies for elementary school math competitions, focused on MOEMS.
Cost: $40/session.
Conditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a safe mask correctly for the duration of the camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>We are here to help you Please contact us with for any tutoring needs in math and computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/faq/</guid>
      <description>Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante. Donec eu libero sit amet quam egestas semper. Aenean ultricies mi vitae est. Mauris placerat eleifend leo.
1. WHAT TO DO IF I HAVE STILL NOT RECEIVED THE ORDER? Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morning Camp for 6-9 year olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/morningwintercamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/morningwintercamp/</guid>
      <description>Camp at a glance When: Monday, December 27 - Friday, December 31, 2021, 10:00 am – 1:00 pm
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia (Pantops area)
What: Coding instruction using block languages (not video games!)
Cost: $350 (early drop off at 9am is available for an additional $50)
Sign Up: nora@cvillemath.comConditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a mask for the duration of the camp.
Daily Schedule Campers will spend three hours daily, from 10am to 1pm working as a group and individually on fun programming challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutoring</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/tutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.githup.io/tutoring/</guid>
      <description>We offer 1-1 tutoring for students from middle school to graduate student level in Mathematics and Computer Science. The cost per class is between $50 and $150 depedning on the complexity of the preparation and materials needed. For a quote and scheduling, please contact us at TODO.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
