<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blue Ridge Boost</title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blue Ridge Boost</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adults</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/adults/</guid>
      <description>Math  Financial Mathematics Calculus Transition to Higher Mathematics Real Analysis Complex Variables and Analysis Linear Algebra Abstract Algebra General Topology  Computer Science  Coding with Java, Python, C/C++, Prolog, Lisp, Haskell, OCaml, and Rust. Introduction to Programming Data Structures and Algorithms Discrete Math Program and Data Representation Theory of Computation Algorithms Operating Systems Compilers Programming Languages  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Afternoon Camp for 9-12 year olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/afternoonwintercamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/afternoonwintercamp/</guid>
      <description>Camp at a glance When: Monday, December 27 – Friday, December 31, 2021, 2:00 am – 4:00 pm
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia (Pantops area)
Who: 9 – 12 years olds, no prior computer programming experience required
What: Coding instruction using Coffee Script or Python depending on student&amp;rsquo;s experience and preference (no video games!)
Cost: $350
Sign Up: nora@blueridgeboost.com
Conditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a mask for the duration of the camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please contact us with for any learning needs in math and computing. We offer online 1-1 instruction and in-person group classes for students from middle school to graduate student level in Mathematics and Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</guid>
      <description>Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante. Donec eu libero sit amet quam egestas semper. Aenean ultricies mi vitae est. Mauris placerat eleifend leo.
1. WHAT TO DO IF I HAVE STILL NOT RECEIVED THE ORDER? Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Classes Schedule</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/schedule/</guid>
      <description>1-1 Classes Availability and booking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High School</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/hs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/hs/</guid>
      <description>For high school students, we offer 1-1 instruction, online or in-person, for all math and computer science classes, including AP.
Math  Algebra 1 Geometry Trigonometry Algebra 2 Math Analysis Computer Mathematics Probability &amp;amp; Statistics Discrete Mathematics AP Calculus AB AP Calculus BC  Computing  Computer Science Foundations Computer Science Principles Computer Science Programming AP Computer Science Principles AP Computer Science (Java) Preparation for USA Computing Olympiad Bronze Level  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Person Group Classes</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</guid>
      <description>In January and February, we offer week-end enrichment classes of up to 4 students. Payment is required to reserve spot, no walk-ins accepted.
Sign Up: nora@blueridgeboost.com
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia (Pantops area). Conditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a mask for the duration of the camp. Coding (grades 1-3) When: Saturday 10am - 11am, January 22 - February 26 What: Each student follows a selection of instructor lessons, Scratch projects, Lego WeDo projects, and Coffee Script programming exercises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/kids/</guid>
      <description>Computing At Blue Ridge Boost, we teach computing using play and robots to visualize the programming concepts. The programming exercises use an attractive graphical interface to reinforce concepts through practice. We believe that students have to be exposed to the same programming concepts in a variety of situations and language variations. For this reason, students learn a few block languages to program WeDo Lego robots, mBot robots, help a beaver build its house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morning Camp for 6-9 year olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/morningwintercamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/morningwintercamp/</guid>
      <description>Camp at a glance When: Monday, December 27 - Friday, December 31, 2021, 10:00 am – 1:00 pm
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia (Pantops area)
What: Coding instruction using block languages (no video games!)
Who: 6 – 9 years olds, no prior computer programming experience required
Cost: $350 (early drop off at 9am is available for an additional $50)
Sign Up: nora@blueridgeboost.com
Conditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a mask for the duration of the camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutoring</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/</guid>
      <description>Math and Computer Science We offer 1-1 tutoring for students from middle school to graduate student level in Mathematics and Computer Science, both in-person and online.
The cost per class is between $50 and $150 depedning on the complexity of the preparation and materials needed.
For a quote and scheduling, please contact us at nora@blueridgeboost.com.
    Your Tutor Ana Nora Evans has a Masters degree in Mathematics from the University of Virginia, a Masters degree in Computer Science from the University of Virginia, and will complete a Masters degree in Teaching in Spring 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Instructor: Ana Nora Evans</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</guid>
      <description>Nora is passionate about math and computing education, especially in attracting and retaining girls and women in STEM fields. The classroom environment and courses are designed to appeal to all students, not only cameo&amp;rsquo;s and boys.
     Ana Nora Evans graduated from Polytechnical University of Bucharest, Romania with a degree in Computer Sience. She earned Masters degrees in Mathematics, Computer Science from the University of Virginia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
