<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>7th on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/7th/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 7th on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/7th/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Problem Solving | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Problem-Solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Problem-Solving/</guid>
      <description>MOEMS is a challenging and engaging math competition for middle schoolers, featuring five monthly contests from November to March that focus on problem-solving and mathematical creativity. Similarly, the AMC 8 is a 40-minute math competition designed for students in grade 8 and below, covering a range of middle school math topics, including some concepts from introductory algebra. At Blue Ridge Boost, students participate in weekly problem-solving sessions to prepare for these competitions, and they have the option to take the tests if they choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerial Drones | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</guid>
      <description>What is the Aerial Drone Competition? A cutting-edge program that prepares students for careers in drone technology Four exciting missions: Teamwork, Autonomous Flight, Piloting Skills, and Communications Compete in local, and regional events No prior experience needed! We&#39;re looking for students who are: Curious about drones and aviation Interested in coding and programming Excited to learn piloting skills Great at teamwork and communication Ready to take on new challenges Students are not required to participate in a Competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Algebra 1 Success Made Simple!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Algebra Sessions: Focused Learning: Small groups of 4 students Expert Guidance: Excel in your algebra homework Clear Explanations: Understand equations and functions Interactive Practice: Build problem-solving skills Weekly Sessions: 60 minutes each Comprehensive Coverage: All key Algebra 1 topics Boost Your Grades and ConfidenceEnroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Algebra Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Algebra Together!&#xA;Join our group algebra homework help sessions:&#xA;Small group classes (4 students)Expert instructor guidanceCollaborative problem-solvingBoost your grades and confidence with peers!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Algebra 1 Success Made Simple!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Algebra Sessions: Focused Learning: Small groups of 4 students Expert Guidance: Excel in your algebra homework Clear Explanations: Understand equations and functions Interactive Practice: Build problem-solving skills Weekly Sessions: 60 minutes each Comprehensive Coverage: All key Algebra 1 topics Boost Your Grades and ConfidenceEnroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Algebra Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Algebra Together!&#xA;Join our group algebra homework help sessions:&#xA;Small group classes (4 students)Expert instructor guidanceCollaborative problem-solvingBoost your grades and confidence with peers!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMC 8 Test | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/AMC8-2025-Test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/AMC8-2025-Test/</guid>
      <description>Are you excited about the AMC 8 but find that your school doesn&#39;t host the contest? No problem! You can sign up and take the test at Blue Ridge Boost. We offer a welcoming space for young math enthusiasts to test their skills and enjoy a rewarding competition experience.&#xA;The AMC 8 is a 25-question, 40-minute competition designed for students in grade 8 and below. The competition focuses on middle school mathematics topics, including counting and probability, estimation, proportional reasoning, elementary geometry (including the Pythagorean Theorem), spatial visualization, and interpreting graphs and tables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMC10 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-AMC10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-AMC10/</guid>
      <description>The AMC 10 (American Mathematics Competitions 10) is a prestigious mathematics contest in the United States designed for students aged 10 through 16, or those enrolled in grades 10 and below. This challenging competition aims to cultivate problem-solving skills, foster mathematical creativity, and promote a deeper understanding of advanced mathematical concepts. With its rigorous content spanning algebra, geometry, number theory, and combinatorics, the AMC 10 serves as a gateway to higher-level math competitions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Before Camp Care | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-Before/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-Before/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chess Tactics and Games | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/chess/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/chess/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to start a chess program for our more dedicated players, who are ready to learn more about the game and improve their skills.&#xA;The classes start at 10 am with a 45 minutes lesson, followed by three 15-minute games. The pickup time is 12:00.&#xA;The classes are held at Blue Ridge Boost and are taught by Daniel Wurtzer.&#xA;Hello my name is Daniel Wurzer and I am excited to teach chess lessons at Blue Ridge Boost this fall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chess Tactics and Games | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to start a chess program for our more dedicated players, who are ready to learn more about the game and improve their skills.&#xA;The classes start at 10 am with a 45 minutes lesson, followed by three 15-minute games. The pickup time is 12:00.&#xA;The classes are held at Blue Ridge Boost and are taught by Daniel Wurtzer.&#xA;Hello my name is Daniel Wurzer and I am excited to teach chess lessons at Blue Ridge Boost this fall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Geometry Homework Made Easy!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Geometry Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of 4 studentsExpert help with your geometry homework Clear explanations of theorems and proofsHands-on problem-solving practice60-minute sessions weeklyCover all high school geometry topicsBoost your grades and confidenceTransform triangles and circles from foes to friends!&#xA;Enroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Geometry Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Geometry-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Geometry-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Geometry Homework Made Easy!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Geometry Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of 4 studentsExpert help with your geometry homework Clear explanations of theorems and proofsHands-on problem-solving practice60-minute sessions weeklyCover all high school geometry topicsBoost your grades and confidenceTransform triangles and circles from foes to friends!&#xA;Enroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Geometry Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl Powered Fridays on 2024-12-06 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/girl-powered-fridays/gpf-2024-12-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/girl-powered-fridays/gpf-2024-12-06/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl Powered Fridays on 2025-02-07 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/girl-powered-fridays/gpf-2025-02-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/girl-powered-fridays/gpf-2025-02-07/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl Powered Fridays on 2025-03-21 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/girl-powered-fridays/gpf-2025-03-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/girl-powered-fridays/gpf-2025-03-21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl Powered Fridays on 2025-05-16 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/girl-powered-fridays/gpf-2025-05-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/girl-powered-fridays/gpf-2025-05-16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Drone Squad | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-Drone-Squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-Drone-Squad/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Female Drone Pilots and Engineers!&#xA;Join our Girl-Powered Aerial Drone Competition Team! Are you ready to soar into the future of technology? We&#39;re forming an all-girl team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition, and we want YOU to be part of this exciting adventure! What is the Aerial Drone Competition?&#xA;• A cutting-edge program that prepares students for careers in drone technology&#xA;• Four exciting missions: Teamwork, Autonomous Flight, Piloting Skills, and Communications</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-First-Tech-Challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-First-Tech-Challenge/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;re forming a new FIRST Tech Challenge team and we want GIRLS!&#xA;This is an inclusive STEM class with a focus on empowering girls. While all genders are welcome and encouraged to participate, we strive to maintain a majority female enrollment to address historical underrepresentation in STEM fields. Our goal is to create a supportive environment that inspires girls to explore and excel in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.&#xA;What is FIRST Tech Challenge?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Olympiad Contest | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-M-Contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-M-Contest/</guid>
      <description>MATH OLYMPIAD 2024-2025&#xA;Unleash Your Mathematical Genius!&#xA;🏆 Calling All Young Math Stars (Grades 6-8)&#xA;Challenge your mind and discover the excitement of problem-solving at this year&#39;s Math Olympiad! Join hundreds of bright young mathematicians for an unforgettable experience.&#xA;Why Participate?&#xA;• Boost your critical thinking skills&#xA;• Meet other math enthusiasts&#xA;• Gain competition experience&#xA;The unique problem sets must be administered each month from November through March.&#xA;You can participate in any or all contests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Fundamentals | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>This course is a comprehensive, year-long program designed for middle school students with no prior coding experience. It introduces fundamental programming concepts using Python through interactive exercises and projects centered around controlling a virtual character named Tracy. The course covers commands, functions, loops, variables, conditionals, and lists, progressing to more complex tasks like user interaction and creating visual projects.&#xA;Topics include:&#xA;Commands Understanding basic commands is crucial as it forms the foundation of programming, allowing Tracy to perform specific actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex IQ Rapid Relay | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Vex-IQ-Rapid-Relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Vex-IQ-Rapid-Relay/</guid>
      <description>Join us for this exciting class! No experience necessary, only a desire to learn and have fun!&#xA;Together, we will build a competition-level robot, hone driving skills, and coding with this year&amp;rsquo;s game.&#xA;The scoring objects in VEX IQ Robotics Competition Rapid Relay are padded Balls, approximately 6&amp;quot; in diameter.&#xA;The primary objectives of the game are to Pass the Balls between Robots, score Balls through Targets, and Clear Switches. Balls are introduced to the field through the Loading Station or, during the last 15 seconds of a Match, a Rapid Load Zone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex IQ Robotics Competition (VIQRC) | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First-Lego-League-VEX-IQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First-Lego-League-VEX-IQ/</guid>
      <description>The VEX IQ Robotics Competition &#34;Rapid Relay&#34; takes place on a 6’ x 8’ rectangular field. In the Teamwork Challenge, two robots form an alliance and work together in 60-second matches to score points collaboratively.&#xA;Teams also participate in the Robot Skills Challenge, where a single robot aims to score as many points as possible. This challenge includes two types of matches: Driving Skills Matches, which are entirely driver-controlled, and Autonomous Coding Skills Matches, which are autonomous with minimal human interaction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Design | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video-Game-Design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video-Game-Design/</guid>
      <description>The video game design curriculum teaches the foundations of creating video games in JavaScript. While this course is introductory, it requires a good mathematical background and analytical thinking. Its curriculum teaches the foundations of computer science and basic programming, with an emphasis on helping students develop logical thinking and problem-solving skills. Once students complete the course, they will have learned material equivalent to a semester college introductory course in Computer Science and be able to program in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
