<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>6th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/6th/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 6th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/6th/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_Excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_Excellence/</guid>
      <description>This class is ideal for students looking to go beyond the typical school curriculum. Based on the renowned textbook by Art of Problem Solving founder Richard Rusczyk, the course emphasizes learning through problem-solving with instructors available to provide clarifying explanations. Instead of traditional lecturing, most of the class time is dedicated to tackling challenging problems. Students will be encouraged to write complete and clear solutions to exercises, an important skill in communicating mathematics effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banana Tales: Python Adventures for Grades 5-6 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana_Tales_Python_Adventures_for_Grades_5-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana_Tales_Python_Adventures_for_Grades_5-6/</guid>
      <description>Through interactive challenges, students help twin baby monkeys reunite by solving coding problems, reinforcing their understanding of Python fundamentals and advanced topics. The course covers essential concepts such as sequencing, loops, conditionals, functions, and introduces more complex topics like classes, string manipulation, and sorting algorithms. With step-by-step instructions, interactive quizzes, and a supportive learning environment, this course provides a fun and effective way for 5th and 6th graders to develop their programming skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Explorers: JavaScript Journey | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Code_Explorers_JavaScript_Journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Code_Explorers_JavaScript_Journey/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Code Explorers: JavaScript Journey&amp;rdquo; is an engaging introductory class designed to introduce middle school students to the world of JavaScript programming. This course takes students on an exciting adventure through the fundamentals of coding, using JavaScript as the vehicle for exploration. Through hands-on projects, interactive exercises, and creative problem-solving, students will discover the power of programming while building a solid foundation in JavaScript concepts. The class aims to spark curiosity, foster logical thinking, and empower young learners to create their own web-based projects, setting them on a path to become the next generation of digital innovators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Drone Squad | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Female Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Girl-Powered Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming an all-girl team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Vex IQ Team! | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</guid>
      <description>Calling all creative, curious, and tech-savvy girls and their supporters! We&#39;re forming a new majority-girl VEX IQ robotics team and we want YOU to be part of it!&#xA;What is VEX IQ? An exciting robotics competition for elementary and middle school students Design, build, and program your own robot Compete in fun challenges No experience needed! We&#39;re looking for: Future engineers and inventors Coders and problem-solvers Team players and leaders Girls who love to learn and have fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Boost for Fifth and Sixth Graders | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Boost_for_Fifth_and_Sixth_Graders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Boost_for_Fifth_and_Sixth_Graders/</guid>
      <description>This class is tailored for students who have been recommended for additional support and are facing challenges in their regular classroom. It offers reinforcement of key concepts through extra practice with typical grade-level problems, ensuring that students can grasp and master the material at their own pace. Additionally, students will have the opportunity to work on materials recommended by their classroom teacher and tackle problems suggested by Blue Ridge Boost instructors, providing a tailored and comprehensive approach to meet their individual learning needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middle School Competition Robotics Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First_Lego_League_ChallengeVEX_IQ_Robotics_Competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First_Lego_League_ChallengeVEX_IQ_Robotics_Competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First Lego League (FLL) is a Lego robotics competition for students grades 4 to 8. Teams engage in research, problem-solving, coding and engineering – building and programming a LEGO robot that navigates the missions of a robot game. As part of Challenge, teams also participate in a research project to identify and solve a relevant real-world problem. &lt;/p&gt; Team members must be willing to work on all aspects of the competition and demonstrate the &lt;b&gt;FIRST core values&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;br&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prealgebra EXcellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra_Excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra_Excellence/</guid>
      <description>Prealgebra prepares students for the rigors of algebra and teaches problem-solving techniques for prestigious middle school math contests such as MATHCOUNTS, MOEMS, and the AMC 8. The course challenges students at a much deeper level than a traditional middle school prealgebra course. Instead of traditional lecturing, most of the class time is dedicated to tackling challenging problems. Students will be encouraged to write complete and clear solutions to exercises, an important skill in communicating mathematics effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prealgebra Mastery| Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra_Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra_Mastery/</guid>
      <description>This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top 50% of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving: Math Olympiad, and AMC8 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</guid>
      <description>MOEMS is a challenging and engaging math competition for elementary and middle schoolers, featuring five monthly contests from November to March that focus on problem-solving and mathematical creativity. Similarly, the AMC 8 is a 40-minute math competition designed for students in grade 8 and below, covering a range of middle school math topics, including some concepts from introductory algebra. At Blue Ridge Boost, students participate in weekly problem-solving sessions to prepare for these competitions, and they have the option to take the tests if they choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rookie Aerial Drone Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming a team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex IQ Rapid Relay | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Vex_IQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Vex_IQ/</guid>
      <description>Join us for this exciting class! No experience necessary, only a desire to learn and have fun!&#xA;Together, we will build a competition-level robot, hone driving skills, and coding with this year&amp;rsquo;s game.&#xA;The scoring objects in VEX IQ Robotics Competition Rapid Relay are padded Balls, approximately 6&amp;quot; in diameter.&#xA;The primary objectives of the game are to Pass the Balls between Robots, score Balls through Targets, and Clear Switches. Balls are introduced to the field through the Loading Station or, during the last 15 seconds of a Match, a Rapid Load Zone.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
