<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/8th/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/8th/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Problem Solving: Math Olympiad, and AMC8 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Python | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you ready to take your Python skills to the next level?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt; Join our in-depth course designed to guide you through some of the most powerful and essential concepts in Python programming. This course is perfect for developers who have a basic understanding of Python and are eager to explore advanced topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 and 2 Boost | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Boost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Boost/</guid>
      <description>This class is suitable for students who need reinforcement of classroom concepts though extra practice with typical grade-level problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 and 2 Mastery| Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Mastery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/ftc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/ftc/</guid>
      <description>The FIRST Tech Challenge is a robotics competition for students in grades 7-12, where they design, build, and program robots to compete in tournaments, gaining hands-on engineering experience, and teamwork skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Drone Squad | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Female Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Girl-Powered Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming an all-girl team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</guid>
      <description>This is an inclusive STEM class with a focus on empowering girls. While all genders are welcome and encouraged to participate, we strive to maintain a majority female enrollment to address historical underrepresentation in STEM fields. Our goal is to create a supportive environment that inspires girls to explore and excel in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Vex IQ Team! | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</guid>
      <description>Calling all creative, curious, and tech-savvy girls and their supporters! We&#39;re forming a new majority-girl VEX IQ robotics team and we want YOU to be part of it!&#xA;What is VEX IQ? An exciting robotics competition for elementary and middle school students Design, build, and program your own robot Compete in fun challenges No experience needed! We&#39;re looking for: Future engineers and inventors Coders and problem-solvers Team players and leaders Girls who love to learn and have fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to AMC10 Competition Math | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro_to_AMC10_Competition_Math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro_to_AMC10_Competition_Math/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java for FTC: Robot Programming Essentials | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_FTC_Robot_Programming_Essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_FTC_Robot_Programming_Essentials/</guid>
      <description>The FIRST Tech Challenge (FTC) OnBot Java Course is designed to introduce students to the fundamentals of programming in Java within the context of robot development and competition. This course covers essential programming concepts such as variables, control structures, and object-oriented programming, as well as specific skills needed to program FTC robots using the OnBot Java environment. Students will learn how to write, test, and debug code for various robot functions like movement, sensor integration, and autonomous navigation. The course emphasizes hands-on learning, problem-solving, and teamwork, preparing participants for success in FTC competitions and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middle School Advanced Programming with JavaScript | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Middle_School_Advanced_Programming_with_JavaScript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Middle_School_Advanced_Programming_with_JavaScript/</guid>
      <description>The advanced middle school JavaScript course is designed to take students with a basic understanding of programming to the next level. The curriculum focuses on enhancing logical thinking and problem-solving skills through hands-on programming practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middle School Competition Robotics Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First_Lego_League_ChallengeVEX_IQ_Robotics_Competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First_Lego_League_ChallengeVEX_IQ_Robotics_Competition/</guid>
      <description>First Lego League (FLL) is a Lego robotics competion for students grades 4 to 8. Teams engage in research, problem-solving, coding and engineering – building and programming a LEGO robot that navigates the missions of a robot game. As part of Challenge, teams also participate in a research project to identify and solve a relevant real-world problem. Team members must be willing to work on all aspects of the competition and demostrate the FIRST core values.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prealgebra EXcellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_Excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_Excellence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Fundamentals: Coding from the Ground Up | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</guid>
      <description>This course is a comprehensive, year-long program designed for middle school students with no prior coding experience. It introduces fundamental programming concepts using Python through interactive exercises and projects centered around controlling a virtual character named Tracy. The course covers commands, functions, loops, variables, conditionals, and lists, progressing to more complex tasks like user interaction and creating visual projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rookie Aerial Drone Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
