<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8th on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/8th/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8th on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/8th/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aerial Drones | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</guid>
      <description>What is the Aerial Drone Competition? A cutting-edge program that prepares students for careers in drone technology Four exciting missions: Teamwork, Autonomous Flight, Piloting Skills, and Communications Compete in local, and regional events No prior experience needed! We&#39;re looking for students who are: Curious about drones and aviation Interested in coding and programming Excited to learn piloting skills Great at teamwork and communication Ready to take on new challenges Students are not required to participate in a Competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMC 8 Test | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/AMC8-2025-Test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/AMC8-2025-Test/</guid>
      <description>Are you excited about the AMC 8 but find that your school doesn&#39;t host the contest? No problem! You can sign up and take the test at Blue Ridge Boost. We offer a welcoming space for young math enthusiasts to test their skills and enjoy a rewarding competition experience.&#xA;The AMC 8 is a 25-question, 40-minute competition designed for students in grade 8 and below. The competition focuses on middle school mathematics topics, including counting and probability, estimation, proportional reasoning, elementary geometry (including the Pythagorean Theorem), spatial visualization, and interpreting graphs and tables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Algebra 1 Success Made Simple!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Algebra Sessions: Focused Learning: Small groups of 4 students Expert Guidance: Excel in your algebra homework Clear Explanations: Understand equations and functions Interactive Practice: Build problem-solving skills Weekly Sessions: 60 minutes each Comprehensive Coverage: All key Algebra 1 topics Boost Your Grades and ConfidenceEnroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Algebra Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Algebra 1 Success Made Simple!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Algebra Sessions: Focused Learning: Small groups of 4 students Expert Guidance: Excel in your algebra homework Clear Explanations: Understand equations and functions Interactive Practice: Build problem-solving skills Weekly Sessions: 60 minutes each Comprehensive Coverage: All key Algebra 1 topics Boost Your Grades and ConfidenceEnroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Algebra Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java for Teens | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java-For-Teens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java-For-Teens/</guid>
      <description>This beginner-friendly class is designed specifically for teens who are interested in learning computer programming using the Java language. Whether you&#39;re completely new to coding or have some prior experience, this course will provide a fun and interactive way to develop essential programming skills.&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn: Java Basics: Learn the fundamentals of Java, including variables, data types, and basic syntax. Programming Logic: Understand core programming concepts like loops, conditionals, and functions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity 2D Games | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Unity-2D-Games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Unity-2D-Games/</guid>
      <description>Explore the exciting world of game design and programming with Unity! These beginner-friendly courses are designed to teach students the fundamentals of game development while building fun and interactive projects. With hands-on lessons and real-world applications, students will learn to create their own games and bring their ideas to life using Unity&#39;s powerful tools.&#xA;Unit 1: 2D Beginner: Adventure GameStep into the world of 2D game development by creating an adventure game from scratch!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Python for Teens | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Python-For-Teens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Python-For-Teens/</guid>
      <description>Advanced Python for Teens builds on foundational Python skills and introduces students to more advanced programming concepts. This course is designed to help students create more powerful and efficient programs by exploring key topics such as functions, strings, data structures, and file input/output operations. Through engaging lessons, hands-on exercises, and creative projects, students will deepen their understanding of Python and develop practical problem-solving skills.&#xA;Course Highlights:&#xA;Functions and Exceptions: Learn how to decompose programs into smaller, reusable components and handle errors effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C# for Unity | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/C-Sharp-for-Unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/C-Sharp-for-Unity/</guid>
      <description>Unit 1: Introduction to C# Programming and Unity&#xA;Dive into the world of game development with this beginner-friendly unit, perfect for students with no prior programming experience. Learn the fundamentals of C# programming while exploring the basics of the Unity game engine, the industry-standard platform for creating interactive games. By the end of this unit, students will:&#xA;Understand the Unity interface and its core components. Learn foundational C# concepts such as variables, data types, and basic syntax.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Basics | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Deep-Learning-Basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Deep-Learning-Basics/</guid>
      <description>Discover the exciting world of deep learning and neural networks in this hands-on course, designed to build a strong foundation in artificial intelligence. Through interactive lessons and real-world projects, you&#39;ll gain the skills to design, build, and train deep learning models using Keras, a user-friendly and powerful library for AI development.&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn: Core Concepts: Understand the fundamentals of neural networks, deep learning models, and how they work. Supervised and Unsupervised Models: Explore supervised models like convolutional neural networks (CNNs) and recurrent neural networks (RNNs), as well as unsupervised models like autoencoders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Foundations with REV DUO | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Mechanical-Foundations-with-REV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Mechanical-Foundations-with-REV/</guid>
      <description>The Mechanical Foundations with REV DUO course provides participants with the hands-on skills and knowledge needed to design, build, and maintain robotic systems confidently. Through interactive projects and challenges, students will explore the foundational mechanical principles that drive robotics, such as structure, motion, power transmission, and mechanical advantage. Using the REV DUO building system, participants will gain practical experience assembling and testing robotic components while learning to solve real-world engineering challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education for Middle School | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Middle-School-Dec-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Middle-School-Dec-28/</guid>
      <description>🎮 Start Your Minecraft Adventure! 🎮&#xA;Join our beginner-friendly class and dive into the world of Minecraft!&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn:&#xA;🏗️ Building Basics: Master the essentials of crafting and construction. 🌿 Survival Skills: Learn how to gather resources and thrive in survival mode. 🗺️ Exploration Tips: Discover exciting biomes and hidden treasures. 👥 Multiplayer Fun: Connect with others and enjoy cooperative gameplay.&#xA;Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education for Middle School | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Middle-School-Feb-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Middle-School-Feb-8/</guid>
      <description>🎮 Start Your Minecraft Adventure! 🎮&#xA;Join our beginner-friendly class and dive into the world of Minecraft!&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn:&#xA;🏗️ Building Basics: Master the essentials of crafting and construction. 🌿 Survival Skills: Learn how to gather resources and thrive in survival mode. 🗺️ Exploration Tips: Discover exciting biomes and hidden treasures. 👥 Multiplayer Fun: Connect with others and enjoy cooperative gameplay.&#xA;Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education for Middle School | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Middle-School-Jan-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Middle-School-Jan-11/</guid>
      <description>🎮 Start Your Minecraft Adventure! 🎮&#xA;Join our beginner-friendly class and dive into the world of Minecraft!&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn:&#xA;🏗️ Building Basics: Master the essentials of crafting and construction. 🌿 Survival Skills: Learn how to gather resources and thrive in survival mode. 🗺️ Exploration Tips: Discover exciting biomes and hidden treasures. 👥 Multiplayer Fun: Connect with others and enjoy cooperative gameplay.&#xA;Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education for Middle School | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Middle-School-Jan-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Middle-School-Jan-25/</guid>
      <description>🎮 Start Your Minecraft Adventure! 🎮&#xA;Join our beginner-friendly class and dive into the world of Minecraft!&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn:&#xA;🏗️ Building Basics: Master the essentials of crafting and construction. 🌿 Survival Skills: Learn how to gather resources and thrive in survival mode. 🗺️ Exploration Tips: Discover exciting biomes and hidden treasures. 👥 Multiplayer Fun: Connect with others and enjoy cooperative gameplay.&#xA;Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Geometry Homework Made Easy!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Geometry Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of 4 studentsExpert help with your geometry homework Clear explanations of theorems and proofsHands-on problem-solving practice60-minute sessions weeklyCover all high school geometry topicsBoost your grades and confidenceTransform triangles and circles from foes to friends!&#xA;Enroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Geometry Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Geometry-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Geometry-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Geometry Homework Made Easy!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Geometry Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of 4 studentsExpert help with your geometry homework Clear explanations of theorems and proofsHands-on problem-solving practice60-minute sessions weeklyCover all high school geometry topicsBoost your grades and confidenceTransform triangles and circles from foes to friends!&#xA;Enroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Geometry Group today!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
