<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/8th/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/8th/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Problem Solving: Math Olympiad, and AMC8 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</guid>
      <description>MOEMS is a challenging and engaging math competition for middle schoolers, featuring five monthly contests from November to March that focus on problem-solving and mathematical creativity. Similarly, the AMC 8 is a 40-minute math competition designed for students in grade 8 and below, covering a range of middle school math topics, including some concepts from introductory algebra. At Blue Ridge Boost, students participate in weekly problem-solving sessions to prepare for these competitions, and they have the option to take the tests if they choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Python | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you ready to take your Python skills to the next level?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt; Join our in-depth course designed to guide you through some of the most powerful and essential concepts in Python programming. This course is perfect for developers who have a basic understanding of Python and are eager to explore advanced topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 and 2 Boost | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Boost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Boost/</guid>
      <description>This class is designed for students seeking reinforcement of classroom concepts through additional practice with grade-appropriate problems. &lt;br&gt; During a typical session, students will receive assistance with homework assignments and review concepts learned in school. As time allows, instructors will provide similar problems to further solidify understanding and boost confidence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 and 2 Mastery| Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Mastery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This class is designed for students performing in the top half of their grade level who occasionally need assistance with challenging homework problems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Focus:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing algebraic skills:&lt;/strong&gt; The class will delve deeper into algebraic concepts, providing students with the tools and techniques to tackle more complex problems.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepening understanding:&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond simply solving problems, the class will emphasize understanding the &#39;why&#39; behind the solutions, fostering a deeper comprehension of algebraic principles.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_Excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_Excellence/</guid>
      <description>This class is ideal for students looking to go beyond the typical school curriculum. Based on the renowned textbook by Art of Problem Solving founder Richard Rusczyk, the course emphasizes learning through problem-solving with instructors available to provide clarifying explanations. Instead of traditional lecturing, most of the class time is dedicated to tackling challenging problems. Students will be encouraged to write complete and clear solutions to exercises, an important skill in communicating mathematics effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/ftc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/ftc/</guid>
      <description>The FIRST Tech Challenge is an exciting robotics program for students in grades 7-12, allowing teams of up to 15 members to design, build, program, and operate robots in a head-to-head competition structured in an alliance format. However, it’s way more than just building robots. Guided by dedicated adult coaches and mentors, students not only develop essential STEM skills but also engage in practicing core engineering principles. Throughout the process, they learn the importance of hard work, innovation, and teamwork. This hands-on experience helps students realize the value of collaboration and creativity, preparing them for future challenges in both academic and professional settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Drone Squad | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Female Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Girl-Powered Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming an all-girl team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</guid>
      <description>This is an inclusive STEM class with a focus on empowering girls. While all genders are welcome and encouraged to participate, we strive to maintain a majority female enrollment to address historical underrepresentation in STEM fields. Our goal is to create a supportive environment that inspires girls to explore and excel in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Vex IQ Team! | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</guid>
      <description>Calling all creative, curious, and tech-savvy girls and their supporters! We&#39;re forming a new majority-girl VEX IQ robotics team and we want YOU to be part of it!&#xA;What is VEX IQ?&#xD;An exciting robotics competition for elementary and middle school students&#xD;Design, build, and program your own robot&#xD;Compete in fun challenges&#xD;No experience needed! We&#39;re looking for:&#xD;Future engineers and inventors&#xD;Coders and problem-solvers&#xD;Team players and leaders&#xD;Girls who love to learn and have fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to AMC10 Competition Math | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro_to_AMC10_Competition_Math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro_to_AMC10_Competition_Math/</guid>
      <description>The AMC 10 (American Mathematics Competitions 10) is a prestigious mathematics contest in the United States designed for students aged 10 through 16, or those enrolled in grades 10 and below. This challenging competition aims to cultivate problem-solving skills, foster mathematical creativity, and promote a deeper understanding of advanced mathematical concepts. With its rigorous content spanning algebra, geometry, number theory, and combinatorics, the AMC 10 serves as a gateway to higher-level math competitions. For students embarking on their competitive mathematics journey, the Blue Ridge Boost class offers a solid foundation, introducing key strategies and fundamental topics essential for success in the AMC 10 and beyond. Students enrolled in the class have the option to take the 2024 contests at Blue Ridge Boost. The class will continue for the duration of the school year to prepare students for the next year&amp;rsquo;s competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java for FTC: Robot Programming Essentials | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_FTC_Robot_Programming_Essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_FTC_Robot_Programming_Essentials/</guid>
      <description>The FIRST Tech Challenge (FTC) OnBot Java Course is designed to introduce students to the fundamentals of programming in Java within the context of robot development and competition. This course covers essential programming concepts such as variables, control structures, and object-oriented programming, as well as specific skills needed to program FTC robots using the OnBot Java environment. Students will learn how to write, test, and debug code for various robot functions like movement, sensor integration, and autonomous navigation. The course emphasizes hands-on learning, problem-solving, and teamwork, preparing participants for success in FTC competitions and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middle School Advanced Programming with JavaScript | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Middle_School_Advanced_Programming_with_JavaScript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Middle_School_Advanced_Programming_with_JavaScript/</guid>
      <description>The advanced middle school JavaScript course is designed to take students with a basic understanding of programming to the next level. The curriculum focuses on enhancing logical thinking and problem-solving skills through hands-on programming practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middle School Competition Robotics Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First_Lego_League_ChallengeVEX_IQ_Robotics_Competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First_Lego_League_ChallengeVEX_IQ_Robotics_Competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First Lego League (FLL) is a Lego robotics competion for students grades 4 to 8. Teams engage in research, problem-solving, coding and engineering – building and programming a LEGO robot that navigates the missions of a robot game. As part of Challenge, teams also participate in a research project to identify and solve a relevant real-world problem. &lt;/p&gt; Team members must be willing to work on all aspects of the competition and demostrate the &lt;b&gt;FIRST core values&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;br&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Fundamentals: Coding from the Ground Up | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</guid>
      <description>This course is a comprehensive, year-long program designed for middle school students with no prior coding experience. It introduces fundamental programming concepts using Python through interactive exercises and projects centered around controlling a virtual character named Tracy. The course covers commands, functions, loops, variables, conditionals, and lists, progressing to more complex tasks like user interaction and creating visual projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rookie Aerial Drone Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming a team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
