<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>10th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/10th/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 10th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/10th/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced C&#43;&#43;: Mastering Data Structures | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_C&#43;&#43;_Mastering_Data_Structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_C&#43;&#43;_Mastering_Data_Structures/</guid>
      <description>This course includes C++ fundamentals, basic data structures, file and error handling, STL containers, recursion, pointers, linked lists, and graphs. Each module has examples and assignments. A final project integrates multiple data structures to solve a real-world problem. The course prepares students for complex programming challenges in academic and professional settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Python | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you ready to take your Python skills to the next level?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt; Join our in-depth course designed to guide you through some of the most powerful and essential concepts in Python programming. This course is perfect for developers who have a basic understanding of Python and are eager to explore advanced topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 and 2 Mastery| Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_and_2_Mastery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This class is designed for students performing in the top half of their grade level who occasionally need assistance with challenging homework problems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Focus:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing algebraic skills:&lt;/strong&gt; The class will delve deeper into algebraic concepts, providing students with the tools and techniques to tackle more complex problems.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepening understanding:&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond simply solving problems, the class will emphasize understanding the &#39;why&#39; behind the solutions, fostering a deeper comprehension of algebraic principles.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/ftc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/ftc/</guid>
      <description>The FIRST Tech Challenge is an exciting robotics program for students in grades 7-12, allowing teams of up to 15 members to design, build, program, and operate robots in a head-to-head competition structured in an alliance format. However, it’s way more than just building robots. Guided by dedicated adult coaches and mentors, students not only develop essential STEM skills but also engage in practicing core engineering principles. Throughout the process, they learn the importance of hard work, innovation, and teamwork. This hands-on experience helps students realize the value of collaboration and creativity, preparing them for future challenges in both academic and professional settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Drone Squad | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Female Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Girl-Powered Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming an all-girl team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</guid>
      <description>This is an inclusive STEM class with a focus on empowering girls. While all genders are welcome and encouraged to participate, we strive to maintain a majority female enrollment to address historical underrepresentation in STEM fields. Our goal is to create a supportive environment that inspires girls to explore and excel in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to AMC10 Competition Math | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro_to_AMC10_Competition_Math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro_to_AMC10_Competition_Math/</guid>
      <description>The AMC 10 (American Mathematics Competitions 10) is a prestigious mathematics contest in the United States designed for students aged 10 through 16, or those enrolled in grades 10 and below. This challenging competition aims to cultivate problem-solving skills, foster mathematical creativity, and promote a deeper understanding of advanced mathematical concepts. With its rigorous content spanning algebra, geometry, number theory, and combinatorics, the AMC 10 serves as a gateway to higher-level math competitions. For students embarking on their competitive mathematics journey, the Blue Ridge Boost class offers a solid foundation, introducing key strategies and fundamental topics essential for success in the AMC 10 and beyond. Students enrolled in the class have the option to take the 2024 contests at Blue Ridge Boost. The class will continue for the duration of the school year to prepare students for the next year&amp;rsquo;s competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java for FTC: Robot Programming Essentials | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_FTC_Robot_Programming_Essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_FTC_Robot_Programming_Essentials/</guid>
      <description>The FIRST Tech Challenge (FTC) OnBot Java Course is designed to introduce students to the fundamentals of programming in Java within the context of robot development and competition. This course covers essential programming concepts such as variables, control structures, and object-oriented programming, as well as specific skills needed to program FTC robots using the OnBot Java environment. Students will learn how to write, test, and debug code for various robot functions like movement, sensor integration, and autonomous navigation. The course emphasizes hands-on learning, problem-solving, and teamwork, preparing participants for success in FTC competitions and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React Native Mobile App Development for High School Students | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/React_Native_Mobile_App_Development_for_High_School_Students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/React_Native_Mobile_App_Development_for_High_School_Students/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;React Native Mobile App Development for High School Students&amp;rdquo; course is designed to equip students with the skills to create dynamic and scalable mobile applications. Over the course of a year, students will delve into the React Native framework, learning to use components, stylesheets, state management, and more to build apps that run seamlessly on their smartphones. With a mix of web-based and hands-on activities, including collaborative exercises and digital presentations, students will gain practical experience in mobile app development. This course is ideal for those with prior knowledge in JavaScript and web design, providing an engaging and comprehensive introduction to the world of mobile app creation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rookie Aerial Drone Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming a team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Design in JavaScript | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video_Game_Design_in_JavaScript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video_Game_Design_in_JavaScript/</guid>
      <description>The video game design curriculum teaches the foundations of creating video games in JavaScript. While this course is introductory, it requires a good mathematical background and analytical thinking. Its curriculum teaches the foundations of computer science and basic programming, with an emphasis on helping students develop logical thinking and problem-solving skills. Once students complete the course, they will have learned material equivalent to a semester college introductory course in Computer Science and be able to program in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
