<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robotics on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robotics on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/ftc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/ftc/</guid>
      <description>The FIRST Tech Challenge is a robotics competition for students in grades 7-12, where they design, build, and program robots to compete in tournaments, gaining hands-on engineering experience, and teamwork skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Drone Squad | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Female Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Girl-Powered Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming an all-girl team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</guid>
      <description>This is an inclusive STEM class with a focus on empowering girls. While all genders are welcome and encouraged to participate, we strive to maintain a majority female enrollment to address historical underrepresentation in STEM fields. Our goal is to create a supportive environment that inspires girls to explore and excel in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered TechQuest: Fall Bots &amp; Spring Bricks | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_TechQuest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_TechQuest/</guid>
      <description>This inclusive STEM class is dedicated to empowering girls, while warmly welcoming and encouraging participation from all genders. Scholarships are available to ensure that financial limitations do not prevent students from joining.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Vex IQ Team! | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</guid>
      <description>Calling all creative, curious, and tech-savvy girls and their supporters! We&#39;re forming a new majority-girl VEX IQ robotics team and we want YOU to be part of it!&#xA;What is VEX IQ? An exciting robotics competition for elementary and middle school students Design, build, and program your own robot Compete in fun challenges No experience needed! We&#39;re looking for: Future engineers and inventors Coders and problem-solvers Team players and leaders Girls who love to learn and have fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Junior Robotics Adventures: Dino Quests &amp; Lego Explorers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Junior_Robotics_Adventures_Dino_Quests_Lego_Explorers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Junior_Robotics_Adventures_Dino_Quests_Lego_Explorers/</guid>
      <description>Embark on an exciting year-long journey where young learners explore basic robotics concepts through themed challenges, including Jurassic adventures with Sphero indi in the fall and collaborative Lego robotics projects in the spring, fostering critical thinking, teamwork, and creativity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middle School Competition Robotics Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First_Lego_League_ChallengeVEX_IQ_Robotics_Competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First_Lego_League_ChallengeVEX_IQ_Robotics_Competition/</guid>
      <description>First Lego League (FLL) is a Lego robotics competion for students grades 4 to 8. Teams engage in research, problem-solving, coding and engineering – building and programming a LEGO robot that navigates the missions of a robot game. As part of Challenge, teams also participate in a research project to identify and solve a relevant real-world problem. Team members must be willing to work on all aspects of the competition and demostrate the FIRST core values.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Discovery for 1st and 2nd Grades | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_1st_and_2nd_Grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_1st_and_2nd_Grades/</guid>
      <description>This class offers a fun and gentle introduction to robotics for students in 1st and 2nd grade, progressively building skills and knowledge through Vex 123, Lego Spike Essential, and Sphero Indie Robotics modules over the academic year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Discovery for 2nd and 3rd Grades | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_2nd_and_3rd_Grades-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_2nd_and_3rd_Grades-copy/</guid>
      <description>This class offers a progressive, hands-on introduction to robotics for students in grades 2 and 3, covering Vex GO, Lego Spike Essential, and Sphero Bolt Robotics throughout the academic year, while developing problem-solving, critical thinking, and teamwork skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Discovery for 4 and 5 Grades | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_4_and_5_Graders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_4_and_5_Graders/</guid>
      <description>This class offers a gentle, engaging introduction to robotics for students in grades 3 and 4. The curriculum is designed to build skills and knowledge throughout the academic year progressively:&#xA;Fall: VEX GO module Learn basic robotics concepts and simple programming Winter: Lego Spike Prime Explore more advanced building and coding techniques Spring: Sphero Bolt Robotics Apply learned skills to program spherical robots Our hands-on approach ensures students gain practical experience with different robotic platforms while developing problem-solving, critical thinking, and teamwork skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Explorations: Jurassic Journeys &amp; Future Discoveries | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Explorations_Jurassic_Journeys_Future_Discoveries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Explorations_Jurassic_Journeys_Future_Discoveries/</guid>
      <description>Embark on an exciting year-long journey where young learners explore basic robotics concepts through themed challenges, including Jurassic adventures with Sphero indi in the fall and collaborative Lego projects in the spring, fostering critical thinking, teamwork, and creativity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rookie Aerial Drone Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechQuest: Fall Bots &amp; Spring Bricks | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/TechQuest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/TechQuest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
