<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robotics on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robotics on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aerial Drones | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</guid>
      <description>What is the Aerial Drone Competition? A cutting-edge program that prepares students for careers in drone technology Four exciting missions: Teamwork, Autonomous Flight, Piloting Skills, and Communications Compete in local, and regional events No prior experience needed! We&#39;re looking for students who are: Curious about drones and aviation Interested in coding and programming Excited to learn piloting skills Great at teamwork and communication Ready to take on new challenges Students are not required to participate in a Competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drones 2-Day Winter Camp | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/Winter-24-Drones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/Winter-24-Drones/</guid>
      <description>Learn to find and modify 3D printing models.&#xA;Learn to create your own design.&#xA;Take home your creations.&#xA;Before and after care is available!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Challenge 2-Day Winter Camp | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/Winter-24-3D-Print/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/Winter-24-3D-Print/</guid>
      <description>Join us for an exciting 2-day immersive experience at the First Lego League Challenge Winter Camp! This hands-on camp is designed for young innovators, problem-solvers, and future engineers passionate about robotics, teamwork, and STEM. Participants will dive into the world of LEGO robotics, learn coding skills, and tackle real-world challenges of this year&#39;s First Lego League Challenge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-1/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the world of Lego robotics Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-2/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the world of Lego robotics Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-3/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the world of Lego robotics Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-on-Saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-on-Saturday/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the world of Lego robotics Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Drone Squad | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-Drone-Squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-Drone-Squad/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Female Drone Pilots and Engineers!&#xA;Join our Girl-Powered Aerial Drone Competition Team! Are you ready to soar into the future of technology? We&#39;re forming an all-girl team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition, and we want YOU to be part of this exciting adventure! What is the Aerial Drone Competition?&#xA;• A cutting-edge program that prepares students for careers in drone technology&#xA;• Four exciting missions: Teamwork, Autonomous Flight, Piloting Skills, and Communications</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-First-Tech-Challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-First-Tech-Challenge/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;re forming a new FIRST Tech Challenge team and we want GIRLS!&#xA;This is an inclusive STEM class with a focus on empowering girls. While all genders are welcome and encouraged to participate, we strive to maintain a majority female enrollment to address historical underrepresentation in STEM fields. Our goal is to create a supportive environment that inspires girls to explore and excel in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.&#xA;What is FIRST Tech Challenge?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lego Robots Jr | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-of-Coding-with-SPIKE-Essential-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-of-Coding-with-SPIKE-Essential-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>This four-class sequence introduces the students to the world of robotics and coding. Students will construct Lego models that use motors and lights and create code to bring their creations to life. This class is suitable for students with no previous experience using Lego robots. Introducing the Next Generation of Coders! The Fundamentals of Coding with SPIKE Essential is the fun and engaging way to teach your elementary students essential STEM skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Discovery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Discovery-4-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Discovery-4-5/</guid>
      <description>This class offers a gentle, engaging introduction to robotics for students in grades 4 and 5. The curriculum is designed to build skills and knowledge throughout the academic year progressively:&#xA;Fall: VEX GO module - Learn basic robotics concepts and simple programmingWinter: Lego Spike Prime - Explore more advanced building and coding techniquesSpring: Sphero Bolt Robotics - Apply learned skills to program spherical robotsOur hands-on approach ensures students gain practical experience with different robotic platforms while developing problem-solving, critical thinking, and teamwork skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring Break Camp | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/Spring-Break-24-Camp-1-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/Spring-Break-24-Camp-1-3/</guid>
      <description>Sphero robots in the morning and Scratch coding in the afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring Break Camp | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/Spring-Break-24-Camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/Spring-Break-24-Camp/</guid>
      <description>Python coding in the morning and Lego Robotics in the afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex IQ Rapid Relay | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Vex-IQ-Rapid-Relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Vex-IQ-Rapid-Relay/</guid>
      <description>Join us for this exciting class! No experience necessary, only a desire to learn and have fun!&#xA;Together, we will build a competition-level robot, hone driving skills, and coding with this year&amp;rsquo;s game.&#xA;The scoring objects in VEX IQ Robotics Competition Rapid Relay are padded Balls, approximately 6&amp;quot; in diameter.&#xA;The primary objectives of the game are to Pass the Balls between Robots, score Balls through Targets, and Clear Switches. Balls are introduced to the field through the Loading Station or, during the last 15 seconds of a Match, a Rapid Load Zone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex IQ Robotics Competition (VIQRC) | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First-Lego-League-VEX-IQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First-Lego-League-VEX-IQ/</guid>
      <description>The VEX IQ Robotics Competition &#34;Rapid Relay&#34; takes place on a 6’ x 8’ rectangular field. In the Teamwork Challenge, two robots form an alliance and work together in 60-second matches to score points collaboratively.&#xA;Teams also participate in the Robot Skills Challenge, where a single robot aims to score as many points as possible. This challenge includes two types of matches: Driving Skills Matches, which are entirely driver-controlled, and Autonomous Coding Skills Matches, which are autonomous with minimal human interaction.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
