<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Monday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Monday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-1-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-1-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Integrated Math 1 Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help:&#xA;Groups of 4 students60-minute focused sessions every weekDirect assistance with your current homeworkStep-by-step guidance on tough problemsCover all Integrated Math 1 topics as they ariseAlgebra, geometry, and statistics supportImprove grades and build confidenceTurn homework struggles into success stories!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Integrated-Math-1-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Integrated-Math-1-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Integrated Math 1 Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help:&#xA;Groups of 4 students60-minute focused sessions every weekDirect assistance with your current homeworkStep-by-step guidance on tough problemsCover all Integrated Math 1 topics as they ariseAlgebra, geometry, and statistics supportImprove grades and build confidenceTurn homework struggles into success stories!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Quest | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Code-Quest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Code-Quest/</guid>
      <description>Banana Code Quest is a gamified coding course designed to teach young students real-world coding from the first challenge. Through engaging puzzles and adventures, students help a monkey catch bananas and outsmart various animals while learning fundamental and advanced coding concepts in a fun and interactive way.&#xA;Key Features Real Coding Language: Students will code using CoffeeScript, a language similar to JavaScript but with a friendlier syntax, making it perfect for kids.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-3/</guid>
      <description>Dive into an exciting new season of FIRST LEGO League with the 2024-2025 theme: SUBMERGED! This year’s challenge invites participants to explore the mysteries and wonders of underwater environments while solving real-world challenges related to oceans, lakes, and waterways.&#xA;Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python for Kids | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Basics/</guid>
      <description>Through interactive challenges, students help twin baby monkeys reunite by solving coding problems, reinforcing their understanding of Python fundamentals and advanced topics. The course covers essential concepts such as sequencing, loops, conditionals, and functions. Course Content Sequencing: Understanding the order of instructions is crucial for programming logic. Lists &amp; Indexing: Learning to store and access multiple items efficiently. For loops: Iterating over sequences to automate repetitive tasks. Variables: Storing data that can be used and modified throughout the program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics with Vex IQ | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Vex-IQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Vex-IQ/</guid>
      <description>Description:&#xA;Join us at Blue Ridge Boost for an exciting, hands-on journey into coding and computational thinking with the VEX IQ (2nd Generation) robotics platform! Using the structured curriculum from the Carnegie Mellon Robotics Academy, this class introduces students to the fundamentals of robotics programming, problem-solving, and real-world applications.&#xA;Designed for beginners and enthusiasts, the course features engaging, project-based activities that teach students to build, program, and control their robots using the VEXcode programming software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Geometry Homework Made Easy!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Geometry Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of 4 studentsExpert help with your geometry homework Clear explanations of theorems and proofsHands-on problem-solving practice60-minute sessions weeklyCover all high school geometry topicsBoost your grades and confidenceTransform triangles and circles from foes to friends!&#xA;Enroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Geometry Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Geometry-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Geometry-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Geometry Homework Made Easy!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Geometry Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of 4 studentsExpert help with your geometry homework Clear explanations of theorems and proofsHands-on problem-solving practice60-minute sessions weeklyCover all high school geometry topicsBoost your grades and confidenceTransform triangles and circles from foes to friends!&#xA;Enroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Geometry Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Boost | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-3-4/</guid>
      <description>This class is tailored for students who are in the top half of the class, but need clarifications of some grade-level concepts. It offers reinforcement of key concepts through extra practice with typical grade-level problems, ensuring that students can grasp and master the material at their own pace. Additionally, students will have the opportunity to work on materials recommended by their classroom teacher and tackle problems suggested by Blue Ridge Boost instructors, providing a tailored and comprehensive approach to meet their individual learning needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Boost | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-5-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-5-6/</guid>
      <description>This class is tailored for students who are in the top half of the class, but need clarifications of some grade-level concepts. It offers reinforcement of key concepts through extra practice with typical grade-level problems, ensuring that students can grasp and master the material at their own pace. Additionally, students will have the opportunity to work on materials recommended by their classroom teacher and tackle problems suggested by Blue Ridge Boost instructors, providing a tailored and comprehensive approach to meet their individual learning needs.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
