<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Coding, Math, and Robotics Camps in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Coding, Math, and Robotics Camps in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Engineering | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-adventures-in-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-adventures-in-engineering/</guid>
      <description>The Vex Adventures in Engineering camp offers an engaging hands-on experience where campers design and build with VEX GO kits. Through a series of STEM lab units and activities, participants learn about simple machines, energy transfer, and the mechanics of movement. They engage in building and testing structures like inclined planes, levers, spring cars, and gears, deepening their understanding of engineering principles and the design process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Structures in Java | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/data-structures-and-algorithms-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/data-structures-and-algorithms-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Elevate your programming skills with our intensive Java course! Dive deep into the world of Data Structures and Algorithms, essential knowledge for any serious programmer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLL/FTC Preason</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/fll-ftc-preseason/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/fll-ftc-preseason/</guid>
      <description>Are you curious about robotics, science, and teamwork? Join the Blue Ridge Boost teams for a week-long introduction to FIRST LEGO League Challenge (FLL Challenge) and FIRST Tech Challenge (FTC).&#xA;Students in grades 4-8 are invited to morning sessions focused on FLL Challenge robotics, learning alongside experienced Blue Ridge Boost team members.&#xA;Students in grades 7-12 can work with our rookie FTC team, learning about the program and helping build our first FTC robot.&#xA;This week-long program offers hands-on experience with robotics, programming, and collaborative problem-solving for both beginners and those looking to expand their skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Design in Unity | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/unity/</guid>
      <description>Game Design in Unity teaches the fundamentals of designing a game using the most widely accessed and preferred editing engine in the world. By the end of this course, campers will understand the design planning process, be able to navigate the Unity environment in order to create 3D games, and create their own game as a course project. The course follows the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.unity.com/pathway/unity-essentials&#34;&gt;Unity Essential Pathway&lt;/a&gt; curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Counting and Probability | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/intro-to-counting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/intro-to-counting/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Counting and Probability is a course designed for advanced middle school students to learn the fundamentals of counting techniques and probability theory. The course follows the textbook of the same name by David Patrick.&#xA;The class is targeted at students who have mastered basic algebra skills like solving linear equations. It is ideal for middle school students preparing for math competitions like MATHCOUNTS and AMC8, and any student looking to develop a strong foundation in counting and probability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Java | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/intro-to-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/intro-to-java/</guid>
      <description>Students will master Java commands and syntax through a combination of daily practice and expert instructor guidance. This intensive approach ensures that learners receive continuous, hands-on experience, which is essential for mastering any programming language. By engaging with real-world coding challenges and receiving personalized feedback, students can identify and address their weaknesses, steadily improving their skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Number Theory | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/intro-to-number-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/intro-to-number-theory/</guid>
      <description>The Introduction to Number Theory course offered by Blue Ridge Boost is designed for advanced middle school students who are interested in gaining a deep understanding of number theory. The course utilizes the Introduction to Number Theory textbook by Mathew Crawford, which is a comprehensive resource covering essential topics in the field.&#xA;The course focuses on a range of fundamental topics in number theory, including: primes and composites, multiples and divisors, prime factorization and its applications, number bases, modular arithmetic, divisibility rules, linear congruences, and developing number sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Programming with Karel the Dog | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/intro-to-programming-karel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/intro-to-programming-karel/</guid>
      <description>Join us for an exciting adventure with Karel the Dog in our specially designed Intro to Programming course! Perfect for middle school students with no coding experience.&lt;br&gt;🐶 Why Karel the Dog? Karel is not just any dog — he’s your gateway to the world of coding! In a fun, grid-based world, you’ll teach Karel to perform tasks, maneuver obstacles, and solve puzzles, all through programming. Campers will work through the challenges at their own pace under the expert guidance of Blue Ridge Boost instructors. Full-day campers are expected to complete almost all units.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn to code with Code Monkey Jr | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/code-monkey-scratch-jr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/code-monkey-scratch-jr/</guid>
      <description>The coding camp offers a comprehensive learning experience, combining structured morning sessions using Code Monkey Jr with creative afternoon projects using PBS KIDS ScratchJr. Mornings focus on fundamental coding concepts, progressing from basic sequencing to loops, advanced loops, conditional looping, and procedures. Afternoons engage campers in themed projects inspired by popular PBS shows, exploring topics like animal abilities, odd patterns, plant growth, decision-making, and space exploration. This balanced approach allows children to build strong coding foundations while applying their skills to fun, interactive projects, fostering both technical knowledge and creativity throughout the week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Compete with Lego Spike Prime</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/lets-compete/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/lets-compete/</guid>
      <description>Dive into our five-day advanced robotics camp designed for middle school students. This hands-on program enhances STEM learning, promoting critical 21st-century skills through daily challenges and collaborative projects. Students will tackle real-world problems, creating innovative solutions and pitching them to stakeholders. Prepare for a transformative learning experience that combines teamwork, engineering, and programming in an engaging environment.&lt;br&gt;The camp is recommended to students with little or no experience with Lego Spike Prime.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living in Space | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/living-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/living-in-space/</guid>
      <description>Perfect for kids aged 6-7, this exciting camp combines the creative power of LEGO with the thrilling world of space exploration. Campers will build and program their own space-themed robots using LEGO WeDo kits, engage in team missions that simulate real-life space challenges, and learn about the science of space travel from expert STEM educators. Sign up now to give your young astronaut a summer filled with innovation, teamwork, and interstellar adventure! 🚀🛠️</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make your own games | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/make-your-own-game-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/make-your-own-game-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Make Your Own Games camp is an immersive week-long adventure where kids aged 10-13 can dive into the exciting world of game design using CodeMonkey&amp;rsquo;s Game Builder course. This camp is designed to teach fundamental coding and game design concepts through engaging, hands-on activities and projects. &lt;br&gt; Skills Developed &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coding:&lt;/strong&gt; Learn to code using CoffeeScript, a simple yet powerful language.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Design:&lt;/strong&gt; Understand the principles of game mechanics, user interface design, and animation.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem-Solving:&lt;/strong&gt; Develop critical thinking and problem-solving skills through coding challenges.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration:&lt;/strong&gt; Work in teams to create and refine game projects.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creativity:&lt;/strong&gt; Use imagination to design unique games and animations.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Camp | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/math-camp-jr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/math-camp-jr/</guid>
      <description>Campers engage in a day of math exploration, starting with Beast Academy Puzzles 1&amp;rsquo;s varied challenges that build critical thinking and problem-solving skills. The afternoon features Singapore Math Intensive Practice 1A, offering diverse questions to deepen elementary math understanding. Both programs provide engaging, skill-building activities for capable learners of different ages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Camp| Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/contest-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/contest-math/</guid>
      <description>Blue Ridge Boost offers a dynamic course based on &lt;i&gt;Art of Problem Solving, Volume 1: The Basics&lt;/i&gt;, designed to enhance mathematical skills for advanced middle school students. This program, ideal for those preparing for contests like MathCounts or AMC 8/10, builds essential problem-solving abilities and fosters critical thinking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ready, Set, GO | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-ready-set-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-ready-set-go/</guid>
      <description>Campers will engage in building and racing various cars to explore the concepts of forces and speed! They will start by constructing a Super Car and experimenting with ways to enhance its distance and speed. Over the course of the camp, they will expand on this foundation by assembling different models of the Super Car. This progression will allow them to investigate the dynamics of how these models move, culminating in coding and operating both the Code Super Car and the Code Base.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scratch Camp | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/scratch/</guid>
      <description>Ignite Creativity with Scratch Camp! This summer, give your child aged 8-9 the opportunity to dive into the world of coding with our Scratch Camp. Using Scratch, a kid-friendly programming language from MIT, campers will learn to code their own games, animations, and stories. Our experienced instructors will guide them through the fundamentals of coding while fostering critical thinking and creativity. oin us for a summer of fun, learning, and digital creation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Adventure | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/space-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/space-adventure/</guid>
      <description>Campers will embark on an immersive Space Odyssey using advanced robotics. They will design and build robotic explorers, mastering motor control for precise maneuvers around celestial models. Using force sensors, they will navigate cosmic obstacles and program their robots for mission-critical tasks. This hands-on adventure blends robotics, coding, and space science, challenging campers to apply engineering principles and problem-solving skills. Working in teams, they will tackle increasingly complex missions while learning about the solar system and space exploration. This STEM-focused program ignites passion for innovation, combining the thrill of space discovery with cutting-edge robotics technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex Robotics and C&#43;&#43; | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-c&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-c&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>In the morning, campers immerse themselves in VEX IQ robotics, building and enhancing robots for exciting challenges like Robot Soccer and Tug of War. Campers explore mechanical concepts and engage in collaborative strategy sessions, honing their technical skills. The program emphasizes teamwork and communication, providing a well-rounded experience that prepares participants for future success in various fields.&lt;br&gt;In the afternoon, young coders dive into a challenging curriculum that explores complex programming concepts such as data structures and algorithms. Through real-world projects, participants gain hands-on experience in applying these advanced topics. Expert instructors guide students throughout the camp, helping them enhance their programming skills and strengthen their problem-solving abilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex123 Move it! Shake it! | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-move-it-shake-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-move-it-shake-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The adventure kicks off as students program their robots to navigate a predefined path, giving them their initial experience in motion control. The excitement builds as they delve into coding dance movements, transforming their robots into lively partying peacocks, showcasing their creativity and understanding of motion sequences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The culmination of the program involves a dynamic bowling activity where students code the robot to knock down pins and even crash into a tower, applying their accumulated skills in a challenging and enjoyable way. This comprehensive approach not only teaches robotics and coding but also fosters creativity, problem-solving, and teamwork among the campers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex123 Space Race | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-space-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/vex-space-race/</guid>
      <description>In the Space Race Camp, campers meet “VEX,” the 123 Robot through a fun and interactive story and establish a set of rules and practices for working with the robot. Then, campers imagine their robot as a Mars rover and complete several missions including coding their robot to collect samples and return them to base camp for delivering to Earth. Then, campers will use the Eye Sensor to detect objects and clear the landing area for future missions. In the afternoons, the campers use the Art Ring and craft materials to transform the Vex123 robot into a variety of animals.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
