<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coding on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Foundations with REV DUO | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Mechanical-Foundations-with-REV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Mechanical-Foundations-with-REV/</guid>
      <description>The Mechanical Foundations with REV DUO course provides participants with the hands-on skills and knowledge needed to design, build, and maintain robotic systems confidently. Through interactive projects and challenges, students will explore the foundational mechanical principles that drive robotics, such as structure, motion, power transmission, and mechanical advantage. Using the REV DUO building system, participants will gain practical experience assembling and testing robotic components while learning to solve real-world engineering challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C# for Unity | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/C-Sharp-for-Unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/C-Sharp-for-Unity/</guid>
      <description>Unit 1: Introduction to C# Programming and Unity&#xA;Dive into the world of game development with this beginner-friendly unit, perfect for students with no prior programming experience. Learn the fundamentals of C# programming while exploring the basics of the Unity game engine, the industry-standard platform for creating interactive games. By the end of this unit, students will:&#xA;Understand the Unity interface and its core components. Learn foundational C# concepts such as variables, data types, and basic syntax.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1-Day Camp; Apr 18, 2025 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/one-day-2025-04-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/one-day-2025-04-18/</guid>
      <description>Join us for an exhilarating exploration of robotics, coding, chess, and math. Teamwork and collaboration are at the heart of our camp experience. Students will have the opportunity to work together, share ideas, and solve challenges. Through hands-on activities and group projects, students will develop critical thinking skills and learn the importance of effective communication.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1-Day Camp; Apr 28, 2025 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/one-day-2025-04-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/one-day-2025-04-28/</guid>
      <description>Join us for an exhilarating exploration of robotics, coding, chess, and math. Teamwork and collaboration are at the heart of our camp experience. Students will have the opportunity to work together, share ideas, and solve challenges. Through hands-on activities and group projects, students will develop critical thinking skills and learn the importance of effective communication.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
