<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutors on Coding and Math Classes and Tutoring in Charlottesville</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/</link><description>Recent content in Tutors on Coding and Math Classes and Tutoring in Charlottesville</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Algebra 2 Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/algebra2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/algebra2/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in algebra and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum. Our services include an Algebra 1 review before school starts, ongoing support with classroom content, and new topics and lessons.
Get Ready for Algebra 2! Join our summer classes in August, to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review Algebra 1, including linear functions, linear equations and systems of equations, exponent laws, quadratic functions, and polynomials.</description></item><item><title>Algebra Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/algebra1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/algebra1/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in algebra and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum. Our services include a prealgebra review before school starts, ongoing support with classroom content, and new topics and lessons. Get Ready for Algebra 1! At Blue Ridge Boost, we strongly believe that math is not a spectator sport. Children learn math and become independent, confident mathematicians by solving a variety of problems.</description></item><item><title>AMC and MathCounts Coaching in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/amc-coach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/amc-coach/</guid><description>AMC Coach and Tutor in Charlottesville An experienced instructor with MathCounts and AMC8 coaching experience teaches mini-lessons on topics commonly found in competition math problems and leads students in solving practice problems.
The content of the class depends on the target competition and the student&amp;rsquo;s background. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch with us for further information.
For more details on our services, fill out the contact form or email nora@blueridgeboost.</description></item><item><title>AP&amp;reg; Calculus AB/BC Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/ap-calculus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/ap-calculus/</guid><description>Get Ready for AP Calculus AB/BC! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review linear, quadratic, polynomial, exponential, and trigonometric functions.
AP Calculus AB/BC Private Tutor Contact us to set up lessons and problem-solving sessions for AP Calculus AB/BC!
Click here to book a tutoring session.</description></item><item><title>AP&amp;reg; Computer Science Principles | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/ap-computer-science-principles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/ap-computer-science-principles/</guid><description>Contact us to set up private lessons with an experienced software engineer and tutor.
Click here to book a tutoring session.</description></item><item><title>AP&amp;reg; Computer Science Tutor in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/ap-computer-science-java/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/ap-computer-science-java/</guid><description>Contact us to set up private lessons with an experienced Java engineer and tutor.
Click here to book a tutoring session.</description></item><item><title>AP&amp;reg; Statistics Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/ap-statistics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/ap-statistics/</guid><description>Get Ready for AP Statistics! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review probabilities, statistics, and linear, quadratic, and exponential functions.
AP Statistics Private Tutoring Contact us to set up lessons and problem-solving sessions for AP Statistics!
Click here to book a tutoring session.</description></item><item><title>Computer Science Tutor | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/book-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/book-now/</guid><description>Book here!</description></item><item><title>Geometry Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/geometry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/geometry/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in geometry and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum. Our services include algebra and middle school geometry review before school starts, ongoing support with classroom content, and new topics and lessons.
Get Ready for Geometry At Blue Ridge Boost, we strongly believe that math is not a spectator sport. Children learn math and become independent, confident mathematicians by solving a variety of problems.</description></item><item><title>Math Tutoring for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/elementary-math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/elementary-math/</guid><description>At Blue Ridge Boost, we teach problem-solving skills using a variety of math manipulatives, Montessori materials, and math games. In addition, we use a variety of curricula based on the Virginia Standards of Learning, Common Core, Singapore Math®, and Beast Academy®.
Experienced instructors are ready to help your child develop a good understanding of the content, whether to keep up with classwork or expand knowledge beyond the school curriculum.</description></item><item><title>Math Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/book-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/book-now/</guid><description>Book here!</description></item><item><title>Middle School Math Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/middle-school-math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/middle-school-math/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in math and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum.
We help your child succeed in math and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum.
At Blue Ridge Boost, a qualified and experienced teacher assesses your student&amp;rsquo;s knowledge and builds an individualized instruction plan that targets weak areas while assisting with topics the student is learning.</description></item><item><title>Precalc Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/precalculus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/precalculus/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in precalculus and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum. Our services include an Algebra 2 review before school starts, ongoing support with classroom content, and new topics and lessons.
Get Ready for Math Analysis/Precalc! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review Algebra 2 and Trigonometry, including quadratic, exponential, polynomial, and trigonometric functions.</description></item><item><title>USA Computing Olympiad Coaching | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/usaco-computing-olympiad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/usaco-computing-olympiad/</guid><description>Contact us to get coaching for USA Computing Olympiad!
Click here to book a tutoring session.</description></item></channel></rss>