<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tuesday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Tuesday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tuesday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Tuesday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Python for Teens | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Python-For-Teens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Python-For-Teens/</guid>
      <description>Advanced Python for Teens builds on foundational Python skills and introduces students to more advanced programming concepts. This course is designed to help students create more powerful and efficient programs by exploring key topics such as functions, strings, data structures, and file input/output operations. Through engaging lessons, hands-on exercises, and creative projects, students will deepen their understanding of Python and develop practical problem-solving skills.&#xA;Course Highlights:&#xA;Functions and Exceptions: Learn how to decompose programs into smaller, reusable components and handle errors effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Block Coding with Beavers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block-Coding-with-Beavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block-Coding-with-Beavers/</guid>
      <description>Students learn sequencing, repetition, problem-solving, and conditional logic while developing practical coding skills. The course employs a hands-on, gamified approach that gradually increases in complexity, allowing each child to advance at their own speed. By the end, students can create sophisticated programs, having built a strong foundation in coding and computational thinking.&#xA;We start to learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a beaver build a dam! The learning continues with learning to code games in Scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scratch Coding | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Scratch-First-and-Second/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Scratch-First-and-Second/</guid>
      <description>Come and learn to code your own games in Scratch!&#xA;Each session will create a new game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics with Lego Spike | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Lego-Spike-Prime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Lego-Spike-Prime/</guid>
      <description>Jump into the world of robotics and coding with the LEGO Education SPIKE Prime system! This hands-on course introduces students to the exciting possibilities of robotics engineering and computational thinking through engaging, project-based learning. Designed for beginners to intermediate learners, this course will teach students how to design, build, and program robotic solutions to solve real-world challenges.&#xA;In this course, students will:&#xA;Learn the basics of robotics using the LEGO SPIKE Prime kit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lego Robots Jr | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-of-Coding-with-SPIKE-Essential-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-of-Coding-with-SPIKE-Essential-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>This four-class sequence introduces the students to the world of robotics and coding. Students will construct Lego models that use motors and lights and create code to bring their creations to life. This class is suitable for students with no previous experience using Lego robots. Introducing the Next Generation of Coders! The Fundamentals of Coding with SPIKE Essential is the fun and engaging way to teach your elementary students essential STEM skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Master Your AP Statistics Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help Sessions:&#xA;Intimate groups of 4 studentsFocused 90-minute sessions every weekDirect assistance with your AP Stats homeworkExpert guidance on complex statistical conceptsHelp with data analysis, probability, and inferenceSupport for statistical software and calculatorsImprove your grades and exam readinessTurn stats stumbling blocks into stepping stones!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s AP Statistics Homework Group</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Statistics-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Statistics-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Master Your AP Statistics Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help Sessions:&#xA;Intimate groups of 4 studentsFocused 90-minute sessions every weekDirect assistance with your AP Stats homeworkExpert guidance on complex statistical conceptsHelp with data analysis, probability, and inferenceSupport for statistical software and calculatorsImprove your grades and exam readinessTurn stats stumbling blocks into stepping stones!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s AP Statistics Homework Group</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precalculus | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Precalculus-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Precalculus-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Precalculus Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help:&#xA;Groups of 4 students60-minute focused sessions every weekDirect assistance with your current homeworkStep-by-step guidance on tough problemsCover all Precalculus topics as they ariseImprove grades and build confidenceTurn homework struggles into success stories!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precalculus | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Precalculus-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Precalculus-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Precalculus Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help:&#xA;Groups of 4 students60-minute focused sessions every weekDirect assistance with your current homeworkStep-by-step guidance on tough problemsCover all Precalculus topics as they ariseImprove grades and build confidenceTurn homework struggles into success stories!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
