<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tuesday on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Tuesday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tuesday on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Tuesday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Problem Solving: Math Olympiad, and AMC8 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Block Coding | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids_Coding_Course_Building_with_Beavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids_Coding_Course_Building_with_Beavers/</guid>
      <description>Students learn sequencing, repetition, problem-solving, and conditional logic while developing practical coding skills. The course employs a hands-on, gamified approach that gradually increases in complexity, allowing each child to advance at their own speed. By the end, students can create sophisticated programs, having built a strong foundation in coding and computational thinking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Hoppers: Kangaroo Math for Young Explorers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kangaroo_Competition_Math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kangaroo_Competition_Math/</guid>
      <description>The Kangaroo Mathematics Competition, set for Thursday, March 20, 2025, is an international event testing students&amp;rsquo; math skills. Preparation involves practicing past papers, reviewing key concepts, and improving time management. The multiple-choice test covers various math topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Leapers: Advanced Kangaroo Challenges | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Leapers_Advanced_Kangaroo_Challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Leapers_Advanced_Kangaroo_Challenges/</guid>
      <description>Preparation class for the Kangaroo Math Competition. The Kangaroo Mathematics Competition, set for Thursday, March 20, 2025.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving: Math Olympiad, and AMC8 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Fundamentals: Coding from the Ground Up | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</guid>
      <description>This course is a comprehensive, year-long program designed for middle school students with no prior coding experience. It introduces fundamental programming concepts using Python through interactive exercises and projects centered around controlling a virtual character named Tracy. The course covers commands, functions, loops, variables, conditionals, and lists, progressing to more complex tasks like user interaction and creating visual projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Design in JavaScript | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video_Game_Design_in_JavaScript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video_Game_Design_in_JavaScript/</guid>
      <description>The video game design curriculum teaches the foundations of creating video games in JavaScript. While this course is introductory, it requires a good mathematical background and analytical thinking. Its curriculum teaches the foundations of computer science and basic programming, with an emphasis on helping students develop logical thinking and problem-solving skills. Once students complete the course, they will have learned material equivalent to a semester college introductory course in Computer Science and be able to program in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
