<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wednesday on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Wednesday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wednesday on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Wednesday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Algebra | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Who should join?&#xA;This class is ideal for students who are generally doing well in their algebra class but:&#xA;Find some homework problems particularly difficult.Want to explore algebraic concepts in greater depth.Are looking for a challenge beyond their regular coursework. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banana Tales | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Tales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Tales/</guid>
      <description>Through interactive challenges, students help twin baby monkeys reunite by solving coding problems, reinforcing their understanding of Python fundamentals and advanced topics. The course covers essential concepts such as sequencing, loops, conditionals, functions, and introduces more complex topics like classes, string manipulation, and sorting algorithms. With step-by-step instructions, interactive quizzes, and a supportive learning environment, this course provides a fun and effective way for 5th and 6th graders to develop their programming skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculus AB/BC | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Calculus-AB-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Calculus-AB-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Calculus Homework!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost Small Group Sessions:&#xA;4 students per groupFocus on current homework assignmentsStep-by-step problem-solving guidanceExpert calculus tutor support90-minute sessionsCover all calculus topics in your curriculumAdditional practice problems for reinforcementTurn your homework headaches into &#39;Aha!&#39; moments!&#xA;Sign up for Blue Ridge Boost and ace your assignments!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League/VEX IQ | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First-Lego-League-VEX-IQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First-Lego-League-VEX-IQ/</guid>
      <description>First Lego League (FLL) is a Lego robotics competition for students grades 4 to 8. Teams engage in research, problem-solving, coding and engineering – building and programming a LEGO robot that navigates the missions of a robot game. As part of Challenge, teams also participate in a research project to identify and solve a relevant real-world problem. Team members must be willing to work on all aspects of the competition and demonstrate the FIRST core values.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-1-2/</guid>
      <description>This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles. Key Features: Advanced Mental Math Strategies: Students will be introduced to various mental math techniques to improve their calculation skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-3-4/</guid>
      <description>This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles. Key Features: Advanced Mental Math Strategies: Students will be introduced to various mental math techniques to improve their calculation skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles. Key Features: Advanced Mental Math Strategies: Students will be introduced to various mental math techniques to improve their calculation skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Statistics-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Statistics-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Master Your AP Statistics Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help Sessions:&#xA;Intimate groups of 4 studentsFocused 90-minute sessions every weekDirect assistance with your AP Stats homeworkExpert guidance on complex statistical conceptsHelp with data analysis, probability, and inferenceSupport for statistical software and calculatorsImprove your grades and exam readinessTurn stats stumbling blocks into stepping stones!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s AP Statistics Homework Group</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechQuest: Fall Bots &amp; Spring Bricks | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/TechQuest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/TechQuest/</guid>
      <description>Fall: The VEX GO Competition The VEX GO Competition (VGOC) is an introductory robotics program designed for elementary school students, typically ages 5-11. It uses the VEX GO building system, which features large, colorful, and easy-to-handle components. Teams of students work together to design, build, and program simple robots to complete challenges on a small playing field. The competition emphasizes hands-on learning, problem-solving, and teamwork while introducing young learners to basic engineering and coding concepts in a fun, engaging environment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
