<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thursday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Thursday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thursday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Thursday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Block Coding with Minecraft | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block-Coding-with-Minecraft-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block-Coding-with-Minecraft-1/</guid>
      <description>This four-class sequence introduces the students to fundamental computer science concepts, including events and coordinates. Students will use a coding environment embedded in Minecraft Education to code their own commands, which they will then use in the game.&#xA;Leveraging the engaging world of Minecraft Education, students will:&#xA;Explore a custom coding environment integrated within the game Learn to write and execute their own commands Apply coding principles to manipulate the Minecraft world in real-time Develop problem-solving skills through interactive challenges Gain hands-on experience with spatial reasoning and algorithmic thinking By the end of the course, students will have a solid foundation in basic programming concepts, enhanced creativity, and improved logical reasoning skills—all while enjoying the familiar and exciting Minecraft platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Foundations with REV DUO | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Mechanical-Foundations-with-REV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Mechanical-Foundations-with-REV/</guid>
      <description>The Mechanical Foundations with REV DUO course provides participants with the hands-on skills and knowledge needed to design, build, and maintain robotic systems confidently. Through interactive projects and challenges, students will explore the foundational mechanical principles that drive robotics, such as structure, motion, power transmission, and mechanical advantage. Using the REV DUO building system, participants will gain practical experience assembling and testing robotic components while learning to solve real-world engineering challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C# for Unity | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/C-Sharp-for-Unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/C-Sharp-for-Unity/</guid>
      <description>Unit 1: Introduction to C# Programming and Unity&#xA;Dive into the world of game development with this beginner-friendly unit, perfect for students with no prior programming experience. Learn the fundamentals of C# programming while exploring the basics of the Unity game engine, the industry-standard platform for creating interactive games. By the end of this unit, students will:&#xA;Understand the Unity interface and its core components. Learn foundational C# concepts such as variables, data types, and basic syntax.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculus AB/BC | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus-AB-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus-AB-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Calculus Homework!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost Small Group Sessions:&#xA;4 students per groupFocus on current homework assignmentsStep-by-step problem-solving guidanceExpert calculus tutor support90-minute sessionsCover all calculus topics in your curriculumAdditional practice problems for reinforcementTurn your homework headaches into &#39;Aha!&#39; moments!&#xA;Sign up for Blue Ridge Boost and ace your assignments!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculus AB/BC | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Calculus-AB-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Calculus-AB-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Calculus Homework!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost Small Group Sessions:&#xA;4 students per groupFocus on current homework assignmentsStep-by-step problem-solving guidanceExpert calculus tutor support90-minute sessionsCover all calculus topics in your curriculumAdditional practice problems for reinforcementTurn your homework headaches into &#39;Aha!&#39; moments!&#xA;Sign up for Blue Ridge Boost and ace your assignments!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-2/</guid>
      <description>Dive into an exciting new season of FIRST LEGO League with the 2024-2025 theme: SUBMERGED! This year’s challenge invites participants to explore the mysteries and wonders of underwater environments while solving real-world challenges related to oceans, lakes, and waterways.&#xA;Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-3-4/</guid>
      <description>In our advanced math class, we harness the engaging and comprehensive materials from Beast Academy to cultivate a deep understanding and passion for mathematics. Each student embarks on a personalized mathematical journey under the guidance of an expert Blue Ridge Boost instructor.&#xA;Class Structure Introduction: Each session begins with a concise lesson introducing new concepts and exercise types. Guided Practice: Students then apply these concepts through hands-on problem-solving, with instructor support readily available.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
