<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3rd on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/3rd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3rd on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/3rd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Banana Code Quest: Adventures in Text-Based Programming | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana_Code_Quest_Adventures_in_Text-Based_Programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana_Code_Quest_Adventures_in_Text-Based_Programming/</guid>
      <description>Banana Code Quest is a gamified coding course designed to teach young students real-world coding from the very first challenge. Through engaging puzzles and adventures, students help a monkey catch bananas and outsmart various animals, all while learning fundamental and advanced coding concepts in a fun and interactive way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered TechQuest: Fall Bots &amp; Spring Bricks | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_TechQuest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_TechQuest/</guid>
      <description>This inclusive STEM class is dedicated to empowering girls, while warmly welcoming and encouraging participation from all genders. Scholarships are available to ensure that financial limitations do not prevent students from joining.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Junior Robotics Adventures: Dino Quests &amp; Lego Explorers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Junior_Robotics_Adventures_Dino_Quests_Lego_Explorers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Junior_Robotics_Adventures_Dino_Quests_Lego_Explorers/</guid>
      <description>Embark on an exciting year-long journey where young learners explore basic robotics concepts through themed challenges, including Jurassic adventures with Sphero Indi in the fall and collaborative Lego robotics projects in the spring, fostering critical thinking, teamwork, and creativity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Junior Robotics Adventures: Dino Quests &amp; Lego Explorers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Junior_Robotics_Adventures_Dino_Quests_Lego_Explorers_Saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Junior_Robotics_Adventures_Dino_Quests_Lego_Explorers_Saturday/</guid>
      <description>Embark on an exciting year-long journey where young learners explore basic robotics concepts through themed challenges, including Jurassic adventures with Sphero Indi in the fall and collaborative Lego robotics projects in the spring, fostering critical thinking, teamwork, and creativity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Boost for Third, Fourth, and Fifth Graders | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Boost_for_Third_and_Fourth_Graders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Boost_for_Third_and_Fourth_Graders/</guid>
      <description>This class is tailored for students who have been recommended for additional support and are facing challenges in their regular classroom. It offers reinforcement of key concepts through extra practice with typical grade-level problems, ensuring that students can grasp and master the material at their own pace. Additionally, students will have the opportunity to work on materials recommended by their classroom teacher and tackle problems suggested by Blue Ridge Boost instructors, providing a tailored and comprehensive approach to meet their individual learning needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Excellence for Third and Fourth Grade| Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Excellence_for_Third_and_Fourth_Grade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Excellence_for_Third_and_Fourth_Grade/</guid>
      <description>In our advanced math class, we harness the engaging and comprehensive materials from Beast Academy to cultivate a deep understanding and passion for mathematics. Each student embarks on a personalized mathematical journey under the guidance of an expert Blue Ridge Boost instructor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Leapers: Advanced Kangaroo Challenges | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Leapers_Advanced_Kangaroo_Challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Leapers_Advanced_Kangaroo_Challenges/</guid>
      <description>The Math Kangaroo competition is an international mathematical competition where students from grades 1 through 12 participate. The curriculum for grades 3 and 4 focuses on enhancing mathematical skills through engaging and challenging problems, building on the foundational knowledge acquired in earlier grades. The Kangaroo Mathematics Competition, set for Thursday, March 20, 2025.  The class will continue for the duration of the school year to prepare students for the next year&amp;rsquo;s competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Mastery for Third and Fourth Graders | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-for_Third_and_Fourth_Graders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-for_Third_and_Fourth_Graders/</guid>
      <description>This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top 50% of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Discovery for 2nd and 3rd Grades | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_2nd_and_3rd_Grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_2nd_and_3rd_Grades/</guid>
      <description>This class offers a progressive, hands-on introduction to robotics for students in grades 2 and 3, covering Vex GO, Lego Spike Essential, and Sphero Bolt Robotics throughout the academic year, while developing problem-solving, critical thinking, and teamwork skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechQuest: Fall Bots &amp; Spring Bricks | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/TechQuest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/TechQuest/</guid>
      <description>This inclusive STEM class is dedicated to empowering all students, warmly welcoming and encouraging participation from all genders.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
