<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>12th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/12th/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 12th on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/12th/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced C&#43;&#43;: Mastering Data Structures | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_C&#43;&#43;_Mastering_Data_Structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_C&#43;&#43;_Mastering_Data_Structures/</guid>
      <description>This course includes C++ fundamentals, basic data structures, file and error handling, STL containers, recursion, pointers, linked lists, and graphs. Each module has examples and assignments. A final project integrates multiple data structures to solve a real-world problem. The course prepares students for complex programming challenges in academic and professional settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Python | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you ready to take your Python skills to the next level?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt; Join our in-depth course designed to guide you through some of the most powerful and essential concepts in Python programming. This course is perfect for developers who have a basic understanding of Python and are eager to explore advanced topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculus AB Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus_AB_Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus_AB_Mastery/</guid>
      <description>This class is perfect for students who want to strengthen their understanding of classroom concepts through additional practice with engaging grade-level problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculus AB Practice | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus_AB_Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus_AB_Practice/</guid>
      <description>This class is designed for students seeking reinforcement of classroom concepts through additional practice with grade-appropriate problems. &lt;br&gt; During a typical session, students will receive assistance with homework assignments and review concepts learned in school. As time allows, instructors will provide similar problems to further solidify understanding and boost confidence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java for AP Computer Science | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_APCS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_APCS/</guid>
      <description>Struggling with AP Computer Science coding exercises? Our expert instructors are ready to guide you. Learn to think like a computer scientist and accelerate your coding skills. From basic concepts to advanced algorithms, we&amp;rsquo;ll help you master AP Computer Science and prepare for your future in tech. Start your journey to coding excellence today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React Native Mobile App Development for High School Students | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/React_Native_Mobile_App_Development_for_High_School_Students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/React_Native_Mobile_App_Development_for_High_School_Students/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;React Native Mobile App Development for High School Students&amp;rdquo; course is designed to equip students with the skills to create dynamic and scalable mobile applications. Over the course of a year, students will delve into the React Native framework, learning to use components, stylesheets, state management, and more to build apps that run seamlessly on their smartphones. With a mix of web-based and hands-on activities, including collaborative exercises and digital presentations, students will gain practical experience in mobile app development. This course is ideal for those with prior knowledge in JavaScript and web design, providing an engaging and comprehensive introduction to the world of mobile app creation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics_Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics_Mastery/</guid>
      <description>This class is designed for students seeking reinforcement of classroom concepts through additional practice with grade-appropriate problems. &lt;br&gt; During a typical session, students will receive assistance with homework assignments and review concepts learned in school. As time allows, instructors will provide similar problems to further solidify understanding and boost confidence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Practice | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics_Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics_Practice/</guid>
      <description>This class is designed for students seeking reinforcement of classroom concepts through additional practice with grade-appropriate problems. &lt;br&gt; During a typical session, students will receive assistance with homework assignments and review concepts learned in school. As time allows, instructors will provide similar problems to further solidify understanding and boost confidence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Design in JavaScript | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video_Game_Design_in_JavaScript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video_Game_Design_in_JavaScript/</guid>
      <description>The video game design curriculum teaches the foundations of creating video games in JavaScript. While this course is introductory, it requires a good mathematical background and analytical thinking. Its curriculum teaches the foundations of computer science and basic programming, with an emphasis on helping students develop logical thinking and problem-solving skills. Once students complete the course, they will have learned material equivalent to a semester college introductory course in Computer Science and be able to program in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
