<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saturday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Saturday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Saturday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Saturday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Problem Solving | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Problem-Solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Problem-Solving/</guid>
      <description>MOEMS is a challenging and engaging math competition for middle schoolers, featuring five monthly contests from November to March that focus on problem-solving and mathematical creativity. Similarly, the AMC 8 is a 40-minute math competition designed for students in grade 8 and below, covering a range of middle school math topics, including some concepts from introductory algebra. At Blue Ridge Boost, students participate in weekly problem-solving sessions to prepare for these competitions, and they have the option to take the tests if they choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerial Drones | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</guid>
      <description>What is the Aerial Drone Competition? A cutting-edge program that prepares students for careers in drone technology Four exciting missions: Teamwork, Autonomous Flight, Piloting Skills, and Communications Compete in local, and regional events No prior experience needed! We&#39;re looking for students who are: Curious about drones and aviation Interested in coding and programming Excited to learn piloting skills Great at teamwork and communication Ready to take on new challenges Students are not required to participate in a Competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Algebra Together!&#xA;Join our group algebra homework help sessions:&#xA;Small group classes (4 students)Expert instructor guidanceCollaborative problem-solvingBoost your grades and confidence with peers!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Algebra-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Algebra Together!&#xA;Join our group algebra homework help sessions:&#xA;Small group classes (4 students)Expert instructor guidanceCollaborative problem-solvingBoost your grades and confidence with peers!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMC 8 Test | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/AMC8-2025-Test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/AMC8-2025-Test/</guid>
      <description>Are you excited about the AMC 8 but find that your school doesn&#39;t host the contest? No problem! You can sign up and take the test at Blue Ridge Boost. We offer a welcoming space for young math enthusiasts to test their skills and enjoy a rewarding competition experience.&#xA;The AMC 8 is a 25-question, 40-minute competition designed for students in grade 8 and below. The competition focuses on middle school mathematics topics, including counting and probability, estimation, proportional reasoning, elementary geometry (including the Pythagorean Theorem), spatial visualization, and interpreting graphs and tables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chess Tactics and Games | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/chess/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/chess/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to start a chess program for our more dedicated players, who are ready to learn more about the game and improve their skills.&#xA;The classes start at 10 am with a 45 minutes lesson, followed by three 15-minute games. The pickup time is 12:00.&#xA;The classes are held at Blue Ridge Boost and are taught by Daniel Wurtzer.&#xA;Hello my name is Daniel Wurzer and I am excited to teach chess lessons at Blue Ridge Boost this fall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chess Tactics and Games | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to start a chess program for our more dedicated players, who are ready to learn more about the game and improve their skills.&#xA;The classes start at 10 am with a 45 minutes lesson, followed by three 15-minute games. The pickup time is 12:00.&#xA;The classes are held at Blue Ridge Boost and are taught by Daniel Wurtzer.&#xA;Hello my name is Daniel Wurzer and I am excited to teach chess lessons at Blue Ridge Boost this fall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-on-Saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-on-Saturday/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the world of Lego robotics Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-First-Tech-Challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-First-Tech-Challenge/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;re forming a new FIRST Tech Challenge team and we want GIRLS!&#xA;This is an inclusive STEM class with a focus on empowering girls. While all genders are welcome and encouraged to participate, we strive to maintain a majority female enrollment to address historical underrepresentation in STEM fields. Our goal is to create a supportive environment that inspires girls to explore and excel in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.&#xA;What is FIRST Tech Challenge?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-1-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-1-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Master Integrated Math 1 with Blue Ridge Boost!&#xA;Join our Focused Group Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of no more than 4 students60-minute intensive weekly sessionsExpert guidance on all Integrated Math 1 topicsAlgebra, geometry, and statistics supportTargeted homework help and problem-solvingAligned with common core standardsPersonalized attention in a collaborative settingTurn math confusion into confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Integrated-Math-1-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Integrated-Math-1-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Master Integrated Math 1 with Blue Ridge Boost!&#xA;Join our Focused Group Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of no more than 4 students60-minute intensive weekly sessionsExpert guidance on all Integrated Math 1 topicsAlgebra, geometry, and statistics supportTargeted homework help and problem-solvingAligned with common core standardsPersonalized attention in a collaborative settingTurn math confusion into confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 2/Algebra 2 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-2-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-2-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Master Integrated Math 2 with Blue Ridge Boost!&#xA;Join our Focused Group Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of no more than four students60-minute intensive weekly sessionsExpert guidance on all Integrated Math 2 topicsAlgebra, geometry, precalculus, and statistics supportTargeted homework help and problem-solvingAligned with common core standardsPersonalized attention in a collaborative settingTurn math confusion into confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 2/Algebra 2 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Integrated-Math-2-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Integrated-Math-2-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Master Integrated Math 2 with Blue Ridge Boost!&#xA;Join our Focused Group Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of no more than four students60-minute intensive weekly sessionsExpert guidance on all Integrated Math 2 topicsAlgebra, geometry, precalculus, and statistics supportTargeted homework help and problem-solvingAligned with common core standardsPersonalized attention in a collaborative settingTurn math confusion into confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 3 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-3-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-3-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Master Integrated Math 3 with Blue Ridge Boost!&#xA;Join our Focused Group Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of no more than four students60-minute intensive weekly sessionsExpert guidance on all Integrated Math 3 topicsAlgebra, geometry, precalculus, and statistics supportTargeted homework help and problem-solvingAligned with common core standardsPersonalized attention in a collaborative settingTurn math confusion into confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 3 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Integrated-Math-3-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/Integrated-Math-3-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Master Integrated Math 3 with Blue Ridge Boost!&#xA;Join our Focused Group Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of no more than four students60-minute intensive weekly sessionsExpert guidance on all Integrated Math 3 topicsAlgebra, geometry, precalculus, and statistics supportTargeted homework help and problem-solvingAligned with common core standardsPersonalized attention in a collaborative settingTurn math confusion into confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Hoppers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Hoppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Hoppers/</guid>
      <description>The Kangaroo Mathematics Competition, set for Thursday, March 20, 2025, is an international event testing students&amp;rsquo; math skills. Preparation involves practicing past papers, reviewing key concepts, and improving time management. The multiple-choice test covers various math topics. The class will continue for the duration of the school year to prepare students for the next year&amp;rsquo;s competition.&#xA;What is Kangaroo Math? Kangaroo Math is a fun and exciting math competition where students from different countries solve interesting and challenging math problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Leapers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Leapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Leapers/</guid>
      <description>The Math Kangaroo competition is an international mathematical competition where students from grades 1 through 12 participate. The curriculum for grades 3 and 4 focuses on enhancing mathematical skills through engaging and challenging problems, building on the foundational knowledge acquired in earlier grades. The Kangaroo Mathematics Competition, set for Thursday, March 20, 2025. The class will continue for the duration of the school year to prepare students for the next year&amp;rsquo;s competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Olympiad Contest | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-E-Contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-E-Contest/</guid>
      <description>MATH OLYMPIAD 2024-2025&#xA;Unleash Your Mathematical Genius!&#xA;🏆 Calling All Young Math Stars (Grades 3-6)&#xA;Challenge your mind and discover the excitement of problem-solving at this year&#39;s Math Olympiad! Join hundreds of bright young mathematicians for an unforgettable experience.&#xA;Why Participate?&#xA;• Boost your critical thinking skills&#xA;• Meet other math enthusiasts&#xA;• Gain competition experience&#xA;The unique problem sets must be administered each month from November through March.&#xA;You can participate in any or all contests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Olympiad Contest | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-M-Contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-M-Contest/</guid>
      <description>MATH OLYMPIAD 2024-2025&#xA;Unleash Your Mathematical Genius!&#xA;🏆 Calling All Young Math Stars (Grades 6-8)&#xA;Challenge your mind and discover the excitement of problem-solving at this year&#39;s Math Olympiad! Join hundreds of bright young mathematicians for an unforgettable experience.&#xA;Why Participate?&#xA;• Boost your critical thinking skills&#xA;• Meet other math enthusiasts&#xA;• Gain competition experience&#xA;The unique problem sets must be administered each month from November through March.&#xA;You can participate in any or all contests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education Esports | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Esports-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Esports-Practice/</guid>
      <description>🎉Three Hours of Fun! 🎉 Dive into the world of Minecraft Education Esports with our exciting practice class! Perfect for having fun and honing your skills. What&#39;s Included: 🎮 Fun Training: Enjoy three hours of engaging gameplay. 🛠️ Creative Building: Unleash your imagination and learn new techniques. 🏆 Friendly Competitions: Play in scrimmages and enjoy some friendly rivalry. 👥 Community Connections: Meet fellow Minecraft fans and make new friends Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education for Elementary School | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Elementary-School/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Elementary-School/</guid>
      <description>🎮 Start Your Minecraft Adventure! 🎮&#xA;Join our beginner-friendly class and dive into the world of Minecraft!&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn:&#xA;🏗️ Building Basics: Master the essentials of crafting and construction. 🌿 Survival Skills: Learn how to gather resources and thrive in survival mode. 🗺️ Exploration Tips: Discover exciting biomes and hidden treasures. 👥 Multiplayer Fun: Connect with others and enjoy cooperative gameplay.&#xA;Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem-Solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem-Solving/</guid>
      <description>MOEMS is a challenging and engaging math competition for elementary and middle schoolers, featuring five monthly contests from November to March that focus on problem-solving and mathematical creativity. Similarly, the AMC 8 is a 40-minute math competition designed for students in grade 8 and below, covering a range of middle school math topics, including some concepts from introductory algebra. At Blue Ridge Boost, students participate in weekly problem-solving sessions to prepare for these competitions, and they have the option to take the tests if they choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roblox Studio | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-Roblox-Studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-Roblox-Studio/</guid>
      <description>This class is perfect for students who are new to creating games in Roblox. We will teach you how to create your first Roblox experience using Roblox Studio. You will use a Baseplate template and a high-quality catapult asset pack to build and organize a data model, customize 3D objects, and organize scripts for proper simulation. We will guide you through testing, publishing, and managing your experience for a global audience, using project templates and asset packs from the Creator Store to simplify the process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex IQ Rapid Relay | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Vex-IQ-Rapid-Relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Vex-IQ-Rapid-Relay/</guid>
      <description>Join us for this exciting class! No experience necessary, only a desire to learn and have fun!&#xA;Together, we will build a competition-level robot, hone driving skills, and coding with this year&amp;rsquo;s game.&#xA;The scoring objects in VEX IQ Robotics Competition Rapid Relay are padded Balls, approximately 6&amp;quot; in diameter.&#xA;The primary objectives of the game are to Pass the Balls between Robots, score Balls through Targets, and Clear Switches. Balls are introduced to the field through the Loading Station or, during the last 15 seconds of a Match, a Rapid Load Zone.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
