<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saturday on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Saturday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Saturday on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Saturday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced C&#43;&#43;: Mastering Data Structures | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_C&#43;&#43;_Mastering_Data_Structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_C&#43;&#43;_Mastering_Data_Structures/</guid>
      <description>This course includes C++ fundamentals, basic data structures, file and error handling, STL containers, recursion, pointers, linked lists, and graphs. Each module has examples and assignments. A final project integrates multiple data structures to solve a real-world problem. The course prepares students for complex programming challenges in academic and professional settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Problem Solving: Math Olympiad, and AMC8 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</guid>
      <description>MOEMS is a challenging and engaging math competition for middle schoolers, featuring five monthly contests from November to March that focus on problem-solving and mathematical creativity. Similarly, the AMC 8 is a 40-minute math competition designed for students in grade 8 and below, covering a range of middle school math topics, including some concepts from introductory algebra. At Blue Ridge Boost, students participate in weekly problem-solving sessions to prepare for these competitions, and they have the option to take the tests if they choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_FTC/</guid>
      <description>This is an inclusive STEM class with a focus on empowering girls. While all genders are welcome and encouraged to participate, we strive to maintain a majority female enrollment to address historical underrepresentation in STEM fields. Our goal is to create a supportive environment that inspires girls to explore and excel in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Vex IQ Team! | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Vex_IQ_Team/</guid>
      <description>Calling all creative, curious, and tech-savvy girls and their supporters! We&#39;re forming a new majority-girl VEX IQ robotics team and we want YOU to be part of it!&#xA;What is VEX IQ?&#xD;An exciting robotics competition for elementary and middle school students&#xD;Design, build, and program your own robot&#xD;Compete in fun challenges&#xD;No experience needed! We&#39;re looking for:&#xD;Future engineers and inventors&#xD;Coders and problem-solvers&#xD;Team players and leaders&#xD;Girls who love to learn and have fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java for FTC: Robot Programming Essentials | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_FTC_Robot_Programming_Essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Java_for_FTC_Robot_Programming_Essentials/</guid>
      <description>The FIRST Tech Challenge (FTC) OnBot Java Course is designed to introduce students to the fundamentals of programming in Java within the context of robot development and competition. This course covers essential programming concepts such as variables, control structures, and object-oriented programming, as well as specific skills needed to program FTC robots using the OnBot Java environment. Students will learn how to write, test, and debug code for various robot functions like movement, sensor integration, and autonomous navigation. The course emphasizes hands-on learning, problem-solving, and teamwork, preparing participants for success in FTC competitions and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Junior Robotics Adventures: Dino Quests &amp; Lego Explorers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Junior_Robotics_Adventures_Dino_Quests_Lego_Explorers_Saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Junior_Robotics_Adventures_Dino_Quests_Lego_Explorers_Saturday/</guid>
      <description>Embark on an exciting year-long journey where young learners explore basic robotics concepts through themed challenges, including Jurassic adventures with Sphero Indi in the fall and collaborative Lego robotics projects in the spring, fostering critical thinking, teamwork, and creativity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Hoppers: Kangaroo Math for Young Explorers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kangaroo_Competition_Math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kangaroo_Competition_Math/</guid>
      <description>The Kangaroo Mathematics Competition, set for Thursday, March 20, 2025, is an international event testing students&amp;rsquo; math skills. Preparation involves practicing past papers, reviewing key concepts, and improving time management. The multiple-choice test covers various math topics. The class will continue for the duration of the school year to prepare students for the next year&amp;rsquo;s competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving: Math Olympiad, and AMC8 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem_Solving_Math_Olympiad_and_AMC8/</guid>
      <description>MOEMS is a challenging and engaging math competition for elementary and middle schoolers, featuring five monthly contests from November to March that focus on problem-solving and mathematical creativity. Similarly, the AMC 8 is a 40-minute math competition designed for students in grade 8 and below, covering a range of middle school math topics, including some concepts from introductory algebra. At Blue Ridge Boost, students participate in weekly problem-solving sessions to prepare for these competitions, and they have the option to take the tests if they choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sphero Time Travelers| Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Sphero_Challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Sphero_Challenge/</guid>
      <description>Embark on an exciting journey through time with the Sphero Global Challenge! This engaging program is designed for students aged 9-11 to develop crucial skills while having fun with technology.&#xA;Using BOLT robots and the Sphero Global Challenge Blueprint Kit, you&amp;rsquo;ll dive into a world of coding, problem-solving, and teamwork. As you tackle various missions set in different historical periods, you&amp;rsquo;ll:&#xA;Master programming concepts and techniques Enhance your critical thinking and problem-solving abilities Improve communication and collaboration skills Learn about different historical eras in an interactive way Boost your creativity by finding innovative solutions to challenges Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or have some coding experience, the missions are designed to help you grow and learn at your own pace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex IQ Rapid Relay | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Vex_IQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_Vex_IQ/</guid>
      <description>Join us for this exciting class! No experience necessary, only a desire to learn and have fun!&#xA;Together, we will build a competition-level robot, hone driving skills, and coding with this year&amp;rsquo;s game.&#xA;The scoring objects in VEX IQ Robotics Competition Rapid Relay are padded Balls, approximately 6&amp;quot; in diameter.&#xA;The primary objectives of the game are to Pass the Balls between Robots, score Balls through Targets, and Clear Switches. Balls are introduced to the field through the Loading Station or, during the last 15 seconds of a Match, a Rapid Load Zone.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
