<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Classes on Coding and Math Classes and Tutoring in Charlottesville</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/</link><description>Recent content in Classes on Coding and Math Classes and Tutoring in Charlottesville</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/class/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Block Language Classes for Six to Ten-Year-Olds | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/kids-block-coding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/kids-block-coding/</guid><description>Students ages six to ten learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a beaver build a dam on instructor-provided Chromebooks. First, students learn to code using simple commands to move left, right and drop logs. Next, students learn to code repetition using repeat loops executed a fixed or a variable number of times. In the second part of the course, students learn to code using conditional loops. In the third part of the course, students learn to code using conditional statements with simple and compound conditions.</description></item><item><title>Coding Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/ongoing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/ongoing/</guid><description>If you are unsure that our classes are a good fit for your student please sign up for a meet-and-greet session or email nora@blueridgeboost.com. Coding classes are NOT eligible for VDOE K-12 Acceleration Grants. Please get in touch with us for scholarships based on financial need.
All coding classes are held at the Blue Ridge Boost office at 222 Court Square, Charlottesville. PK-K Block Coding With Code Monkey Jr</description></item><item><title>Coding Group Classes for 4 to 6 year olds | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/preschool-block-coding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/preschool-block-coding/</guid><description>Our youngest students learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a [monkey collect bananas](https://www.codemonkey.com/courses/codemonkey-jr) on instructor-provided Chromebooks. Students learn the basics of coding using left, right, jump up, jump left, and jump right commands to guide a monkey to collect all bananas before opening a treasure chest. In addition, students learn to code repetition by using loops and conditional loops. The course concludes with procedures. The classes are organized into four-lesson units.</description></item><item><title>Get ready for FLL Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-challenge/</guid><description>The FIRST LEGO League Challenge curriculum immerses students in research, problem-solving, coding, and engineering, providing diverse, challenging, and relevant learning experiences. Students are tasked with developing innovative solutions to real-world problems and designing, building, and coding a LEGO robot that can tackle themed challenge missions.
> The 2023-2024 art-themed MASTERPIECE materials will help students imagine and innovate new ways to create and communicate art globally. At Blue Ridge Boost, students work in pairs using one SPIKE Prime set to ensure each student has the time and the tools to share their ideas and experiment.</description></item><item><title>Join our First Lego League Discover Class | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-discover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-discover/</guid><description>The FIRST LEGO League Discover is a fun and engaging STEM program designed for teams of children aged 4-6, which nurtures their innate curiosity and fosters lifelong learning habits. By the end of the program, children emerge with greater confidence, better equipped to tackle upcoming challenges, and with a newfound passion for learning. Every year, a fresh and thrilling Challenge is unveiled, and each team of eight kids commences their exploration of the real-world theme with an exclusive LEGO Education Discover Set.</description></item><item><title>Join our First Lego League Explore Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-explore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-explore/</guid><description>The FIRST LEGO League Explore is an educational program where teams of six students aged 6-10 concentrate on the basics of engineering. They delve into real-world problems, learn to design, code, and develop novel solutions using LEGO bricks powered by LEGO Education SPIKE Essential. The 2023-2024 art-themed MASTERPIECE materials will help students imagine and innovate new ways to create and communicate art across the globe. At Blue Ridge Boost students works in pairs using one SPIKE Essential set to ensure each student has the time and the tools to share their ideas and to experiment.</description></item><item><title>Kids Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/tweens-coffee-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/tweens-coffee-script/</guid><description>Students learn fundamental coding concepts using Coffee Script, a beginner-friendly text-based coding language. The young coders use an attractive graphical interface to generate text by pressing buttons on instructor-provided Chromebooks. Some previous experience typing is helpful but not necessary. Classes run in semester-long sessions. Each class is 50 minutes long. We adjust classes to the pace of each student.
Sign up for a free trial class! Unit 1 Students learn that coding is giving precise instructions to a computer, using advanced planning to create efficient programs.</description></item><item><title>Learn through play using Lego&amp;reg; STEAM Park | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/steam-park/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/steam-park/</guid><description>Come and learn to math and science with Lego STEAM Park! Small class sizes with a maximum of four students sharing one set allow the learners to engage with all the components.
The STEAM Park unit enables students to delve into the world around them by constructing interactive models using functional components. The lessons encourage students to adopt a scientific mindset as they build and test models, experiment, and seek answers to questions.</description></item><item><title>Lego&amp;reg; Robotics for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/lego-wedo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/lego-wedo/</guid><description>Come and learn to build and program Lego&amp;reg; robots! In each lesson, students build a Lego&amp;reg; robot using a design model, improve and extend it, and then create a program using Scratch to control and move the robot. The robots use a medium power motor to act, depth, and tilt sensor to sense. A Scratch program encodes the robot's actions in response to sensing. Sign up for a free trial class!</description></item><item><title>Lego&amp;reg; Spike Robotics for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/lego-spike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/lego-spike/</guid><description>Come and learn to build and program Lego® robots!
Students learn to build robot attachments and code the Lego Spike® robot using Scratch.
Sign up for a free trial class!</description></item><item><title>Middle School Python Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/middle-school-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/middle-school-python/</guid><description>Are you a middle schooler interested in Python? Come and learn with us!
Students learn Python using a combination of lessons that use the Code Monkey platform and Jupyter Notebooks created by the instructor.
Classes run in semester-long sessions. Each class is 50 minutes long. We adjust classes to the pace of each student.
Sign up for a free trial class!
Unit 1. Sequencing, Objects and For Loops Students learn that coding means giving precise instructions to a computer, the concept of objects, and that objects can perform several actions.</description></item><item><title>Python Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/python/</guid><description> We are teaching Python using the Art of Problem Solving version of the textbook How to Think Like a Computer Scientist, Learning with Python 3 (AoPS Edition). Who should take this class? Students that: pass the pretest have had some previous exposure to text-based programming languages, are mature enough to read a textbook, and are willing to commit at least an hour of outside class work time.</description></item><item><title>Scratch Coding for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/scratch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/scratch/</guid><description>Learn Scratch with us! We teach Scratch using a project-based approach. You will learn to create games, including Make it Fly!, Dungeons, Pong, Dodge the Balls, Jumping game, Math facts practice, a clone of Crossy Road, and much more.
Sign up for a free trial class!</description></item></channel></rss>