<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sunday on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Sunday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sunday on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Sunday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Python | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Wizardry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you ready to take your Python skills to the next level?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt; Join our in-depth course designed to guide you through some of the most powerful and essential concepts in Python programming. This course is perfect for developers who have a basic understanding of Python and are eager to explore advanced topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_Excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra_1_Excellence/</guid>
      <description>This class is ideal for students looking to go beyond the typical school curriculum. Based on the renowned textbook by Art of Problem Solving founder Richard Rusczyk, the course emphasizes learning through problem-solving with instructors available to provide clarifying explanations. Instead of traditional lecturing, most of the class time is dedicated to tackling challenging problems. Students will be encouraged to write complete and clear solutions to exercises, an important skill in communicating mathematics effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculus AB Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus_AB_Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus_AB_Mastery/</guid>
      <description>This class is perfect for students who want to strengthen their understanding of classroom concepts through additional practice with engaging grade-level problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Drone Squad | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl_Powered_Drone_Squad/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Female Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Girl-Powered Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming an all-girl team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Fundamentals: Coding from the Ground Up | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</guid>
      <description>This course is a comprehensive, year-long program designed for middle school students with no prior coding experience. It introduces fundamental programming concepts using Python through interactive exercises and projects centered around controlling a virtual character named Tracy. The course covers commands, functions, loops, variables, conditionals, and lists, progressing to more complex tasks like user interaction and creating visual projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Discovery for 2nd and 3rd Grades | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_2nd_and_3rd_Grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_2nd_and_3rd_Grades/</guid>
      <description>This class offers a progressive, hands-on introduction to robotics for students in grades 2 and 3, covering Vex GO, Lego Spike Essential, and Sphero Bolt Robotics throughout the academic year, while developing problem-solving, critical thinking, and teamwork skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rookie Aerial Drone Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Rookie_Aerial_Drone_Team/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Drone Pilots and Engineers! Join our Aerial Drone Competition Team! We&amp;rsquo;re forming a team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics_Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics_Mastery/</guid>
      <description>This class is designed for students seeking reinforcement of classroom concepts through additional practice with grade-appropriate problems. &lt;br&gt; During a typical session, students will receive assistance with homework assignments and review concepts learned in school. As time allows, instructors will provide similar problems to further solidify understanding and boost confidence.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
