<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sunday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Sunday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sunday on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/day_tags/Sunday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Calculus AB/BC | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus-AB-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus-AB-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Calculus with Intensive Practice!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost Small Group Tutoring:&#xA;4 students per groupDeep dive into calculus conceptsExpert calculus tutor guidance90-minutes sessionsTransform your calculus struggles into strengths!&#xA;Enroll now and differentiate yourself from the rest!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Fundamentals | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>This course is a comprehensive, year-long program designed for middle school students with no prior coding experience. It introduces fundamental programming concepts using Python through interactive exercises and projects centered around controlling a virtual character named Tracy. The course covers commands, functions, loops, variables, conditionals, and lists, progressing to more complex tasks like user interaction and creating visual projects.&#xA;Topics include:&#xA;Commands Understanding basic commands is crucial as it forms the foundation of programming, allowing Tracy to perform specific actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Kids | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Machine-Learning-for-Kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Machine-Learning-for-Kids/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the fascinating world of artificial intelligence with this hands-on class designed for young learners! Using the Machine Learning for Kids platform, students will explore how machines can &#34;learn&#34; from data and apply this knowledge to solve real-world problems in creative ways.&#xA;This class introduces the basics of machine learning through fun, interactive projects, where students will:&#xA;Learn how to train machine learning models using simple datasets. Explore key concepts like classification, recognition, and prediction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Basics | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Deep-Learning-Basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Deep-Learning-Basics/</guid>
      <description>Discover the exciting world of deep learning and neural networks in this hands-on course, designed to build a strong foundation in artificial intelligence. Through interactive lessons and real-world projects, you&#39;ll gain the skills to design, build, and train deep learning models using Keras, a user-friendly and powerful library for AI development.&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn: Core Concepts: Understand the fundamentals of neural networks, deep learning models, and how they work. Supervised and Unsupervised Models: Explore supervised models like convolutional neural networks (CNNs) and recurrent neural networks (RNNs), as well as unsupervised models like autoencoders.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
