<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coding and Math Classes and Tutoring in Charlottesville</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/</link><description>Recent content on Coding and Math Classes and Tutoring in Charlottesville</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Lego League</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/08/12/fll-23/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/08/12/fll-23/</guid><description>Join Our Lego Teams!</description></item><item><title>Last Week of Summer Camps</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/08/11/end-summer-camps-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/08/11/end-summer-camps-23/</guid><description>The fun does not have to stop.</description></item><item><title>Free trial classes</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/08/05/trial-classes-booking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/08/05/trial-classes-booking/</guid><description>Book a trial class today!</description></item><item><title>Math Review</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/06/05/math-review-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/06/05/math-review-23/</guid><description>Get your child ready for the new school year with math review sessions!</description></item><item><title>Summer Camps</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/05/21/summer-camps-23/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/05/21/summer-camps-23/</guid><description>Coding and math camp in the last week of July and the first two weeks of August.</description></item><item><title>Summer Break</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/05/14/summer-break-23/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2023/05/14/summer-break-23/</guid><description>Blue Ridge Boost will be closed from June 5th to July 23rd.</description></item><item><title>Free trial classes</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/17/trial-classes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/17/trial-classes/</guid><description>Open house every Sunday at 1 pm!</description></item><item><title>The new office is ready for students!</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/05/new-office-ready/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/09/05/new-office-ready/</guid><description/></item><item><title>New Downtown Location</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/29/brb-new-location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/29/brb-new-location/</guid><description>Starting in September, Blue Ridge Boost is located at 222 Court Square, Charlottesville.
To reach us, please walk around to the back of the building. Walk up the stairs to the second floor and enter through the door on your left.
The closest paid parking is the Market Street Garage. Free 2-hour parking is available throughout the Downtown area.</description></item><item><title>Fall Classes</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/15/fall-coding-classes-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/2022/08/15/fall-coding-classes-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Algebra 2 Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/algebra2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/algebra2/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in algebra and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum. Our services include an Algebra 1 review before school starts, ongoing support with classroom content, and new topics and lessons.
Get Ready for Algebra 2! Join our summer classes in August, to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review Algebra 1, including linear functions, linear equations and systems of equations, exponent laws, quadratic functions, and polynomials.</description></item><item><title>Algebra Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/algebra1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/algebra1/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in algebra and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum. Our services include a prealgebra review before school starts, ongoing support with classroom content, and new topics and lessons.
Get Ready for Algebra 1! At Blue Ridge Boost, we strongly believe that math is not a spectator sport. Children learn math and become independent, confident mathematicians by solving a variety of problems.</description></item><item><title>AMC and MathCounts Coaching in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/math/amc-coach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/math/amc-coach/</guid><description>An experienced instructor with MathCounts and AMC8 coaching experience teaches mini-lessons on topics commonly found in competition math problems and leads students in solving practice problems.
The content of the class depends on the target competition and the student&amp;rsquo;s background. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch with us for further information.</description></item><item><title>AP&amp;reg; Calculus AB/BC Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/ap-calculus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/ap-calculus/</guid><description>Get Ready for AP Calculus AB/BC! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review linear, quadratic, polynomial, exponential, and trigonometric functions.
AP Calculus AB/BC Private Tutor Contact us to set up lessons and problem-solving sessions for AP Calculus AB/BC!</description></item><item><title>AP&amp;reg; Computer Science Principles | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/ap-computer-science-principles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/ap-computer-science-principles/</guid><description>Contact us to set up private lessons with an experienced software engineer and tutor.
Click here to book a tutoring session.</description></item><item><title>AP&amp;reg; Computer Science Tutor in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/ap-computer-science-java/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/ap-computer-science-java/</guid><description>Contact us to set up private lessons with an experienced Java engineer and tutor.
Click here to book a tutoring session.</description></item><item><title>AP&amp;reg; Statistics Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/ap-statistics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/ap-statistics/</guid><description>Get Ready for AP Statistics! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review probabilities, statistics, and linear, quadratic, and exponential functions.
AP Statistics Private Tutoring Contact us to set up lessons and problem-solving sessions for AP Statistics!</description></item><item><title>Authors | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/authors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/authors/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Block Language Classes for Six to Ten-Year-Olds | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/kids-block-coding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/kids-block-coding/</guid><description>Sign Up
Students ages six to ten learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a beaver build a dam on instructor-provided Chromebooks. First, students learn to code using simple commands to move left, right and drop logs. Next, students learn to code repetition using repeat loops executed a fixed or a variable number of times. In the second part of the course, students learn to code using conditional loops. In the third part of the course, students learn to code using conditional statements with simple and compound conditions.</description></item><item><title>Charlottesville Kids' Chess Club | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/chess/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/chess/</guid><description>Sign-up here for one of our chess club meetings!
Joins us for two hours of fun, every Thursday, from 4:30 to 6:30. All levels from novice to expert are welcome. The club is free, but sign up is required as we have limited space. Please cancel your sign-up if your plans change and you can not make it. Parking is available at the Market St Parking Garage (first hour is free).</description></item><item><title>Class Request Form | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/form/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/form/</guid><description>
Please submit this form or email nora@blueridgeboost.com for more information or to join a class.
Your email:
Your name:
Which type of class are you interested in?
Select and age range
Kindergarten - Second Grade
Second - Fifth Grade
Middle School
Any other information that would be helpful (including scheduling preferences):
Send</description></item><item><title>Coding Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/camps/</guid><description>Unleash Your Creativity with Lego Robotics: Winter 2023 Camp Adventure!
Are you ready to embark on an extraordinary journey of creativity, innovation, and teamwork? Look no further! Join us for an exhilarating exploration of Lego robots using the cutting-edge Spike Prime or Spike Essential. This winter camp is designed for Lego enthusiasts aged six to twelve, where imagination knows no bounds! At our Lego Robotics Winter Camp, students have the freedom to choose from existing Lego projects or unleash their creativity by building their own unique models.</description></item><item><title>Coding Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/spring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/spring/</guid><description>
Spring 24 math and coding classes will be posted in January.
Spring classes run from March to May.</description></item><item><title>Coding Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/winter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/winter/</guid><description>Winter Coding Classes. January 6 to February 25.
Signup for a two-week trial or the entire class. Commitment for the entire duration of the program is required to continue after the first two classes.
Block Coding Jr
Saturdays, 10:00 am &amp;ndash; 10:50 am. Grades PK and K. Teacher: Ransford Dunu.
Sign Up
Robotics introduction with LEGO WeDo 2.0
Saturdays, 11:00 am &amp;ndash; 12:20 pm. (90-minute class)
Grades K and 1.</description></item><item><title>Coding Group Classes for 4 to 6 year olds | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/preschool-block-coding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/preschool-block-coding/</guid><description>Our youngest students learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a [monkey collect bananas](https://www.codemonkey.com/courses/codemonkey-jr) on instructor-provided Chromebooks. Students learn the basics of coding using left, right, jump up, jump left, and jump right commands to guide a monkey to collect all bananas before opening a treasure chest. In addition, students learn to code repetition by using loops and conditional loops. The course concludes with procedures.
The classes are organized into four-lesson units.</description></item><item><title>Competition Math for Elementary and Middle School | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/math/math-olympiad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/math/math-olympiad/</guid><description>An experienced instructor teaches mini-lessons on topics commonly found in Math Olympiad contests and leads students in solving carefuly selected practice problems.
Math Olympiad Program Goals To stimulate enthusiasm and a love for mathematics To introduce mathematical concepts To teach strategies for problem solving To develop mathematical flexibility To strengthen mathematical intuition To foster mathematical creativity and ingenuity To provide the satisfaction, joy and thrill of solving challenges To develop an appreciation of mathematics Download a sample contest from Elementary Division (grades 4-6) and Middle School Division (grades 6-8) here.</description></item><item><title>Computer Science Tutor | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/book-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/book-now/</guid><description>Book here!</description></item><item><title>Contact | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</guid><description>
Don't hesitate to get in touch with us for any learning needs in math
and computing. We offer online and in-person one-on-one
instruction and in-person group classes for
students from middle school to graduate student level in Mathematics
and Computer Science.
Name
Your Email
Your Message
&amp;nbsp; Send Message</description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</guid><description>Coming soon &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Geometry Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/geometry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/geometry/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in geometry and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum. Our services include algebra and middle school geometry review before school starts, ongoing support with classroom content, and new topics and lessons.
Get Ready for Geometry At Blue Ridge Boost, we strongly believe that math is not a spectator sport. Children learn math and become independent, confident mathematicians by solving a variety of problems.</description></item><item><title>Get ready for FLL Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-challenge/</guid><description>The FIRST LEGO League Challenge curriculum immerses students in research, problem-solving, coding, and engineering, providing diverse, challenging, and relevant learning experiences. Students are tasked with developing innovative solutions to real-world problems and designing, building, and coding a LEGO robot that can tackle themed challenge missions.
>
The 2023-2024 art-themed MASTERPIECE materials will help students imagine and innovate new ways to create and communicate art globally.
At Blue Ridge Boost, students work in pairs using one SPIKE Prime set to ensure each student has the time and the tools to share their ideas and experiment.</description></item><item><title>Join our First Lego League Discover Class | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-discover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-discover/</guid><description>The FIRST LEGO League Discover is a fun and engaging STEM program designed for teams of children aged 4-6, which nurtures their innate curiosity and fosters lifelong learning habits. By the end of the program, children emerge with greater confidence, better equipped to tackle upcoming challenges, and with a newfound passion for learning. Every year, a fresh and thrilling Challenge is unveiled, and each team of eight kids commences their exploration of the real-world theme with an exclusive LEGO Education Discover Set.</description></item><item><title>Join our First Lego League Explore Team | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-explore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/fll-explore/</guid><description>The FIRST LEGO League Explore is an educational program where teams of six students aged 6-10 concentrate on the basics of engineering. They delve into real-world problems, learn to design, code, and develop novel solutions using LEGO bricks powered by LEGO Education SPIKE Essential.
The 2023-2024 art-themed MASTERPIECE materials will help students imagine and innovate new ways to create and communicate art across the globe. At Blue Ridge Boost students works in pairs using one SPIKE Essential set to ensure each student has the time and the tools to share their ideas and to experiment.</description></item><item><title>Learn through play using Lego&amp;reg; STEAM Park | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/steam-park/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/steam-park/</guid><description>Come and learn to math and science with Lego STEAM Park! Small class sizes with a maximum of four students sharing one set allow the learners to engage with all the components.
The STEAM Park unit enables students to delve into the world around them by constructing interactive models using functional components. The lessons encourage students to adopt a scientific mindset as they build and test models, experiment, and seek answers to questions.</description></item><item><title>Lego&amp;reg; Robotics for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/lego-wedo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/lego-wedo/</guid><description>Come and learn to build and program Lego&amp;reg; robot!
Sign Up
In each lesson, students build a Lego&amp;reg; robot using a design model,
improve and extend it, and then create a program using Scratch to
control and move the robot. The robots use a medium power motor to act, depth, and tilt sensor to sense. A Scratch program encodes the robot's actions in response to sensing. Each class students build and code a model of a Lego robot.</description></item><item><title>Lego&amp;reg; Spike Robotics for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/lego-spike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/lego-spike/</guid><description>Come and learn to build and program Lego® robots!
Students learn to build robot attachments and code the Lego Spike® robot using Scratch.</description></item><item><title>Math and Coding Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/fall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/fall/</guid><description>Signup for a two-week trial or the entire class. Commitment for the entire duration of the program is required to continue after the first two classes.
Math Olympiad for Elementary School (grades 4, 5, and 6)
Saturdays 12:30 to 1:20. October 28 to March 31. 20 lessons for $495. Advanced third graders are also welcome.
Sign Up
Math Olympiad for Middle School (grades 6,7, and 8)
Saturdays 1:30 to 2:20.</description></item><item><title>Math and Computer Science Tutor | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutoring/</guid><description>Math
Email nora@blueridgeboost.com to set up a free evaluation an we will match you with one of our wonderful instructors.
Coding and Computer Science
Book a private tutoring session or email nora@blueridgeboost.com. Well qualified tutors are eager to help.
Elementary Math
Math Olympiad Coaching
Middle School Math
Algebra 1 Geometry
AMC 8/10/12 Coaching
Algebra 2
Pre-calculus
AP&amp;reg; Calculus AB/BC
AP&amp;reg; Statistics
College Calculus
Abstract Algebra
Real Analysis
General Topology
AP&amp;reg; Computer Science Principles (Python)
AP&amp;reg;Computer Science (Java)
USA Computing Olympiad Bronze
CS 1110 Introduction to Programming
CS 2100 Data Structures and Algorithms 1
CS 2120 Discrete Mathematics and Theory 1
CS 3120 Discrete Mathematics and Theory 2
CS 3100 Data Structures and Algorithms 2
CS 3140 Software Development Essentials
CS 3240 Advanced Software Development Techniques
CS 3250 Software Testing
CS 3710 Introduction to Cybersecurity
CS 4620 Compilers
CS 4630 Defense Against the Dark Arts
CS 4750 Database Systems
Tutoring sessions may be virtual or in person at the Blue Ridge Boost office at 222 Court Square, Charlottesville.</description></item><item><title>Math Tutoring for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/elementary-math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/elementary-math/</guid><description>At Blue Ridge Boost, we teach problem-solving skills using a variety of math manipulatives, Montessori materials, and math games. In addition, we use a variety of curricula based on the Virginia Standards of Learning, Common Core, Singapore Math®, and Beast Academy®.
Experienced instructors are ready to help your child develop a good understanding of the content, whether to keep up with classwork or expand knowledge beyond the school curriculum.</description></item><item><title>Math Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/book-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/book-now/</guid><description>Book here!</description></item><item><title>Middle School Math Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/middle-school-math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/middle-school-math/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in math and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum.
We help your child succeed in math and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum.
At Blue Ridge Boost, a qualified and experienced teacher assesses your student&amp;rsquo;s knowledge and builds an individualized instruction plan that targets weak areas while assisting with topics the student is learning.</description></item><item><title>Middle School Python Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/middle-school-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/middle-school-python/</guid><description>Are you a middle schooler interested in Python? Come and learn with us!
Students learn Python using a combination of lessons that use the Code Monkey platform and Jupyter Notebooks created by the instructor.
Classes run in semester-long sessions. Each class is 50 minutes long. We adjust classes to the pace of each student.
Unit 1. Sequencing, Objects and For Loops Students learn that coding means giving precise instructions to a computer, the concept of objects, and that objects can perform several actions.</description></item><item><title>Precalc Tutoring in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/precalculus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/math/precalculus/</guid><description>We help your child succeed in precalculus and teach advanced concepts to students that are ready for a challenging curriculum. Our services include an Algebra 2 review before school starts, ongoing support with classroom content, and new topics and lessons.
Get Ready for Math Analysis/Precalc! Join our summer classes in August to participate in a carefully developed curriculum to review Algebra 2 and Trigonometry, including quadratic, exponential, polynomial, and trigonometric functions.</description></item><item><title>Python Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/python/</guid><description>
We are teaching Python using the Art of Problem Solving version of the textbook How to Think Like a Computer Scientist, Learning with Python 3 (AoPS Edition).
Who should take this class? Students that:
pass the pretest
have had some previous exposure to text-based programming languages, are mature enough to read a textbook, and
are willing to commit at least an hour of outside class work time.</description></item><item><title>Scratch Coding for Children in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/scratch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/scratch/</guid><description>Learn Scratch with us!
Sign Up
We teach Scratch using a project-based approach. You will learn to create games, including Make it Fly!, Dungeons, Pong, Dodge the Balls, Jumping game, Math facts practice, a clone of Crossy Road, and much more.</description></item><item><title>Text Coding Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/tweens-coffee-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/class/coding/tweens-coffee-script/</guid><description>Students learn fundamental coding concepts using Coffee Script, a beginner-friendly text-based coding language. The young coders use an attractive graphical interface to generate text by pressing buttons on instructor-provided Chromebooks. Some previous experience typing is helpful but not necessary. Classes run in semester-long sessions. Each class is 50 minutes long. We adjust classes to the pace of each student.
Sign Up for Part 1 &amp;nbsp; Sign Up for Part 2 Unit 1
Students learn that coding is giving precise instructions to a computer, using advanced planning to create efficient programs.</description></item><item><title>USA Computing Olympiad Coaching | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/usaco-computing-olympiad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/tutor/computer-science/usaco-computing-olympiad/</guid><description>Contact us to get coaching for USA Computing Olympiad!
Click here to book a tutoring session.</description></item><item><title>Vision and History | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/vision/</guid><description>During the COVID-19 pandemic, I spent a significant amount of time teaching and helping my children learn and discovered that I greatly enjoy teaching young students. As a result, I quit my Ph.D. program in Computer Science to pursue a degree in teaching at the University of Virginia and launched Blue Ridge Boost. During the lockdown, Maxwell and Dorina tried a variety of challenging and exciting classes from the Center for Talented Youth at John Hopkins and The Art Of Problem Solving.</description></item><item><title>We are hiring! | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/jobs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/jobs/</guid><description>We are looking for the following roles:
Lead teacher for preschool and kindergarten coding classes.
The ideal candidate:
has experience working with young children.
has availability after school, or on weekends.
is qualified to teach following a lesson plan one or more of our PK-K classes, including Block Coding, Coding Express, STEAM Park, lego story hour, and FLL Discover. time commitment two to six hours per week.
Pay range: $20 to $30 per hour.</description></item><item><title>Your Instructors | Blue Ridge Boost</title><link>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</guid><description>Coding Instructors Nora Evans
I am originally from Bucharest, Romania and earned a B.Sc. in Computer Science at the Polytechnical University of Bucharest. I moved to Charlottesville in the Fall of 2004 to pursue graduate school at the University of Virginia, where I earned a Master's in Computer Science, a Master of Science in Mathematics, and a Master of Teaching. Some of my accomplishments include:
co-author of several research articles several years of industry experience as a Java software developer over two years of online tutoring on Wyzant in C, C++, Java, Python, List, and Prolog.</description></item></channel></rss>