<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Science and AP Calculus Tutor Charlottesville</title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Computer Science and AP Calculus Tutor Charlottesville</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&gt;Coding For Kids in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/kids/</guid>
      <description>Computing At Blue Ridge Boost, we teach computing using play, starting with robots to visualize the programming concepts. The programming exercises use an attractive graphical interface to reinforce concepts through practice.
We believe that students have to be exposed to the same programming concepts in a variety of situations and language variations. For this reason, students learn a few block languages to program WeDo Lego robots, mBot robots, help a beaver build its house in the Code Monkey framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Afternoon Camp for 9-12 year olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/afternoonwintercamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/afternoonwintercamp/</guid>
      <description>Camp at a glance When: Monday, December 27 – Friday, December 31, 2021, 2:00 am – 4:00 pm
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia (Pantops area)
Who: 9 – 12 years olds, no prior computer programming experience required
What: Coding instruction using Coffee Script or Python depending on student&amp;rsquo;s experience and preference (no video games!)
Cost: $350
Sign Up: nora@blueridgeboost.com
Conditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a mask for the duration of the camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/authors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/authors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block Language for Kids Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/k2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/k2/</guid>
      <description>Students learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a a beaver build a dam on instructor-provided chromebooks. Small class size of up to 6 students ensures that each student gets the attention they need to be successful. Sessions contain 8 lessons. Each lesson is 45 minutes long. The cost per session is $190.
Session 1. Sequencing and Loops Students build a foundation in coding and problem solving.
Lesson 1. What is coding?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</guid>
      <description>Fall classes coming soon In September and October 2022, we offer group coding classes: block languages for preschool, lower elementary, Coffee Script for upper elementary, and Python for middle school.
Each class is 8-weeks long. The class time will be announced soon.
For individual tutoring, please schedule your math lesson here and your coding lesson here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Script Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/upper_elementary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/upper_elementary/</guid>
      <description>Students learn fundamental coding concepts using Coffee Script, a beginner friendly text-based coding language. The young coders use an attractive graphical interface to generate text by pressing buttons on instructor-provided chromebooks. Some previous experience typing is helpful, but not necessary. Small class size of up to 6 students ensures that each student gets the attention they need to be successful. Sessions contain 8 lessons. Each lesson is 45 minutes long. The cost per session is $190.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science and Math Tutoring</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/hs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/hs/</guid>
      <description>Computing At Blue Ridge Boost, we provide individual tutoring sessions for high ability students in the following subjects:
AP Computer Science Principles (Python) AP Computer Science (Java) Preparation for USA Computing Olympiad Bronze Level Math A licensed, experienced teacher provides individual instruction in:
Algebra 1 Geometry Trigonometry Algebra 2 Math Analysis AP Calculus AB AP Calculus BC Math for SAT/ACT Book a computer science session now! Book a math session now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science and Math Tutoring in Charlottesville for Adults</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/adults/</guid>
      <description>Computer Science Coding with Java, Python, C/C++, Prolog, Lisp, and Rust. Introduction to Programming Data Structures and Algorithms Discrete Math Program and Data Representation Programming Languages Math Financial Mathematics Calculus Transition to Higher Mathematics Real Analysis Abstract Algebra General Topology Book a computer science session now! Book a math session now! Contact us if your needs are not met by one of the existing offerings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science Sessions</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/cstutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/cstutoring/</guid>
      <description>Click on a session to see availability and book it! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please contact us with for any learning needs in math and computing. We offer online one-on-one instruction and in-person group classes for students from middle school to graduate student level in Mathematics and Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall Classes</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/1/01/01/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/blog/1/01/01/post1/</guid>
      <description>Fall classes coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/faq/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Classes Schedule</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/schedule/</guid>
      <description> Book 1-1 classes here! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Sessions</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/mathtutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/mathtutoring/</guid>
      <description>Click on a session to see availability and book it! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morning Camp for 6-9 year olds</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/morningwintercamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/morningwintercamp/</guid>
      <description>Camp at a glance When: Monday, December 27 - Friday, December 31, 2021, 10:00 am – 1:00 pm
Where: 1629 Appian Way, Charlottesville, Virginia (Pantops area)
What: Coding instruction using block languages (no video games!)
Who: 6 – 9 years olds, no prior computer programming experience required
Cost: $350 (early drop off at 9am is available for an additional $50)
Sign Up: nora@blueridgeboost.com
Conditions to attend: proof of COVID-19 vaccination, commitment to wear a mask for the duration of the camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past Coding Classes Offered at Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/past_classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/past_classes/</guid>
      <description>Where: Before August 15, Zoom meeting from the comfort of your home.
When: at a time that works for you.Who: Any student interested in coding.Cost for six 1-hour sessions: $250 for elementary school, $350 for middle school, $400 for high school.Introduction to Coding At Blue Ridge Boost, we teach the same fundamental coding concepts to students of all ages. The courses are structured around three 6-class sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preschool Coding Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/preschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/preschool/</guid>
      <description>Students learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a monkey collect bananas on instructor-provided chromebooks. Small class size of up to 4 students ensures that each student gets the attention they need to be successful. Sessions contain 8 lessons. Each lesson is 35 minutes long. The cost per session is $165.
Session 1. Sequencing and Loops Students build a foundation in coding and problem solving.
Lesson 1. What is coding? Students learn that coding is giving precise instructions to a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Classes in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/python_ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/python_ms/</guid>
      <description>Students learn to code instructor-provided chromebooks using Python, a widely used programming language in academia and industry. Previous experience with computer typing is recommended. Small class size of up to 6 students ensures that each student gets the attention they need to be successful. Sessions contain 8 lessons. Each lesson is 45 minutes long. The cost per session is $190.
Session 1. Sequencing, Objects, Loops and Variables In the first 8-week session students learn objects and properties, lists and indexing, for loops, variables, and conditional statements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Instructor: Ana Nora Evans</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/instructor/</guid>
      <description>Math Experience Master of Science - Mathematics from the University of Virginia Master of Teaching - Mathematics Calculus teacher at Renaissance School AP Summer Institute training in AP Calculus AB/BC Calculus and Abstract Algebra in-person tutoring for over a year internship at Monticello High School in Algebra 2, Precalculus, and Geometry co-founder and organizer of Cville Math Circle for preschool and elementary school age girls teaching assistant for graduate-level courses Financial Mathematics instructor at the University of Virginia Computer Science and Coding Experience Master in Computer Science co-author of several research articles several year of industry experience over a year of online tutoring on Wyzant in C, C++, Java, Python, List and Prolog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
