<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Coding, Math, and Robotics Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Coding, Math, and Robotics Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-on-Saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-on-Saturday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dive into an exciting new season of &lt;strong&gt;FIRST LEGO League&lt;/strong&gt; with the 2024-2025 theme: &lt;strong&gt;SUBMERGED&lt;/strong&gt;! This year’s challenge invites participants to explore the mysteries and wonders of underwater environments while solving real-world challenges related to oceans, lakes, and waterways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Work on collaborative projects with peers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our advanced math class, we harness the engaging and comprehensive materials from Beast Academy to cultivate a deep understanding and passion for mathematics. Each student embarks on a personalized mathematical journey under the guidance of an expert Blue Ridge Boost instructor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Class Structure&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction:&lt;/strong&gt; Each session begins with a concise lesson introducing new concepts and exercise types.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guided Practice:&lt;/strong&gt; Students then apply these concepts through hands-on problem-solving, with instructor support readily available.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual Exploration:&lt;/strong&gt; Using Beast Academy practice books, students tackle challenging exercises and puzzles that reinforce learning and promote critical thinking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Our Approach&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This integrated approach goes beyond mere calculation, emphasizing:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIRST Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dive into an exciting new season of FIRST LEGO League with the 2024-2025 theme: SUBMERGED! This year’s challenge invites participants to explore the mysteries and wonders of underwater environments while solving real-world challenges related to oceans, lakes, and waterways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Work on collaborative projects with peers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIRST Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dive into an exciting new season of FIRST LEGO League with the 2024-2025 theme: SUBMERGED! This year’s challenge invites participants to explore the mysteries and wonders of underwater environments while solving real-world challenges related to oceans, lakes, and waterways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Work on collaborative projects with peers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate Counting And Probabilities | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intermediate-Counting-And-Probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intermediate-Counting-And-Probabilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course comprehensively explores advanced counting, probability, and combinatorics topics essential for problem-solving in mathematics and related fields. Designed for students with a foundational understanding of mathematics, it emphasizes theoretical concepts and practical problem-solving skills. The course is structured to gradually build expertise, starting with basics and progressing to more complex topics like generating functions, graph theory, and advanced probability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Summary of Topics&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review of Counting &amp; Probability Basics&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Counting techniques, probability basics, expected value, Pascal&#39;s triangle, binomial theorem, and summation notation.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sets and Logic&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Set theory, operations on sets, logical reasoning, truth tables, and quantifiers.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle of Inclusion-Exclusion (PIE)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Counting with overlapping sets, extending PIE to multiple properties, and solving advanced counting problems.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constructive Counting and 1-1 Correspondences&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Constructive approaches to counting, one-to-one correspondences, and clever problem-solving techniques.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pigeonhole Principle&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Applications of the pigeonhole principle in basic and advanced combinatorics problems.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constructive Expectation&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Calculating expectations constructively, summing expectations, and handling complex expectation problems.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributions&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Distributing items among groups, applying conditions, and solving complex distribution problems.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mathematical Induction&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Introduction to induction, basic proofs, and problem-solving with this fundamental technique.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fibonacci Numbers&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Properties, problems, formulas, and applications of Fibonacci numbers.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recursion&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Understanding recursion, linear recurrences, Catalan numbers, and their applications.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conditional Probability&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Basics, notation, harder examples, and real-world applications like the &#34;Let&#39;s Make a Deal&#34; problem.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Combinatorial Identities&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Deriving and applying basic and advanced combinatorial identities.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Events With States&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;State diagrams, random walks, infinite states, and strategy games.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generating Functions&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Basics, applications to binomial theorem, distributions, partitions, and Fibonacci numbers.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graph Theory&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Definitions, properties, cycles, paths, planar graphs, Eulerian and Hamiltonian paths.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Number Theory | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-Number-Theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-Number-Theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn the fundamentals of number theory. This course covers essential topics such as:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Primes and composites&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Multiples and divisors&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Prime factorization and its applications&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Base numbers&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Modular arithmetic&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Divisibility rules&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Linear congruences&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Techniques for developing number sense&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;And much more&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;This course is crafted to ignite curiosity and foster the development of innovative ideas. Each session begins with a series of thought-provoking problems, encouraging students to explore solutions independently before engaging in collaborative discussions with peers and the instructor. Throughout the course, emphasis is placed on essential concepts and effective problem-solving strategies, equipping students with tools to tackle challenges with confidence and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prealgebra Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra-Excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra-Excellence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prealgebra prepares students for the rigors of algebra and teaches problem-solving techniques for prestigious middle school math contests such as MATHCOUNTS, MOEMS, and the AMC 8. The course challenges students at a much deeper level than a traditional middle school prealgebra course. Instead of traditional lecturing, most of the class time is dedicated to tackling challenging problems. Students will be encouraged to write complete and clear solutions to exercises, an important skill in communicating mathematics effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Python for Teens | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Python-For-Teens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Python-For-Teens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advanced Python for Teens&lt;/em&gt; builds on foundational Python skills and introduces students to more advanced programming concepts. This course is designed to help students create more powerful and efficient programs by exploring key topics such as functions, strings, data structures, and file input/output operations. Through engaging lessons, hands-on exercises, and creative projects, students will deepen their understanding of Python and develop practical problem-solving skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Functions and Exceptions:&lt;/strong&gt; Learn how to decompose programs into smaller, reusable components and handle errors effectively.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strings:&lt;/strong&gt; Master advanced techniques for manipulating and processing text in programs.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Structures:&lt;/strong&gt; Explore the creation and manipulation of tuples, lists, grids, and dictionaries to build complex programs.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File I/O:&lt;/strong&gt; Gain the ability to read, write, and process information from text files.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Foundations with REV DUO | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Mechanical-Foundations-with-REV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Mechanical-Foundations-with-REV/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Mechanical Foundations with REV DUO&lt;/strong&gt; course provides participants with the hands-on skills and knowledge needed to design, build, and maintain robotic systems confidently. Through interactive projects and challenges, students will explore the foundational mechanical principles that drive robotics, such as structure, motion, power transmission, and mechanical advantage. Using the &lt;strong&gt;REV DUO building system&lt;/strong&gt;, participants will gain practical experience assembling and testing robotic components while learning to solve real-world engineering challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Python for Tweens | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Python-For-Tweens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Python-For-Tweens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Through interactive challenges, students help twin baby monkeys reunite by solving coding problems, reinforcing their understanding of Python fundamentals and advanced topics. The course covers essential concepts such as sequencing, loops, conditionals, and functions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Course Content&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basics review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classes:&lt;/strong&gt; Understanding object-oriented programming to create and manage complex data structures.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Input:&lt;/strong&gt; Interacting with users by receiving and processing input data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;String manipulation:&lt;/strong&gt; Performing operations on text data to modify and analyze it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced data types:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizing complex data structures like dictionaries and sets for efficient data management.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2D lists:&lt;/strong&gt; Working with multi-dimensional arrays to handle grid-based data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bubble sort:&lt;/strong&gt; Learning basic sorting algorithms to organize data effectively.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy &amp; Physiology | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Science-Olympiad-Div-B-Anatomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Science-Olympiad-Div-B-Anatomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dive into the fascinating world of human anatomy with this engaging class focused on the &lt;strong&gt;integumentary, muscular, and skeletal systems&lt;/strong&gt;! Students will explore how these three systems work together to protect, support, and move the body. Through interactive lessons, hands-on activities, and real-world examples, participants will:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integumentary System:&lt;/strong&gt; Learn about the skin, hair, nails, and glands, and discover how they protect the body, regulate temperature, and enable sensory perception.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Muscular System:&lt;/strong&gt; Examine the three types of muscles (skeletal, smooth, and cardiac) and understand how muscle contractions drive movement, posture, and vital bodily functions.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skeletal System:&lt;/strong&gt; Uncover the structure and function of bones, joints, and cartilage, and see how the skeleton supports the body, protects vital organs, and enables movement.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will gain a deeper understanding of how these systems contribute to overall health and interact to maintain the body’s structure and function. This class is perfect for anyone curious about biology, anatomy, or pursuing a career in healthcare or science!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science Challenges | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Science-Olympiad-Sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Science-Olympiad-Sunday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;4-Class Series: Building a Hydraulic System&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In these hands-on sessions, teams will design and construct a freestanding hydraulic device capable of lifting a 100g weight at least 30 cm and holding it for 30 seconds. Using only the materials provided, students will explore the practical applications of hydraulic systems while working collaboratively to solve this engineering challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;4-Class Series: Origami Glider Relay&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In these hands-on events, teams will construct an origami glider (either a Dihedral Magnus Effect glider or a Tumblewing glider) and navigate it through a relay-style obstacle course for the fastest time. Participants must optimize their design during the building phase to ensure their glider performs well in flight. This session emphasizes creativity, precision, and teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scratch Coding | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Scratch-First-and-Second/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Scratch-First-and-Second/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come and learn to code your own games in Scratch!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each session will create a new game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lego Robotics | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Lego-Spike-Prime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Lego-Spike-Prime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jump into the world of robotics and coding with the &lt;strong&gt;LEGO Education SPIKE Prime&lt;/strong&gt; system! This hands-on course introduces students to the exciting possibilities of robotics engineering and computational thinking through engaging, project-based learning. Designed for beginners to intermediate learners, this course will teach students how to design, build, and program robotic solutions to solve real-world challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this course, students will:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Learn the basics of robotics using the &lt;strong&gt;LEGO SPIKE Prime kit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Explore block-based programming concepts like loops, conditionals, and variables.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Build and program robots to complete fun and interactive challenges.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Integrate sensors and motors to create responsive, autonomous robots.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Apply problem-solving and critical thinking skills to tackle real-world scenarios.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will have a strong foundation in programming and robotics, having built and programmed their own robotics projects. This course is perfect for students looking to get started with STEM learning in a fun and accessible way!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indi Sphero | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Lego-Robots-Jr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Lego-Robots-Jr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session 1: Introduction to Sphero Indi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Familiarize students with Sphero Indi, its color-coded tiles, and how it operates.&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt; Sphero Indi robots, color tiles, printed activity sheets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warm-Up (10 min)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Explain what Sphero Indi is and how it moves based on color tiles (e.g., green = go, red = stop, etc.).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Demonstrate basic movement using color tiles.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activity 1: Meet Indi (20 min)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Students create a simple path using 3–5 tiles (e.g., green → yellow → red).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Place Indi on the path and observe its movement.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussion/Reflection (15 min)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Ask students: What did Indi do when it saw each color?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Discuss how different colors &#34;program&#34; Indi to perform actions.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session 2: Building Simple Paths&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Practice creating paths that guide Indi to a specific destination.&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt; Sphero Indi robots, color tiles, printed grid mat (or flat play area).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Algebra 1 Success Made Simple!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Algebra Sessions:&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focused Learning:&lt;/strong&gt; Small groups of 4 students&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expert Guidance:&lt;/strong&gt; Excel in your algebra homework&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clear Explanations:&lt;/strong&gt; Understand equations and functions&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Practice:&lt;/strong&gt; Build problem-solving skills&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weekly Sessions:&lt;/strong&gt; 60 minutes each&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Coverage:&lt;/strong&gt; All key Algebra 1 topics&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boost Your Grades and Confidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Algebra Group today!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build a Capture the Flag in Unreal Editor for Fortnite | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Capture-the-Flag-Unreal-Editor-for-Fortnite-4-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Capture-the-Flag-Unreal-Editor-for-Fortnite-4-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; Dive into the exciting world of game development with Unreal Editor for Fortnite (UEFN). In this 6-session course, you’ll learn how to create a fully functional &#34;Capture the Flag&#34; game, from designing levels to scripting gameplay mechanics using Verse. No prior experience? No problem! This course is beginner-friendly and will set you up for success in game design.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session 1: Introduction to Unreal Editor for Fortnite (UEFN)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build a Capture the Flag in Unreal Editor for Fortnite | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Capture-the-Flag-Unreal-Editor-for-Fortnite-6-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Capture-the-Flag-Unreal-Editor-for-Fortnite-6-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; Dive into the exciting world of game development with Unreal Editor for Fortnite (UEFN). In this 6-session course, you’ll learn how to create a fully functional &#34;Capture the Flag&#34; game, from designing levels to scripting gameplay mechanics using Verse. No prior experience? No problem! This course is beginner-friendly and will set you up for success in game design.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session 1: Introduction to Unreal Editor for Fortnite (UEFN)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Geometry Homework Made Easy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Geometry Sessions:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;li&gt; Small groups of 4 students&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Expert help with your geometry homework&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Clear explanations of theorems and proofs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hands-on problem-solving practice&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;60-minute sessions weekly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cover all high school geometry topics&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Boost your grades and confidence&lt;/li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transform triangles and circles from foes to friends!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Geometry Group today!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sumo Bots | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Sumo-Bots-Wednesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Sumo-Bots-Wednesday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 1: Introduction to SumoBot and Building Basics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Understand the concept of Robot Sumo, learn about SumoBot, and begin building the basic robot.&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt; VEX IQ Super Kit, SumoBot building instructions (from the URL), printed diagrams, markers for the Sumo ring.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warm-Up (10 min)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Introduce the concept of Robot Sumo: two robots compete to push each other out of a ring.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Show videos/examples of Robot Sumo matches for inspiration.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Explain the rules of the game (e.g., size and weight limits, staying inside the ring).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activity: Build the SumoBot (35 min)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Provide the students with the VEX IQ Super Kit and SumoBot building instructions.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Begin assembling the base of the robot (focus on drivetrain and stability).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Encourage teamwork and problem-solving during the build process.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrap-Up (5 min)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Check progress and discuss challenges faced during the build.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Assign students to complete their builds at the start of the next lesson.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;hr&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 2: Completing the Build and Introduction to Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Finish building the SumoBot and explore basic programming with the VEX IQ Brain.&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt; VEX IQ Super Kit, laptops/tablets with VEXcode IQ or comparable programming software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Kids | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Machine-Learning-for-Kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Machine-Learning-for-Kids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dive into the fascinating world of artificial intelligence with this hands-on class designed for young learners! Using the &lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning for Kids&lt;/strong&gt; platform, students will explore how machines can &#34;learn&#34; from data and apply this knowledge to solve real-world problems in creative ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This class introduces the basics of &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt; through fun, interactive projects, where students will:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Learn how to train machine learning models using simple datasets.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Explore key concepts like classification, recognition, and prediction.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Use their machine learning models to create exciting projects, such as chatbots, games, and interactive applications.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Experiment with coding tools like &lt;strong&gt;Scratch&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;, ideal for beginners and adaptable for more advanced learners.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;By combining coding, creativity, and problem-solving, this class helps students understand the power of AI and machine learning in technology today. Perfect for students who want to learn how AI works in a fun and accessible way!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chess Club and Classes | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/chess/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Coding Classes and Tutoring | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Boost | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-3-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This class is tailored for students who are in the top half of the class, but need clarifications of some grade-level concepts. It offers reinforcement of key concepts through extra practice with typical grade-level problems, ensuring that students can grasp and master the material at their own pace. Additionally, students will have the opportunity to work on materials recommended by their classroom teacher and tackle problems suggested by Blue Ridge Boost instructors, providing a tailored and comprehensive approach to meet their individual learning needs.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Classes and Tutoring | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/math/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-3-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our advanced math class, we harness the engaging and comprehensive materials from Beast Academy to cultivate a deep understanding and passion for mathematics. Each student embarks on a personalized mathematical journey under the guidance of an expert Blue Ridge Boost instructor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Class Structure&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction:&lt;/strong&gt; Each session begins with a concise lesson introducing new concepts and exercise types.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guided Practice:&lt;/strong&gt; Students then apply these concepts through hands-on problem-solving, with instructor support readily available.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual Exploration:&lt;/strong&gt; Using Beast Academy practice books, students tackle challenging exercises and puzzles that reinforce learning and promote critical thinking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Our Approach&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This integrated approach goes beyond mere calculation, emphasizing:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-3-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Key Features:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Mental Math Strategies:&lt;/strong&gt; Students will be introduced to various mental math techniques to improve their calculation skills.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variety of Problems:&lt;/strong&gt; The curriculum offers a range of problems, from basic exercises to more challenging ones, fostering critical and creative thinking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mastery of Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt; Repeated practice ensures students achieve a solid understanding of each topic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem-Solving Skills:&lt;/strong&gt; Activities and exercises are designed to enhance analytical and logical thinking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Why Choose This Class?&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Mental Math:&lt;/strong&gt; Exposure to more mental math strategies and a greater variety of problems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Curriculum:&lt;/strong&gt; Aims to advance students beyond the typical U.S. curriculum while still covering Common Core Standards, sometimes at an earlier grade level.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic Challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides a more rigorous and engaging math experience.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparation for Higher Studies:&lt;/strong&gt; Equips students with skills for advanced math courses and exams.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holistic Approach:&lt;/strong&gt; Focuses on understanding rather than rote learning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Ideal For:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Students in the top half of their class who show an interest and aptitude in mathematics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Parents seeking advanced math education for their children.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Learners who enjoy tackling complex and engaging math problems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enroll your student today to help them excel and develop a deeper appreciation for mathematics with the Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Classes | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/robotics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/robotics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science Classes | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/science/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
