<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Coding, Math, and Robotics Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Coding, Math, and Robotics Classes in Charlottesville | Blue Ridge Boost on Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-3D-Printing-Grades-5-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-3D-Printing-Grades-5-6/</guid>
      <description>Class 1: Introduction to 3D Printing What is 3D printing and what is it used for? How to use a 3D printer? Where to find STL files How to convert STL to gcode Class 2: Advanced Techniques Prusa Slicer basics How to CAD Design considerations while Cading for 3D printing Design iteration Class 3: Troubleshooting Common issues with 3D printers Why some prints fail? Class 4: Material Considerations Printing with PLA, PETG, and TPU What are the differences between PLA, PETG, and TPU?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing 2-Day Winter Camp | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-3D-Print/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-3D-Print/</guid>
      <description>Learn to find and modify 3D printing models.&#xA;Learn to create your own design.&#xA;Take home your creations.&#xA;Before and after care is available!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Problem Solving | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Problem-Solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-Problem-Solving/</guid>
      <description>MOEMS is a challenging and engaging math competition for middle schoolers, featuring five monthly contests from November to March that focus on problem-solving and mathematical creativity. Similarly, the AMC 8 is a 40-minute math competition designed for students in grade 8 and below, covering a range of middle school math topics, including some concepts from introductory algebra. At Blue Ridge Boost, students participate in weekly problem-solving sessions to prepare for these competitions, and they have the option to take the tests if they choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerial Drones | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Aerial-Drones/</guid>
      <description>What is the Aerial Drone Competition? A cutting-edge program that prepares students for careers in drone technology Four exciting missions: Teamwork, Autonomous Flight, Piloting Skills, and Communications Compete in local, and regional events No prior experience needed! We&#39;re looking for students who are: Curious about drones and aviation Interested in coding and programming Excited to learn piloting skills Great at teamwork and communication Ready to take on new challenges Students are not required to participate in a Competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Coding Camp Care | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-After/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-After/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Algebra 1 Success Made Simple!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Algebra Sessions: Focused Learning: Small groups of 4 students Expert Guidance: Excel in your algebra homework Clear Explanations: Understand equations and functions Interactive Practice: Build problem-solving skills Weekly Sessions: 60 minutes each Comprehensive Coverage: All key Algebra 1 topics Boost Your Grades and ConfidenceEnroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Algebra Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Algebra-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Algebra Together!&#xA;Join our group algebra homework help sessions:&#xA;Small group classes (4 students)Expert instructor guidanceCollaborative problem-solvingBoost your grades and confidence with peers!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMC 8 Test | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/AMC8-2025-Test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/AMC8-2025-Test/</guid>
      <description>Are you excited about the AMC 8 but find that your school doesn&#39;t host the contest? No problem! You can sign up and take the test at Blue Ridge Boost. We offer a welcoming space for young math enthusiasts to test their skills and enjoy a rewarding competition experience.&#xA;The AMC 8 is a 25-question, 40-minute competition designed for students in grade 8 and below. The competition focuses on middle school mathematics topics, including counting and probability, estimation, proportional reasoning, elementary geometry (including the Pythagorean Theorem), spatial visualization, and interpreting graphs and tables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMC10 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-AMC10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-AMC10/</guid>
      <description>The AMC 10 (American Mathematics Competitions 10) is a prestigious mathematics contest in the United States designed for students aged 10 through 16, or those enrolled in grades 10 and below. This challenging competition aims to cultivate problem-solving skills, foster mathematical creativity, and promote a deeper understanding of advanced mathematical concepts. With its rigorous content spanning algebra, geometry, number theory, and combinatorics, the AMC 10 serves as a gateway to higher-level math competitions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banana Code Quest | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Code-Quest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Code-Quest/</guid>
      <description>Banana Code Quest is a gamified coding course designed to teach young students real-world coding from the first challenge. Through engaging puzzles and adventures, students help a monkey catch bananas and outsmart various animals while learning fundamental and advanced coding concepts in a fun and interactive way.&#xA;Key Features Real Coding Language: Students will code using CoffeeScript, a language similar to JavaScript but with a friendlier syntax, making it perfect for kids.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banana Tales | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Tales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Tales/</guid>
      <description>Through interactive challenges, students help twin baby monkeys reunite by solving coding problems, reinforcing their understanding of Python fundamentals and advanced topics. The course covers essential concepts such as sequencing, loops, conditionals, functions, and introduces more complex topics like classes, string manipulation, and sorting algorithms. With step-by-step instructions, interactive quizzes, and a supportive learning environment, this course provides a fun and effective way for 5th and 6th graders to develop their programming skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Before Camp Care | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-Before/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-Before/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Block Coding with Minecraft | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block-Coding-with-Minecraft-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block-Coding-with-Minecraft-1/</guid>
      <description>This four-class sequence introduces the students to fundamental computer science concepts, including events and coordinates. Students will use a coding environment embedded in Minecraft Education to code their own commands, which they will then use in the game.&#xA;Leveraging the engaging world of Minecraft Education, students will:&#xA;Explore a custom coding environment integrated within the game Learn to write and execute their own commands Apply coding principles to manipulate the Minecraft world in real-time Develop problem-solving skills through interactive challenges Gain hands-on experience with spatial reasoning and algorithmic thinking By the end of the course, students will have a solid foundation in basic programming concepts, enhanced creativity, and improved logical reasoning skills—all while enjoying the familiar and exciting Minecraft platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculus AB/BC | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus-AB-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus-AB-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Calculus with Intensive Practice!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost Small Group Tutoring:&#xA;4 students per groupDeep dive into calculus conceptsExpert calculus tutor guidance90-minutes sessionsTransform your calculus struggles into strengths!&#xA;Enroll now and differentiate yourself from the rest!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculus AB/BC | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus-AB-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Calculus-AB-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Calculus Homework!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost Small Group Sessions:&#xA;4 students per groupFocus on current homework assignmentsStep-by-step problem-solving guidanceExpert calculus tutor support90-minute sessionsCover all calculus topics in your curriculumAdditional practice problems for reinforcementTurn your homework headaches into &#39;Aha!&#39; moments!&#xA;Sign up for Blue Ridge Boost and ace your assignments!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chess Club and Classes | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/chess/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chess Tactics and Games | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Chess-Tactics-And-Games-Dec-7/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to start a chess program for our more dedicated players, who are ready to learn more about the game and improve their skills.&#xA;The classes start at 10 am with a 45 minutes lesson, followed by three 15-minute games. The pickup time is 12:00.&#xA;The classes are held at Blue Ridge Boost and are taught by Daniel Wurtzer.&#xA;Hello my name is Daniel Wurzer and I am excited to teach chess lessons at Blue Ridge Boost this fall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Coding Classes and Tutoring | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/coding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-1/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the world of Lego robotics Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-2/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the world of Lego robotics Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-3/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the world of Lego robotics Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lego League Explore | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-on-Saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/FLL-Explore-on-Saturday/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the world of Lego robotics Participate in the official First Lego League Explore program Work on collaborative projects with peers Learn about real-world applications of robotics and engineering This class is perfect for budding engineers and curious minds ready to take their first steps into the world of robotics! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Geometry-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Geometry Homework Made Easy!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Group Geometry Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of 4 studentsExpert help with your geometry homework Clear explanations of theorems and proofsHands-on problem-solving practice60-minute sessions weeklyCover all high school geometry topicsBoost your grades and confidenceTransform triangles and circles from foes to friends!&#xA;Enroll in Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Geometry Group today!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered Drone Squad | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-Drone-Squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-Drone-Squad/</guid>
      <description>Calling All Future Female Drone Pilots and Engineers!&#xA;Join our Girl-Powered Aerial Drone Competition Team! Are you ready to soar into the future of technology? We&#39;re forming an all-girl team for the REC Foundation Aerial Drone Competition, and we want YOU to be part of this exciting adventure! What is the Aerial Drone Competition?&#xA;• A cutting-edge program that prepares students for careers in drone technology&#xA;• Four exciting missions: Teamwork, Autonomous Flight, Piloting Skills, and Communications</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl-Powered First Tech Challenge | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-First-Tech-Challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Girl-Powered-First-Tech-Challenge/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;re forming a new FIRST Tech Challenge team and we want GIRLS!&#xA;This is an inclusive STEM class with a focus on empowering girls. While all genders are welcome and encouraged to participate, we strive to maintain a majority female enrollment to address historical underrepresentation in STEM fields. Our goal is to create a supportive environment that inspires girls to explore and excel in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.&#xA;What is FIRST Tech Challenge?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-1-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-1-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Master Integrated Math 1 with Blue Ridge Boost!&#xA;Join our Focused Group Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of no more than 4 students60-minute intensive weekly sessionsExpert guidance on all Integrated Math 1 topicsAlgebra, geometry, and statistics supportTargeted homework help and problem-solvingAligned with common core standardsPersonalized attention in a collaborative settingTurn math confusion into confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-1-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-1-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Integrated Math 1 Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help:&#xA;Groups of 4 students60-minute focused sessions every weekDirect assistance with your current homeworkStep-by-step guidance on tough problemsCover all Integrated Math 1 topics as they ariseAlgebra, geometry, and statistics supportImprove grades and build confidenceTurn homework struggles into success stories!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 2/Algebra 2 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-2-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-2-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Master Integrated Math 2 with Blue Ridge Boost!&#xA;Join our Focused Group Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of no more than four students60-minute intensive weekly sessionsExpert guidance on all Integrated Math 2 topicsAlgebra, geometry, precalculus, and statistics supportTargeted homework help and problem-solvingAligned with common core standardsPersonalized attention in a collaborative settingTurn math confusion into confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 2/Algebra 2 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-2-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-2-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Integrated Math 2 Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help:&#xA;Groups of 4 students60-minute focused sessions every weekDirect assistance with your current homeworkStep-by-step guidance on tough problemsCover all Integrated Math 2 topics as they ariseAlgebra, geometry, and statistics supportImprove grades and build confidenceTurn homework struggles into success stories!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 3 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-3-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-3-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Master Integrated Math 3 with Blue Ridge Boost!&#xA;Join our Focused Group Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of no more than four students60-minute intensive weekly sessionsExpert guidance on all Integrated Math 3 topicsAlgebra, geometry, precalculus, and statistics supportTargeted homework help and problem-solvingAligned with common core standardsPersonalized attention in a collaborative settingTurn math confusion into confidence!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Math 3 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-3-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Integrated-Math-3-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Integrated Math 3 Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help:&#xA;Groups of 4 students60-minute focused sessions every weekDirect assistance with your current homeworkStep-by-step guidance on tough problemsCover all Integrated Math 3 topics as they ariseAlgebra, geometry, and statistics supportImprove grades and build confidenceTurn homework struggles into success stories!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kids&#39; Coding Course | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids-Coding-Course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids-Coding-Course/</guid>
      <description>Students learn sequencing, repetition, problem-solving, and conditional logic while developing practical coding skills. The course employs a hands-on, gamified approach that gradually increases in complexity, allowing each child to advance at their own speed. By the end, students can create sophisticated programs, having built a strong foundation in coding and computational thinking.&#xA;We start to learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a beaver build a dam! The learning continues with learning to code games in Scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lego Robots Jr | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-of-Coding-with-SPIKE-Essential-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-of-Coding-with-SPIKE-Essential-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>This four-class sequence introduces the students to the world of robotics and coding. Students will construct Lego models that use motors and lights and create code to bring their creations to life. This class is suitable for students with no previous experience using Lego robots. Introducing the Next Generation of Coders!The Fundamentals of Coding with SPIKE Essential is the fun and engaging way to teach your elementary students essential STEM skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Boost | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-1-2/</guid>
      <description>This class is tailored for students who are in the top half of the class, but need clarifications of some grade-level concepts. It offers reinforcement of key concepts through extra practice with typical grade-level problems, ensuring that students can grasp and master the material at their own pace. Additionally, students will have the opportunity to work on materials recommended by their classroom teacher and tackle problems suggested by Blue Ridge Boost instructors, providing a tailored and comprehensive approach to meet their individual learning needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Boost | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-3-4/</guid>
      <description>This class is tailored for students who are in the top half of the class, but need clarifications of some grade-level concepts. It offers reinforcement of key concepts through extra practice with typical grade-level problems, ensuring that students can grasp and master the material at their own pace. Additionally, students will have the opportunity to work on materials recommended by their classroom teacher and tackle problems suggested by Blue Ridge Boost instructors, providing a tailored and comprehensive approach to meet their individual learning needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Boost | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-5-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Boost-5-6/</guid>
      <description>This class is tailored for students who are in the top half of the class, but need clarifications of some grade-level concepts. It offers reinforcement of key concepts through extra practice with typical grade-level problems, ensuring that students can grasp and master the material at their own pace. Additionally, students will have the opportunity to work on materials recommended by their classroom teacher and tackle problems suggested by Blue Ridge Boost instructors, providing a tailored and comprehensive approach to meet their individual learning needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Classes and Tutoring | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/math/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Classes and Tutoring | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/robotics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/robotics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-1-2/</guid>
      <description>In our advanced math class, we harness the engaging and comprehensive materials from Beast Academy to cultivate a deep understanding and passion for mathematics. Each student embarks on a personalized mathematical journey under the guidance of an expert Blue Ridge Boost instructor.&#xA;Class Structure Introduction: Each session begins with a concise lesson introducing new concepts and exercise types. Guided Practice: Students then apply these concepts through hands-on problem-solving, with instructor support readily available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Excellence-3-4/</guid>
      <description>In our advanced math class, we harness the engaging and comprehensive materials from Beast Academy to cultivate a deep understanding and passion for mathematics. Each student embarks on a personalized mathematical journey under the guidance of an expert Blue Ridge Boost instructor.&#xA;Class Structure Introduction: Each session begins with a concise lesson introducing new concepts and exercise types. Guided Practice: Students then apply these concepts through hands-on problem-solving, with instructor support readily available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Hoppers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Hoppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Hoppers/</guid>
      <description>The Kangaroo Mathematics Competition, set for Thursday, March 20, 2025, is an international event testing students&amp;rsquo; math skills. Preparation involves practicing past papers, reviewing key concepts, and improving time management. The multiple-choice test covers various math topics. The class will continue for the duration of the school year to prepare students for the next year&amp;rsquo;s competition.&#xA;What is Kangaroo Math? Kangaroo Math is a fun and exciting math competition where students from different countries solve interesting and challenging math problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Leapers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Leapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Leapers/</guid>
      <description>The Math Kangaroo competition is an international mathematical competition where students from grades 1 through 12 participate. The curriculum for grades 3 and 4 focuses on enhancing mathematical skills through engaging and challenging problems, building on the foundational knowledge acquired in earlier grades. The Kangaroo Mathematics Competition, set for Thursday, March 20, 2025. The class will continue for the duration of the school year to prepare students for the next year&amp;rsquo;s competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-1-2/</guid>
      <description>This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles. Key Features: Advanced Mental Math Strategies: Students will be introduced to various mental math techniques to improve their calculation skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-3-4/</guid>
      <description>This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles. Key Features: Advanced Mental Math Strategies: Students will be introduced to various mental math techniques to improve their calculation skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Mastery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles. Key Features: Advanced Mental Math Strategies: Students will be introduced to various mental math techniques to improve their calculation skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Olympiad Contest | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-E-Contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-E-Contest/</guid>
      <description>MATH OLYMPIAD 2024-2025&#xA;Unleash Your Mathematical Genius!&#xA;🏆 Calling All Young Math Stars (Grades 3-6)&#xA;Challenge your mind and discover the excitement of problem-solving at this year&#39;s Math Olympiad! Join hundreds of bright young mathematicians for an unforgettable experience.&#xA;Why Participate?&#xA;• Boost your critical thinking skills&#xA;• Meet other math enthusiasts&#xA;• Gain competition experience&#xA;The unique problem sets must be administered each month from November through March.&#xA;You can participate in any or all contests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Olympiad Contest | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-M-Contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/MOEM-24-25-M-Contest/</guid>
      <description>MATH OLYMPIAD 2024-2025&#xA;Unleash Your Mathematical Genius!&#xA;🏆 Calling All Young Math Stars (Grades 6-8)&#xA;Challenge your mind and discover the excitement of problem-solving at this year&#39;s Math Olympiad! Join hundreds of bright young mathematicians for an unforgettable experience.&#xA;Why Participate?&#xA;• Boost your critical thinking skills&#xA;• Meet other math enthusiasts&#xA;• Gain competition experience&#xA;The unique problem sets must be administered each month from November through March.&#xA;You can participate in any or all contests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft 2-Day Winter Camp | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-Minecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-Minecraft/</guid>
      <description>❄️ MINECRAFT WINTER WONDERLAND CAMP ❄️&#xA;A Fun-Filled 2-Day Adventure for Young Builders!&#xA;🎮 CALLING ALL YOUNG ADVENTURERS&#xA;Join us for an exciting journey into a snowy Minecraft world! Perfect for both new and experienced players ages 7-10.&#xA;⚒️ EXCITING ACTIVITIES:&#xA;• Build magical snow castles and cozy winter cottages&#xA;• Create your own winter village with friends&#xA;• Learn cool building tricks and secrets&#xA;• Play friendly snowball games</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education Esports | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Esports-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Esports-Practice/</guid>
      <description>🎉Three Hours of Fun! 🎉 Dive into the world of Minecraft Education Esports with our exciting practice class! Perfect for having fun and honing your skills. What&#39;s Included: 🎮 Fun Training: Enjoy three hours of engaging gameplay. 🛠️ Creative Building: Unleash your imagination and learn new techniques. 🏆 Friendly Competitions: Play in scrimmages and enjoy some friendly rivalry. 👥 Community Connections: Meet fellow Minecraft fans and make new friends Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education for Elementary School | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Elementary-School/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Elementary-School/</guid>
      <description>🎮 Start Your Minecraft Adventure! 🎮&#xA;Join our beginner-friendly class and dive into the world of Minecraft!&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn:&#xA;🏗️ Building Basics: Master the essentials of crafting and construction. 🌿 Survival Skills: Learn how to gather resources and thrive in survival mode. 🗺️ Exploration Tips: Discover exciting biomes and hidden treasures. 👥 Multiplayer Fun: Connect with others and enjoy cooperative gameplay.&#xA;Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prealgebra Excellence | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra-Excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Prealgebra-Excellence/</guid>
      <description>Prealgebra prepares students for the rigors of algebra and teaches problem-solving techniques for prestigious middle school math contests such as MATHCOUNTS, MOEMS, and the AMC 8. The course challenges students at a much deeper level than a traditional middle school prealgebra course. Instead of traditional lecturing, most of the class time is dedicated to tackling challenging problems. Students will be encouraged to write complete and clear solutions to exercises, an important skill in communicating mathematics effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precalculus | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Precalculus-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Precalculus-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Conquer Your Precalculus Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help:&#xA;Groups of 4 students60-minute focused sessions every weekDirect assistance with your current homeworkStep-by-step guidance on tough problemsCover all Precalculus topics as they ariseImprove grades and build confidenceTurn homework struggles into success stories!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem-Solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Problem-Solving/</guid>
      <description>MOEMS is a challenging and engaging math competition for elementary and middle schoolers, featuring five monthly contests from November to March that focus on problem-solving and mathematical creativity. Similarly, the AMC 8 is a 40-minute math competition designed for students in grade 8 and below, covering a range of middle school math topics, including some concepts from introductory algebra. At Blue Ridge Boost, students participate in weekly problem-solving sessions to prepare for these competitions, and they have the option to take the tests if they choose to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Fundamentals | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>This course is a comprehensive, year-long program designed for middle school students with no prior coding experience. It introduces fundamental programming concepts using Python through interactive exercises and projects centered around controlling a virtual character named Tracy. The course covers commands, functions, loops, variables, conditionals, and lists, progressing to more complex tasks like user interaction and creating visual projects.&#xA;Topics include:&#xA;Commands Understanding basic commands is crucial as it forms the foundation of programming, allowing Tracy to perform specific actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roblox 2-Day Winter Camp | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-Roblox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Winter-24-Roblox/</guid>
      <description>Join our kid-friendly Roblox camp designed specifically for grades 1-4. Create your very own carnival game in a fun, supportive environment where imagination meets basic coding skills.&#xA;What Your Child Will Learn:&#xA;Simple drag-and-drop game building Basic Roblox Studio tools Creative design choices Teamwork and problem-solving Game testing basics Fun Activities:&#xA;Design colorful magic spells Place carnival games and decorations Create simple challenges Test games with classmates Earn special Roblox itemsBefore and after care is available!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roblox Studio | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-Roblox-Studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-Roblox-Studio/</guid>
      <description>This class is perfect for students who are new to creating games in Roblox. We will teach you how to create your first Roblox experience using Roblox Studio. You will use a Baseplate template and a high-quality catapult asset pack to build and organize a data model, customize 3D objects, and organize scripts for proper simulation. We will guide you through testing, publishing, and managing your experience for a global audience, using project templates and asset packs from the Creator Store to simplify the process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Discovery | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Discovery-4-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics-Discovery-4-5/</guid>
      <description>This class offers a gentle, engaging introduction to robotics for students in grades 4 and 5. The curriculum is designed to build skills and knowledge throughout the academic year progressively:&#xA;Fall: VEX GO module - Learn basic robotics concepts and simple programmingWinter: Lego Spike Prime - Explore more advanced building and coding techniquesSpring: Sphero Bolt Robotics - Apply learned skills to program spherical robotsOur hands-on approach ensures students gain practical experience with different robotic platforms while developing problem-solving, critical thinking, and teamwork skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scratch | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Scratch-First-and-Second/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Scratch-First-and-Second/</guid>
      <description>Come and learn to code your own games in Scratch!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics-Mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics-Mastery/</guid>
      <description>Boost Your AP Statistics Score!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Extra Practice Sessions:&#xA;Small groups of 4 studentsIntensive 90-minute sessions every weekExtra practice beyond classroom assignmentsFocus on challenging AP Statistics conceptsCover descriptive statistics, probability, inferenceExam-style questions and problem-solving strategiesIncrease your chances for a 5 on the AP examTransform your stats skills from average to exceptional!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Statistics-Practice/</guid>
      <description>Master Your AP Statistics Homework!&#xA;Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s Weekly Homework Help Sessions:&#xA;Intimate groups of 4 studentsFocused 90-minute sessions every weekDirect assistance with your AP Stats homeworkExpert guidance on complex statistical conceptsHelp with data analysis, probability, and inferenceSupport for statistical software and calculatorsImprove your grades and exam readinessTurn stats stumbling blocks into stepping stones!&#xA;Join Blue Ridge Boost&#39;s AP Statistics Homework Group</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex IQ Rapid Relay | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Vex-IQ-Rapid-Relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Vex-IQ-Rapid-Relay/</guid>
      <description>Join us for this exciting class! No experience necessary, only a desire to learn and have fun!&#xA;Together, we will build a competition-level robot, hone driving skills, and coding with this year&amp;rsquo;s game.&#xA;The scoring objects in VEX IQ Robotics Competition Rapid Relay are padded Balls, approximately 6&amp;quot; in diameter.&#xA;The primary objectives of the game are to Pass the Balls between Robots, score Balls through Targets, and Clear Switches. Balls are introduced to the field through the Loading Station or, during the last 15 seconds of a Match, a Rapid Load Zone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vex IQ Robotics Competition (VIQRC) | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First-Lego-League-VEX-IQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/First-Lego-League-VEX-IQ/</guid>
      <description>The VEX IQ Robotics Competition &#34;Rapid Relay&#34; takes place on a 6’ x 8’ rectangular field. In the Teamwork Challenge, two robots form an alliance and work together in 60-second matches to score points collaboratively.&#xA;Teams also participate in the Robot Skills Challenge, where a single robot aims to score as many points as possible. This challenge includes two types of matches: Driving Skills Matches, which are entirely driver-controlled, and Autonomous Coding Skills Matches, which are autonomous with minimal human interaction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Design | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video-Game-Design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video-Game-Design/</guid>
      <description>The video game design curriculum teaches the foundations of creating video games in JavaScript. While this course is introductory, it requires a good mathematical background and analytical thinking. Its curriculum teaches the foundations of computer science and basic programming, with an emphasis on helping students develop logical thinking and problem-solving skills. Once students complete the course, they will have learned material equivalent to a semester college introductory course in Computer Science and be able to program in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
