<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Coding on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Computer-Coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Coding on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Computer-Coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced 3D Printing | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_3D_Printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced_3D_Printing/</guid>
      <description>Take your 3D printing to new heights!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banana Code Quest: Adventures in Text-Based Programming | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana_Code_Quest_Adventures_in_Text-Based_Programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana_Code_Quest_Adventures_in_Text-Based_Programming/</guid>
      <description>Banana Code Quest is a gamified coding course designed to teach young students real-world coding from the very first challenge. Through engaging puzzles and adventures, students help a monkey catch bananas and outsmart various animals, all while learning fundamental and advanced coding concepts in a fun and interactive way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banana Tales: Python Adventures for Grades 5-6 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana_Tales_Python_Adventures_for_Grades_5-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana_Tales_Python_Adventures_for_Grades_5-6/</guid>
      <description>Through interactive challenges, students help twin baby monkeys reunite by solving coding problems, reinforcing their understanding of Python fundamentals and advanced topics. The course covers essential concepts such as sequencing, loops, conditionals, functions, and introduces more complex topics like classes, string manipulation, and sorting algorithms. With step-by-step instructions, interactive quizzes, and a supportive learning environment, this course provides a fun and effective way for 5th and 6th graders to develop their programming skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Block Coding with Minecraft Part 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block_Coding_With_Minecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block_Coding_With_Minecraft/</guid>
      <description>This six-class sequence introduces the students to fundamental computer science concepts, including events and coordinates. Students will use a coding environment embedded in Minecraft Education to code their own commands, which they will then use in the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Block Coding | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids_Coding_Course_Building_with_Beavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids_Coding_Course_Building_with_Beavers/</guid>
      <description>Students learn sequencing, repetition, problem-solving, and conditional logic while developing practical coding skills. The course employs a hands-on, gamified approach that gradually increases in complexity, allowing each child to advance at their own speed. By the end, students can create sophisticated programs, having built a strong foundation in coding and computational thinking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Fundamentals: Coding from the Ground Up | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python_Fundamentals_Coding_from_the_Ground_Up/</guid>
      <description>This course is a comprehensive, year-long program designed for middle school students with no prior coding experience. It introduces fundamental programming concepts using Python through interactive exercises and projects centered around controlling a virtual character named Tracy. The course covers commands, functions, loops, variables, conditionals, and lists, progressing to more complex tasks like user interaction and creating visual projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Design in JavaScript | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video_Game_Design_in_JavaScript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video_Game_Design_in_JavaScript/</guid>
      <description>The video game design curriculum teaches the foundations of creating video games in JavaScript. While this course is introductory, it requires a good mathematical background and analytical thinking. Its curriculum teaches the foundations of computer science and basic programming, with an emphasis on helping students develop logical thinking and problem-solving skills. Once students complete the course, they will have learned material equivalent to a semester college introductory course in Computer Science and be able to program in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
