<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Coding on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Computer-Coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Coding on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/subject_tags/Computer-Coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced 3D Printing | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-3D-Printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Advanced-3D-Printing/</guid>
      <description>Do you already know how to modify and print small models? Are you ready to create your own 3D designs?&#xA;This is the class for you! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banana Code Quest | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Code-Quest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Code-Quest/</guid>
      <description>Banana Code Quest is a gamified coding course designed to teach young students real-world coding from the first challenge. Through engaging puzzles and adventures, students help a monkey catch bananas and outsmart various animals while learning fundamental and advanced coding concepts in a fun and interactive way.&#xA;Key Features Real Coding Language: Students will code using CoffeeScript, a language similar to JavaScript but with a friendlier syntax, making it perfect for kids.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banana Tales | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Tales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Banana-Tales/</guid>
      <description>Through interactive challenges, students help twin baby monkeys reunite by solving coding problems, reinforcing their understanding of Python fundamentals and advanced topics. The course covers essential concepts such as sequencing, loops, conditionals, functions, and introduces more complex topics like classes, string manipulation, and sorting algorithms. With step-by-step instructions, interactive quizzes, and a supportive learning environment, this course provides a fun and effective way for 5th and 6th graders to develop their programming skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Block Coding with Minecraft | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block-Coding-with-Minecraft-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Block-Coding-with-Minecraft-1/</guid>
      <description>This five-class sequence introduces the students to fundamental computer science concepts, including events and coordinates. Students will use a coding environment embedded in Minecraft Education to code their own commands, which they will then use in the game.&#xA;Leveraging the engaging world of Minecraft Education, students will:&#xA;Explore a custom coding environment integrated within the game Learn to write and execute their own commands Apply coding principles to manipulate the Minecraft world in real-time Develop problem-solving skills through interactive challenges Gain hands-on experience with spatial reasoning and algorithmic thinking By the end of the course, students will have a solid foundation in basic programming concepts, enhanced creativity, and improved logical reasoning skills—all while enjoying the familiar and exciting Minecraft platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kids&#39; Coding Course | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids-Coding-Course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids-Coding-Course/</guid>
      <description>Students learn sequencing, repetition, problem-solving, and conditional logic while developing practical coding skills. The course employs a hands-on, gamified approach that gradually increases in complexity, allowing each child to advance at their own speed. By the end, students can create sophisticated programs, having built a strong foundation in coding and computational thinking.&#xA;We start to learn fundamental coding concepts by helping a beaver build a dam! The learning continues with learning to code games in Scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education Esports for Middle Schoolers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Esports-Practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Esports-Practice/</guid>
      <description>🎉Three Hours of Fun! 🎉 Dive into the world of Minecraft Education Esports with our exciting practice class! Perfect for having fun and honing your skills. What&#39;s Included: 🎮 Fun Training: Enjoy three hours of engaging gameplay. 🛠️ Creative Building: Unleash your imagination and learn new techniques. 🏆 Friendly Competitions: Play in scrimmages and enjoy some friendly rivalry. 👥 Community Connections: Meet fellow Minecraft fans and make new friends Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education for Beginners | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Beginners/</guid>
      <description>🎮 Start Your Minecraft Adventure! 🎮&#xA;Join our beginner-friendly class and dive into the world of Minecraft!&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn:&#xA;🏗️ Building Basics: Master the essentials of crafting and construction. 🌿 Survival Skills: Learn how to gather resources and thrive in survival mode. 🗺️ Exploration Tips: Discover exciting biomes and hidden treasures. 👥 Multiplayer Fun: Connect with others and enjoy cooperative gameplay.&#xA;Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Education for Elementary School | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Elementary-School/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Minecraft-Education-Elementary-School/</guid>
      <description>🎮 Start Your Minecraft Adventure! 🎮&#xA;Join our beginner-friendly class and dive into the world of Minecraft!&#xA;What You&#39;ll Learn:&#xA;🏗️ Building Basics: Master the essentials of crafting and construction. 🌿 Survival Skills: Learn how to gather resources and thrive in survival mode. 🗺️ Exploration Tips: Discover exciting biomes and hidden treasures. 👥 Multiplayer Fun: Connect with others and enjoy cooperative gameplay.&#xA;Free pizza included!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Fundamentals | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Python-Fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>This course is a comprehensive, year-long program designed for middle school students with no prior coding experience. It introduces fundamental programming concepts using Python through interactive exercises and projects centered around controlling a virtual character named Tracy. The course covers commands, functions, loops, variables, conditionals, and lists, progressing to more complex tasks like user interaction and creating visual projects.&#xA;Topics include:&#xA;Commands Understanding basic commands is crucial as it forms the foundation of programming, allowing Tracy to perform specific actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roblox Studio | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-Roblox-Studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Intro-to-Roblox-Studio/</guid>
      <description>This class is perfect for students who are new to creating games in Roblox. We will teach you how to create your first Roblox experience using Roblox Studio. You will use a Baseplate template and a high-quality catapult asset pack to build and organize a data model, customize 3D objects, and organize scripts for proper simulation. We will guide you through testing, publishing, and managing your experience for a global audience, using project templates and asset packs from the Creator Store to simplify the process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Design | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video-Game-Design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Video-Game-Design/</guid>
      <description>The video game design curriculum teaches the foundations of creating video games in JavaScript. While this course is introductory, it requires a good mathematical background and analytical thinking. Its curriculum teaches the foundations of computer science and basic programming, with an emphasis on helping students develop logical thinking and problem-solving skills. Once students complete the course, they will have learned material equivalent to a semester college introductory course in Computer Science and be able to program in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
