<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1st on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </title>
    <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/1st/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1st on Computer Science - Robotics - Math - Computer Coding - Chess in Charlottesville </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blueridgeboost.com/grade_tags/1st/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Coding with SPIKE Essential Part 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-Spike-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-Spike-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>This four-class sequence introduces the students to the world of robotics and coding. Students will construct Lego models that use motors and lights and create code to bring their creations to life. This class is suitable for students with no previous experience using Lego robots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Coding with SPIKE Essential Part 1 | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-Spike-Part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Fundamentals-Spike-Part-2/</guid>
      <description>This four-class sequence introduces the students to sensors used in robotics and coding robots to respond to stimuli in the environment. Students will construct Lego models that use motors, color sensors, and gyros and create code to bring their creations to life. This class is suitable for students with some previous experience using Lego robots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Block Coding | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids_Coding_Course_Building_with_Beavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kids_Coding_Course_Building_with_Beavers/</guid>
      <description>Students learn sequencing, repetition, problem-solving, and conditional logic while developing practical coding skills. The course employs a hands-on, gamified approach that gradually increases in complexity, allowing each child to advance at their own speed. By the end, students can create sophisticated programs, having built a strong foundation in coding and computational thinking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Boost for First and Second Graders | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Boost_for_First_and_Second_Graders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Boost_for_First_and_Second_Graders/</guid>
      <description>This class is tailored for students who have been recommended for additional support and are facing challenges in their regular classroom. It offers reinforcement of key concepts through extra practice with typical grade-level problems, ensuring that students can grasp and master the material at their own pace. Additionally, students will have the opportunity to work on materials recommended by their classroom teacher and tackle problems suggested by Blue Ridge Boost instructors, providing a tailored and comprehensive approach to meet their individual learning needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Excellence for First and Second Grade| Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Excellence_for_First_and_Second_Grade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math_Excellence_for_First_and_Second_Grade/</guid>
      <description>In our advanced math class, we harness the engaging and comprehensive materials from Beast Academy to cultivate a deep understanding and passion for mathematics. Each student embarks on a personalized mathematical journey under the guidance of an expert Blue Ridge Boost instructor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Hoppers: Kangaroo Math for Young Explorers | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kangaroo_Competition_Math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Kangaroo_Competition_Math/</guid>
      <description>The Kangaroo Mathematics Competition, set for Thursday, March 20, 2025, is an international event testing students&amp;rsquo; math skills. Preparation involves practicing past papers, reviewing key concepts, and improving time management. The multiple-choice test covers various math topics. The class will continue for the duration of the school year to prepare students for the next year&amp;rsquo;s competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Mastery for First and Second Graders | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-for_First_and_Second_Graders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Math-Mastery-for_First_and_Second_Graders/</guid>
      <description>This advanced mathematics class is designed for curious students ranking in the top 50% of their class who are eager to explore math beyond the typical school curriculum. Utilizing the renowned Dimensions Singapore Math curriculum, our year-long program emphasizes deep conceptual understanding, critical thinking, problem-solving strategies, and practical application of mathematical principles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Discovery for 1st and 2nd Grades | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_1st_and_2nd_Grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Discovery_for_1st_and_2nd_Grades/</guid>
      <description>This class offers a fun and gentle introduction to robotics for students in 1st and 2nd grade, progressively building skills and knowledge through Vex 123, Lego Spike Essential, and Sphero Indie Robotics modules over the academic year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Explorations: Jurassic Journeys &amp; Future Discoveries | Blue Ridge Boost</title>
      <link>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Explorations_Jurassic_Journeys_Future_Discoveries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blueridgeboost.com/classes/Robotics_Explorations_Jurassic_Journeys_Future_Discoveries/</guid>
      <description>Embark on an exciting year-long journey where young learners explore basic robotics concepts through themed challenges, including Jurassic adventures with Sphero indi in the fall and collaborative Lego projects in the spring, fostering critical thinking, teamwork, and creativity.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
